[
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-changes-to-the-cpf-contribution-rates-from-1-january-2025",
        "question": "What are the changes to the CPF contribution rates from 1 January 2025?",
        "answer": "The CPF contribution rates for employees aged above 55 to 65 have been increased to strengthen their retirement adequacy. The changes in CPF contribution rates for Singapore Citizens and Singapore Permanent Residents (from third year and onwards) have taken effect from 1 January 2025.There is no change to the CPF contribution rates for other age groups.Find out more about therevised CPF contribution rates.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-cpf-allocation-rates-from-1-january-2024",
        "question": "What are the CPF allocation rates from 1 January 2024?",
        "answer": "The increase in the CPF contribution rates from 1 January 2024 will be fully allocated to the member’s Special Account to provide a bigger boost to their retirement income.You may refer to theCPF allocation rate table(PDF, 0.1 MB) for more details.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-are-my-cpf-contributions-allocated-to-my-cpf-accounts",
        "question": "How are my CPF contributions allocated to my CPF accounts?",
        "answer": "When you’re younger, more of your CPF contributions are allocated to your Ordinary Account (OA) to support your home purchase. As you grow older, more CPF contributions are allocated to your Special Account (SA) or Retirement Account (RA) and MediSave Account (MA) to meet growing retirement and healthcare needs respectively. You can view theCPF allocation ratesfor details.When you move to the next age group, the change in allocation rates is applied from the first day of the month after your birthday.Example:If you turn 35 years old on 13 January 2025,Your allocation rates for January 2025 will be based on the “35 years and below” age group; andYour allocation rates for February 2025 will be based on the “Above 35 to 45 years” age group.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-pay-my-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "How do I pay my CPF contributions?",
        "answer": "As an employee, you need not do anything as your employer is required to pay the employer’s and employee’s share of CPF contributions to CPF Board on a monthly basis. Your employer will deduct the employee’s share of CPF contributions from your wages.You may refer to the table below to find out if you and/or your employer need to pay CPF contributions based on your total wages per month.Total wages per monthCPF contribution by employerCPF contribution by employeeUp to $50NoNoAbove $50 to $500YesNoAbove $500YesYesYou can use theCPF contribution calculatorto check if your CPF contributions are correctly paid by your employer.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-is-the-due-date-for-my-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "When is the due date for my CPF contributions?",
        "answer": "The due date for CPF contributions is on the last day of the calendar month. Enforcement action would be taken against employers who fail to pay by the 14thof the following month (or the next working day if the 14thfalls on a Saturday, Sunday or Public Holiday). This includes imposing late payment interest charged at 1.5% per month commencing from the first day after the due date.If you are not paid your CPF contributions on time or accurately, you should approach your employer for an explanation and ask when your employer will be making the payment.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-do-if-my-employer-did-not-pay-my-cpf-contributions-on-time",
        "question": "What should I do if my employer did not pay my CPF contributions on time?",
        "answer": "If you are not paid your CPF contributions on time, you should approach your employer for an explanation and ask when your employer will be making the payment.If your employer does not provide you with a satisfactory response, you canlodge a reportwith CPF Board.The Board takes a serious view of employers who default on CPF contributions. The due date for CPF contributions is on the last day of the calendar month.Enforcement actionwould be taken against employers who fail to pay by the 14thof the following month (or the next working day if the 14thfalls on a Saturday, Sunday or Public Holiday). This includes imposing late payment interest charged at 1.5% per month commencing from the first day after the due date. In cases where the company is in financial difficulty, CPF arrears may not always be recoverable despite our enforcement efforts.You mayfind outmore on your rights and employer’s obligations under the CPF Act and the Employment Act.If you face difficulty servicing your Housing Development Board (HDB) loans, you may contactHDBto explore possible alternative housing repayment options. In the event that you wish to look for alternative employment, you may approachWorkforce Singaporefor assistance.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-i-lose-out-on-interest-on-my-cpf-contributions-when-my-employer-pays-my-cpf-contributions-late",
        "question": "Will I lose out on interest on my CPF contributions when my employer pays my CPF contributions late?",
        "answer": "You will not lose out on the interest when your employer pays late. The interest will be credited to you when CPF Board recovers the CPF arrears from your employer.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-lodge-a-report-for-non-payment-or-underpayment-of-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "How can I lodge a report for non-payment or underpayment of CPF contributions?",
        "answer": "For discrepancies in CPF contributions:If you suspect any non-payment or underpayment of CPF contributions, you may use theCPF calculatorto verify the CPF contribution rates applicable to you. Please note that certain types of payments do not attract CPF contributions, you may clickhereto find out more.If there are discrepancies, you should approach your employer immediately, while the documentary evidence is fresh. Your employer is expected to rectify the errors without delay.If your employer does not provide you with a satisfactory response, you can lodge a report with CPF Board. Please enclose all available supporting documents to support your claim (e.g. pay slips and employment contract). Claims made without any supporting documents would require a longer time to investigate.If you would like to lodge a report, please clickhere. Please note the likelihood of recovery for any non/underpayment of CPF contributions beyond 1 year is low as the parties’ recollection of the facts or availability of evidence may diminish over time.For discrepancies in CPF contributions and employment-related claims:If you have any salary and dismissal related claims, you should try to resolve the dispute amicably with your employer first. If your employer does not provide you with a satisfactory response, you should file your claims with theTripartite Alliance for Dispute Management (TADM).The Board will compute the CPF contributions based on the amount of wages due and payable once TADM has concluded your claims.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-to-my-outstanding-cpf-contributions-if-my-employer-is-made-a-bankrupt-or-is-under-liquidation-or-winding-up",
        "question": "What happens to my outstanding CPF contributions if my employer is made a bankrupt, or is under liquidation or winding up?",
        "answer": "In the event that an employer is made a bankrupt, or is under liquidation or winding up, an Official Assignee or Official Receiver/Liquidator respectively, will be appointed by the High Court, company’s shareholders or creditors (depending on the company’s situation). The Board will file the claims for owed CPF contributions for affected employees with the Official Assignee or Official Receiver/Liquidator, as the case may be.If the employer is made a bankrupt, the Official Assignee will investigate into the conduct and affairs of the bankrupt and also recover and realise his assets for distribution to the bankrupt’s creditors. For a company that is under liquidation or winding up, the Official Receiver/Liquidator will investigate into the affairs and assets of the company, the conduct of its officers (including the company directors) and the claims of creditors and third parties. Any proceeds realised by the Official Assignee or Official Receiver/Liquidator will be paid in the following order in accordance with the law: costs and expenses incurred by the Official Assignee or Official Receiver/Liquidator, costs of applicant for the bankruptcy or winding up order, salary (including allowance or reimbursement), retrenchment benefits or ex gratia payments under employment contracts, amounts due in respect of workmen’s compensation under the Work Injury Compensation Act, before it can be paid to employee’s CPF. The bankruptcy, liquidation or winding up process will take time, and could take years to complete for complex cases. If you wish to know more about the bankruptcy, liquidation or winding up process, you can visitMinistry of Law – Insolvency Office website.It is the employers’ obligation to pay the CPF contributions for their employees. However if your employer is made a bankrupt, or is under liquidation or winding up, the owed CPF contributions may not be recovered despite the Board’s actions. To find out the status of the bankruptcy administration, liquidation or winding up, you can contact the Official Assignee or Official Receiver/Liquidator directly.We would like to take this opportunity to advise employees that if your employer is in financial difficulties, while CPF Board will continue to take enforcement actions, employees should be mentally prepared that the CPF owed may not be recoverable. In such situation, to avoid adding to the amounts owed, employees may wish to assess their situation carefully and consider approaching Workforce Singapore for job switch assistance.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-service-standards-for-processing-applications-relating-to-employees-cpf-matters",
        "question": "What are the service standards for processing applications relating to employees' CPF Matters?",
        "answer": "Please refer to the table for our service standards for processing applications relating to employees' CPF Matters.ServiceNormal Processing TimeFeedback on late/underpayment or omission of CPF contributions from employers (a case officer will be assigned to you).You will receive an acknowledgement of your report within 5 working days.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-am-concurrently-employed-by-more-than-one-employer-can-i-choose-to-contribute-cpf-for-one-of-my-employments-only",
        "question": "If I am concurrently employed by more than one employer, can I choose to contribute CPF for one of my employments only?",
        "answer": "If you are concurrently employed by more than one employer, all your employers must pay CPF contributions based on the wages payable to you. This is because the Ordinary Wage (OW) ceiling is applicable on a “per employment” basis.However, if your total OW from your employers exceed thecurrent OW ceiling, you may apply to limit your share of contributions. There will be no change to the employer’s share ofCPF contributions. All your employers will have to pay the employer's share of CPF contributions on the OW at the prevailing rate, subject to the OW ceiling. As contributions are payable monthly, the approval cannot be backdated and it will only take effect once CPF Board’s approval has been granted.You can submit an onlineapplication(via Singpass) to limit your share of CPF contributions.*Please note that the below examples are for illustration purpose only. Please refer to the above links for the latest current OW ceiling and CPF contribution rates applicable.Example 1:For month of June 2023Current OW ceiling =$6,000CPF contribution rate for employee’s share =20%Employee’s share of CPF contributions based on current OW ceiling =$6,000 * 20% =$1,200a)Salary with Employer A =$6,100b) Your employee’s share of CPF contributions paid by employer A =$6,000 (current OW ceiling) * 20% = $1,200c) The amount of employee’s share of CPF contributions you want employer A to contribute on your OW =$1,200a) Salary with Employer B =$2,000b) Your employee’s share of CPF contributions paid by employer B =$2,000 * 20% = $400c) The amount of employee’s share of CPF contributions you want employer B to contribute on your OW =$0Example 2:For month of June 2023Using the same OW ceiling of $6,000 as example.Employee’s share of CPF contributions based on current OW ceiling =$1,200a) Salary with Employer A =$8,000b) Your employee’s share of CPF contributions paid by employer A =$6,000 (current OW ceiling) * 20% = $1,200c) The amount of employee’s share of CPF contributions y ou want employer A to contribute on your OW =$1,000a) Salary with Employer B =$2,000b) Your employee’s share of CPF contributions paid by employer B =$2,000 * 20% = $400c) The amount of employee’s share of CPF contributions you want employer B to contribute on your OW =$200Note: The value in (c) shouldnotexceed (b) for the respective employer, and the sum of (c) across all employersmust be equalto the maximum CPF payable on OW (i.e. prevailing OW ceiling x employee’s share of contribution rate applicable to you)Please also take note that whenever there are change(s) to the circumstances which may affect your CPF contributions on your OW, such as, but not limited to:changes tocurrent OW ceilingyour total combined OW falls below the current OW ceilingchanges to employment status (e.g. new or left employment, no longer concurrently employed by 2 or more employers)changes tocontribution ratescrossing over to another age group as different contribution rates apply to different age groupyoumust informall your affected employers therevise apportionmentsof your employee’s share of CPF contributions, if applicable.Please see below Example 3 for better illustration of circumstance change(s).Example 3:OW ceiling adjustment change from $6,000 to$6,300For month of September 2023Employee’s share of CPF contributions based on current OW ceiling =$6,300 * 20% =$1,260a) Salary with Employer A =$6,100b) Your employee’s share of CPF contributions paid by this employer A =$6,100 * 20% = $1,220c) The amount of employee’s share of CPF contributions you want this employer A to contribute on your OW =$1,220a) Salary with Employer B =$2,000b) Your employee’s share of CPF contributions paid by this employer B =$2,000 * 20% = $400c) The amount of employee’s share of CPF contributions you want this employer B to contribute on your OW =($6,300 * 20% = $1,260) - $$1,220 (Employee's share under Employer A)= $40In the event of any circumstance change(s) (i.e. the above example illustrate change to OW ceiling), the employee (applicant) has to revised the apportionments by using the applicable rates and inform all affected employers of the new revised apportionments.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-apply-for-refund-on-my-share-of-cpf-contributions-that-was-paid-above-the-cpf-wage-ceiling-s",
        "question": "How do I apply for refund on my share of CPF contributions that was paid above the CPF wage ceiling(s)?",
        "answer": "You will need to applyonlinefor refund of CPF contributions paid above the CPF Wage Ceiling(s).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-do-if-my-employer-overpaid-my-cpf-contributions-to-cpf-board-and-did-not-refund-my-share-to-me",
        "question": "What should I do if my employer overpaid my CPF contributions to CPF Board and did not refund my share to me?",
        "answer": "Your employer should refund your share of CPF contributions before applying to the Board for a refund of the excess CPF contributions paid in error. If you did not receive the refund, you canwrite to usand we will contact your employer on the refund.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-documents-must-i-provide-when-i-lodge-a-report-regarding-cpf-non-under-payment",
        "question": "What documents must I provide when I lodge a report regarding CPF non/under-payment?",
        "answer": "You should provide documents such as your monthly pay slips or employment contract for CPF Board to determine the CPF contributions due to you.To minimise potential disputes between you and your employer, the contract must include key employment terms (KETs) and essential clauses, such as hours of work and job scope. For further information on employment contract and KETs, please refer to theMinistry of Manpower website.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-received-a-notification-on-the-refund-of-cpf-contributions-paid-in-excess-of-the-cpf-annual-limit-but-i-have-yet-to-receive-my-share-of-the-excess-contributions-from-my-ex-employer-what-should-i-do",
        "question": "I have received a notification on the refund of CPF contributions paid in excess of the CPF Annual Limit but I have yet to receive my share of the excess contributions from my (ex-)employer, what should I do?",
        "answer": "Your (ex-)employer has been notified to refund your share of excess CPF contributions to you, if any. You should contact your (ex-)employer directly regarding the refund.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/for-cpf-contributions-paid-in-excess-of-the-cpf-annual-limit-how-do-i-derive-the-employee-s-share-to-be-refunded-to-me",
        "question": "For CPF contributions paid in excess of the CPF Annual Limit, how do I derive the employee's share to be refunded to me?",
        "answer": "For example, if you are a Singaporean Citizen who is below 55 years old and has received a total of $40,000 of CPF contributions for 2023, the excess contributions to be refunded to you can be estimated based on the calculation below:Step 1: Total excess CPF contributions refunded to the employer= Total CPF contributions paid – CPF Annual Limit= $40,000 – $37,740= $2,260Step 2: Employee’s share to be refunded= (Total excess CPF contributions refunded ÷ applicable CPF contribution rate) x applicable employee CPF contribution rate= ($2,260 ÷ 37%) x 20%= $1,221* (cents should be dropped)You can also verify the above estimated employee’s share of refund by computing the difference between the total employee’s share of contributions paid and employee’s share of contributions payable. The employee’s share of contributions payable can be computed using theAdditional Wage ceiling Calculator.1This rate is applicable for an employee who is a Singapore Citizen or Singapore Permanent Resident (3rd year onwards) and is 55 or below.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-report-invalid-cpf-contributions-from-employers-whom-i-did-not-work-for",
        "question": "How can I report invalid CPF contributions from employers whom I did not work for?",
        "answer": "You can lodge a report with CPF Board by clickinghereif you have received invalid CPF contributions from employers whom you did not work for.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-cpf-allocation-rates-for-2025",
        "question": "What are the CPF allocation rates for 2025?",
        "answer": "From 1 January 2025, the CPF contribution rates for employees aged above 55 to 65 are increased to strengthen their retirement adequacy.Upon the closure of the Special Account (SA) for CPF members aged 55 and above in early 2025, the CPF contributions allocated to SA will be fully allocated to the member’s Retirement Account (RA), up to the Full Retirement Sum (FRS). For members who have set aside the FRS in the RA, these contributions will be channelled to the Ordinary Account.You may refer to theCPF allocation rate table (PDF, 0.1 MB)for more details.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-ordinary-wage-ow-ceiling-mbr",
        "question": "What is the Ordinary Wage (OW) ceiling?",
        "answer": "TheOrdinary Wage (OW) ceilinglimits the amount of OW that attract CPF contributions in a calendar month for all employees.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-is-exempted-from-receiving-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "Who is exempted from receiving CPF contributions?",
        "answer": "Employeesshould receive CPF contributions from their employers. However, the following employees are exempted from receiving CPF contributions:Students who fulfil exemption criteria. Find out more aboutWho you need to pay CPF contributions for(PDF, 0.2MB) under the header “Students”.Foreigners. Persons who are not Singapore Citizens or Permanent Residents.Domestic employees with employment not exceeding 14 hours in any week. Examples include cooks, maids and gardeners.Employees of the United Nations (UN) Organisation, or any agency or institution of the United Nations Organisation stationed in Singapore. Please refer to theUN websitefor the list of organisations that are part of the UN Organisation under the headers United Nations Organs and Programmes and Specialized Agencies and other Organizations.Employees of the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development, who is assigned to work for the International Energy Agency Regional Cooperation Centre that is located in Singapore.Seamen who are Singapore Citizens and are employed:in a Swedish ship on terms and conditions of service applicable to Swedish seamen; orin a Norwegian ship on terms and conditions of service applicable to Norwegian seamen; orby the East Asiatic Co. Ltd. of Denmark on terms and conditions of the agreement between the Danish Shipowners’ Association and the Seamen’s Union in Denmark.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-just-obtained-my-singapore-permanent-resident-status-do-i-need-to-contribute-cpf",
        "question": "I have just obtained my Singapore Permanent Resident status. Do I need to contribute CPF?",
        "answer": "Yes, CPF contributions are payable from the day you obtained your Singapore Permanent Resident (SPR) status.In the first two years of obtaining the SPR status, you and your employer will contribute to CPF at graduated rates to help you adjust to the lower take-home pay. However, you and your employer have the option toapply jointly to CPF Board to contribute at higher rates.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-determine-the-year-of-my-singapore-permanent-resident-status-for-the-purpose-of-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "How do I determine the year of my Singapore Permanent Resident status for the purpose of CPF contributions?",
        "answer": "The year of Singapore Permanent Resident (SPR) status determines your CPF contribution rates as an SPR.The first year rate applies from the day you obtain your SPR status. This refers to the date indicated on your entry permit (Form 5/5A) issued by the Immigration and Checkpoints Authority of Singapore (ICA). It ends on the last day of the month of your first anniversary of SPR conversion.The second and third year rates apply from the month following the anniversary of your conversion to an SPR.ExampleIf you have obtained your SPR status on 15 January 2020, the start and end dates for first, second and third year of obtaining SPR status are shown in the table below:",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/my-singapore-permanent-resident-status-was-reinstated-with-a-new-re-entry-permit-which-issue-date-should-i-refer-to-determine-my-cpf-contribution-rates",
        "question": "My Singapore Permanent Resident status was reinstated with a new Re-Entry Permit. Which issue date should I refer to determine my CPF contribution rates?",
        "answer": "CPF contributions will be payable from the day your Singapore Permanent Resident (SPR) status was reinstated.However, to determine the year of SPR status, you should refer to the date indicated on your valid Entry Permit (Form 5/5A) issued by the Immigration and Checkpoints Authority of Singapore (ICA).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-just-converted-from-a-singapore-permanent-resident-to-a-singapore-citizen-when-should-i-apply-the-cpf-contribution-rates-applicable-to-singapore-citizens",
        "question": "I have just converted from a Singapore Permanent Resident to a Singapore Citizen. When should I apply the CPF contribution rates applicable to Singapore Citizens?",
        "answer": "The CPF contribution rates for a Singapore Citizen will apply from the date you have converted to a Singapore Citizen.For Ordinary Wages (OW), your employer will need to pro-rate your OW and apply the appropriate rates to determine your CPF contributions. Your employer canwrite to usfor assistance on the computation if the OW for the month exceeds theOW ceilingor if the pro-rated wages are below $750.For Additional Wages (AW), your employer will need to apply the applicable contribution rate depending on when the AW is payable to you.Example:Assuming you are in your second year of Singapore Permanent Resident (SPR) status and become a Singapore Citizen on 15 June 2020:For OWThe second year SPR rate should be applied on the pro-rated wages for the period 1 June to 14 June 2020.The Singapore Citizen rate should be applied on the pro-rated wages for the period of 15 June to 30 June 2020.For AWThe second year SPR rate should be applied on the AW if it is payable between 1 June and 14 June 2020.The Singapore Citizen rate should be applied on the AW if it is payable between 15 June and 30 June 2020.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-minimum-age-to-qualify-for-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "What is the minimum age to qualify for CPF contributions?",
        "answer": "As an employee, you are required to pay CPF contributions as long as you are a Singapore Citizen or Permanent Resident, and are employed in Singapore under acontract of service.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/are-cpf-contributions-payable-when-i-am-on-leave",
        "question": "Are CPF contributions payable when I am on leave?",
        "answer": "When you are on leave, you may still receive wages which attract CPF contributions. Some examples of wages that are given when employees are on leave are as follows:Paid Annual LeavePaid Sick/Hospitalisation LeavePaid Maternity/Paternity/Shared Parental/Childcare leaveYou can find out more about yourleave entitlementson the Ministry of Manpower (MOM) website.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/are-cpf-contributions-payable-on-the-national-service-ns-make-up-pay-when-i-am-away-from-work-for-ns-training",
        "question": "Are CPF contributions payable on the National Service (NS) make-up pay when I am away from work for NS training?",
        "answer": "Your employer should continue to pay CPF contributions on the total wages payable to you, as if you are not away for the NS training. The basic salary and fixed allowance components of your wages, as well as the variable allowances (e.g. overtime pay and allowances) typically paid to you on a monthly basis, as shown in payslips, would attract CPF contributions.ExampleTim earns a basic salary of $2,000 and an average overtime pay of $800 every month. He went on NS training for one week in July.Tim’s employer will have to pay CPF contributions on his typical total monthly wage of $2,800. The employee’s share of CPF contributions will also be based on the total wages of $2,800, and Tim’s employer is entitled to recover this from Tim’s wages.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/are-cpf-contributions-payable-if-i-am-working-in-singapore-for-an-overseas-employer",
        "question": "Are CPF contributions payable if I am working in Singapore for an overseas employer?",
        "answer": "CPF contributions are required on wages payable to any Singapore Citizen or Permanent Resident employee working in Singapore, even if the contract is signed overseas.Employed directly by an overseas employerYou should research your prospective employer to ensure that it has legitimate business presence in Singapore and whether it is registered with Accounting and Corporate Regulatory Authority (ACRA). You should also communicate your CPF rights clearly to the overseas employer before the start of your employment to avoid subsequent disputes. If your CPF contributions are not paid on time or discrepancies are found, please approach your employer for clarification immediately while documentary evidence is fresh. If your employer does not provide you with a satisfactory explanation, you can lodge a report with CPF Board.Do note that enforcement actions would not be effective against an overseas employer with no presence in Singapore and is not registered with ACRA. CPF Board may not be able to assist you in such claims. You may wish to exercise caution when seeking employment with such employer.Employed through an Employer of Record (EOR) to work for an overseas entityYou may consider working for an overseas entity through an EOR. An EOR serves as the employer, taking on employment-related roles such as paying salaries for its employees, withholding taxes, paying employment-related benefits, while its employees perform work for its client, e.g. an overseas company.When you’re employed through an EOR to work for an overseas entity, the EOR is your employer and will be responsible for paying your CPF contributions. Do read through your employment contract with the EOR to ensure your rights are protected.While it may be easier to take enforcement actions against an EOR located in Singapore compared to an overseas entity, you should still exercise caution when seeking employment with an EOR. The recovery of any unpaid CPF contributions depends on the EOR’s financial ability to pay up the arrears. Do check with the EOR early if any discrepancies are found in your CPF contributions, while documentary evidence is fresh and before your CPF arrears accumulate.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-work-for-an-overseas-employer-outside-singapore-and-have-to-return-to-singapore-for-personal-reasons-during-the-covid-19-period-are-cpf-contributions-payable-while-i-work-remotely-in-singapore",
        "question": "I work for an overseas employer outside Singapore and have to return to Singapore for personal reasons during the COVID-19 period. Are CPF contributions payable while I work remotely in Singapore?",
        "answer": "If you are returning to Singapore for personal reasons and will be working remotely in Singapore for your overseas employer during the Stay Home Notice (SHN) period or unable to return overseas after your personal trip due to COVID-19 travel restrictions, CPF contributions are not payable until 30 June 2021 since this is a temporary work arrangement due to COVID-19 restrictions. However, similar to other employees who are working in Singapore, CPF contributions are payable on wages given to employees who are working remotely in Singapore from 1 July 2021 onwards.If you choose to continue working remotely in Singapore not due to COVID-19 travel restrictions, and your employer agrees with this work arrangement, CPF contributions are payable on your wages as they are given in respect of your employment in Singapore.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/are-cpf-contributions-payable-during-my-overseas-training",
        "question": "Are CPF contributions payable during my overseas training?",
        "answer": "CPF contributions are payable during overseas training if you are employed in Singapore but are required to go overseas for the training period.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-cpf-contributions-should-i-receive",
        "question": "How much CPF contributions should I receive?",
        "answer": "Use ourCPF contribution calculatorto calculate the amount of CPF contributions you should receive from your employer.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-additional-wage-aw-ceiling",
        "question": "What is the Additional Wage (AW) ceiling?",
        "answer": "TheAdditional Wage (AW) ceilinglimits the amount of Additional Wages that attract CPF contributions. The AW ceiling is applied on a per employer per calendar year basis. The AW ceiling is computed as follows:$102,000 - Total Ordinary Wage subject to CPF for the yearYou can also compute the amount of AW that is CPF payable using theAdditional Wage ceiling Calculator.Find out more aboutAWand theAW ceiling.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/are-cpf-contributions-payable-by-the-holding-company-or-the-subsidiary-company-if-i-am-seconded-from-the-former-to-latter",
        "question": "Are CPF contributions payable by the holding company or the subsidiary company if I am seconded from the former to latter?",
        "answer": "The employer who had entered into an employment contract with you is required to pay the CPF contributions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-received-a-notification-informing-me-that-my-cpf-contributions-have-been-credited-what-is-this-notification-about",
        "question": "I received a notification informing me that my CPF contributions have been credited. What is this notification about?",
        "answer": "The CPF Contribution Alert is a notification service to inform CPF members (Singapore Citizens and 3rd year onwards Singapore Permanent Residents) when their monthly CPF contributions are credited. For example, you will be notified when your CPF contributions for the month of September 2022 have been credited any day between 1 September 2022 to 31 October 2022.CPF members can receive the notification viatheir registered email address; orpush notification via CPF Mobile app. CPF members will need toenable personalised notificationswithin the mobile app’s settings to start receiving the alert.With the CPF Contribution Alert, you can conveniently verify the wages declared and CPF contributions paid by your employer against your pay slip.If there are any discrepancies or if you have any clarifications, please approach your supervisor or company’s HR immediately so that any error can be rectified early while documentary evidence is fresh. If CPF contributions were paid in error, your employer will need to submit an adjustment or refund request immediately, and no later than one year from the payment date.Find outmore information on the CPF Contribution Alert.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-verify-that-the-cpf-contribution-alert-email-i-received-is-legitimate",
        "question": "How do I verify that the CPF Contribution Alert email I received is legitimate?",
        "answer": "The CPF Contribution Alert is a notification service to inform CPF members who are Singapore Citizens and 3rd year onwards Singapore Permanent Residents when their monthly CPF contributions are credited.Members will receive the email notification at the email address registered with the Board. You maycheck or update your email addresswhich you have earlier registered with us using your Singpass.If you have the CPF Mobile app installed, you will be directed to view your details via the app.To verify if the CPF Contribution Alert email you received is legitimate andavoid falling prey to phishing scams,Ensure that the sender's email address is correctly spelt and ends with\"@e.cpf.gov.sg\".Ensure that the hyperlinks or links you click on has a domain ending with“.gov.sg”.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-receive-the-cpf-contribution-alert-via-cpf-mobile-app",
        "question": "How do I receive the CPF Contribution Alert via CPF Mobile app?",
        "answer": "You canenable personalised notificationsat CPF Mobile app Settings page.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-view-my-cpf-contributions-details-in-the-cpf-contribution-alert-email",
        "question": "How can I view my CPF contributions details in the CPF Contribution Alert email?",
        "answer": "If you have downloaded the latest version of theCPF Mobile app, you will be directed to the CPF Mobile app upon clicking the link.If you have not downloaded the latest version of the CPF Mobile app, or you are viewing on a desktop or laptop, you will be directed to your web browser to view the details.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-check-whether-my-cpf-contributions-are-correct",
        "question": "How can I check whether my CPF contributions are correct?",
        "answer": "You can use ourCPF contribution calculatorto check if your CPF contributions are correct by keying in the wages indicated in your payslip. The Employment Act requires your employer to provide you with an itemised payslip.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-do-if-my-employer-has-overpaid-my-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "What should I do if my employer has overpaid my CPF contributions?",
        "answer": "If your employer has overpaid your CPF contributions, please inform your employer immediately to rectify the errors early while documentary evidence is fresh. Your employer can apply online, for arefund or adjustmentof the overpaid CPF contributions immediately and no later than one year from the payment date.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-was-the-employee-s-share-of-cpf-contributions-indicated-on-my-cpf-contribution-alert-being-derived",
        "question": "How was the employee's share of CPF contributions indicated on my CPF Contribution Alert being derived?",
        "answer": "Your employee’s share of CPF contributions on the CPF Contribution Alert is derived by applying the applicable CPF contribution rate to the total CPF contributions made by your employer.The computation is performed on a per transaction basis, and is not aggregated if your employer had made multiple CPF contributions for you in a particular month. It also does not take into account if you had applied tolimit your employee’s share of contributionon Ordinary Wages for multiple employments. As the employee’s share of CPF contributions indicated on the CPF Contribution Alert are meant to be indicative, please use ourCPF contribution calculatorto determine the exact breakdown of your employee's share of CPF contributions based on your total wages per month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-it-important-for-my-employer-to-declare-accurate-wages-for-me-to-cpf-board",
        "question": "Why is it important for my employer to declare accurate wages for me to CPF Board?",
        "answer": "CPF contributions are computed based on your wages. It is therefore important that your employer declares accurate wage information to CPF Board so that the correct amount of CPF contribution can be verified.It is an offence under the CPF Act to knowingly provide false information to CPF Board. If convicted, a first offender may be fined up to $5,000 or jailed for up to 6 months, or both.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/the-wages-declared-are-correct-but-i-did-not-receive-the-correct-amount-of-wages-what-should-i-do",
        "question": "The wages declared are correct, but I did not receive the correct amount of wages. What should I do?",
        "answer": "If your employer did not pay you the correct amount of wages, you can lodge a report through MOM Workright hotline at 1800-221-9922 or email mom_lrwd@mom.gov.sg.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-my-wages-reflected-as-0-on-my-cpf-contribution-alert",
        "question": "Why are my wages reflected as $0 on my CPF Contribution Alert?",
        "answer": "Your wages are reflected as $0 as your employer has either declared it as $0 or omitted to declare your wages.You should approach your supervisor or company HR for an explanation. The discrepancy could be due to an administrative error, and your employer should rectify it as soon as possible.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-stop-receiving-the-cpf-contribution-alert-via-cpf-mobile-app",
        "question": "How do I stop receiving the CPF Contribution Alert via CPF Mobile app?",
        "answer": "You candisable personalised notificationsat CPF Mobile app Settings page.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-is-a-platform-worker",
        "question": "Who is a platform worker?",
        "answer": "You are a platform worker if you have an agreement with a platform operator to provide ride-hail or delivery services in Singapore to users for the platform operator and from this, derive any payment or benefit in kind. You are also subject to the control of platform operators, such as what tasks are assigned to you and how much you are paid. You will be given an earnings slip that specifies your status as a platform worker.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-is-a-platform-operator",
        "question": "Who is a platform operator?",
        "answer": "Platform operatorsare companies that:a. have an agreement with users to provide ride-hail or delivery services to the users;b. use data to automate decision making relating to platform workers, in areas such as task assignment and how much platform workers are paid per task; andc. impose rules, requirements or prohibitions on platform workers.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-benefits-of-cpf-contributions-for-platform-workers",
        "question": "What are the benefits of CPF contributions for platform workers?",
        "answer": "CPF contributions for platform workers and platform operators will gradually increase over five years from 2025 to 2029 to align to those for employees and employers. This enables you to achieve the same level of housing and retirement adequacy as employees who earn the same amount.The increased CPF contributions will be mandatory for platform workers born in or after 1995 and will be allocated to all three CPF accounts – Ordinary, Special and MediSave account. Older cohorts can choose to opt in to the increased CPF contributions. If you choose not to opt in, you will be required to continue to make MediSave contributions, and will not receive the platform operator share of CPF contributions.To ensure a seamless process, platform operators will submit CPF contributions for all platform workers every month, by deducting your share of CPF contributions from your income as and when you earn. If you do not opt in, platform operators will deduct just the MediSave contributions as and when you earn.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-if-platform-operators-discriminate-against-workers-who-are-mandated-or-opt-in-to-increased-cpf-contributions-such-as-through-job-allocation-or-incentives",
        "question": "What if platform operators discriminate against workers who are mandated or opt in to increased CPF contributions, such as through job allocation or incentives?",
        "answer": "Due to the cohort-based approach where it is mandatory for all platform workers born in 1995 or later to make CPF contributions aligned with that of employees, an increasing proportion of platform workers will be making the increased contributions. It would be advantageous for platform operators in the long term to treat all workers fairly, regardless of whether they opt in, are in the mandatory cohort, or do not opt in.Platform workers also have the option of switching between platform operators. It is therefore in the interest of platform operators to treat all workers fairly from the perspective of worker retention.Tripartite partners will be including additional guidelines in the Tripartite Guidelines on Fair Employment Practices to provide greater clarity that intermediaries such as platform operators should not discriminate based on characteristics that are not related to the job, including when allocating work to platform workers.Finally, Platform Work Associations will have the legal mandate to represent the interests of platform workers. If there are instances of possible discriminatory practices by any platform operator, Platform Work Associations can take this up with the relevant platform operators and, where necessary, inform MOM.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-would-my-platform-operator-submit-my-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "When would my platform operator submit my CPF contributions?",
        "answer": "Platform operators are required to submit CPF contributions on a monthly basis. The due date for CPF contribution is on the last day of the calendar month. Enforcement action would be taken against platform operators who fail to pay by the 14th of the following month (or the next working day if the 14th falls on a Saturday, Sunday or Public Holiday). This includes imposing late payment interest charged at 1.5% per month commencing from the first day after the due date.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-it-mandatory-for-platform-workers-born-in-1995-or-later-to-have-increased-cpf-contributions-aligned-to-employees-while-those-born-before-1995-have-the-option-to-opt-in",
        "question": "Why is it mandatory for platform workers born in 1995 or later to have increased CPF contributions aligned to employees, while those born before 1995 have the option to opt in?",
        "answer": "Younger platform workers have a greater need for CPF contributions because of housing needs and can benefit more from the compounding interest given their longer runway for accumulation.Older platform workers can choose to opt in to the increased CPF contributions if they wish to, as they may have existing plans to finance housing and retirement needs.Older platform workers who do not opt in will continue to be required to make CPF MediSave contributions, and will not receive the platform operator’s share of CPF contributions.Platform operators will deduct the CPF contributions from platform workers’ earnings as and when they earn and transmit them to CPF Board monthly for all platform workers, including the MediSave contributions for those who do not opt in.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-contribution-rates-for-platform-workers",
        "question": "What are the contribution rates for platform workers?",
        "answer": "Your CPF contribution rate depends on your earnings, age and opt-in status. You can verify your CPF contribution amount using theplatform workers CPF Contribution Calculator.The CPF contribution rates for platform workers and platform operators will be gradually increased over five years, by up to 2.5%-pt per year and up to 3.5%-pt per year respectively.The actual schedule for platform workers aged 55 to 70 will depend on progress of the increases to CPF contributions for Senior Workers.If you are born on or after 1 Jan 1995 or have opted in, you can refer to thisfile.If you are born before 1 Jan 1995 and have not opted in, you can refer to thisfile.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-platform-workers-cpf-contributions-be-allocated-to-the-cpf-accounts",
        "question": "How will platform workers’ CPF contributions be allocated to the CPF accounts?",
        "answer": "If you are born on or after 1 Jan 1995 or have opted in, your CPF contributions will be allocated to your Ordinary Account, Special Account and MediSave Account. You can view the allocation rateshere.If you are born before 1 Jan 1995 and have not opted in, your CPF contributions will be allocated to your MediSave Account only.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-benefits-if-i-opt-in-to-increased-cpf-contributions-as-a-platform-worker",
        "question": "What are the benefits if I opt in to increased CPF contributions as a platform worker?",
        "answer": "By opting in, you can enjoy CPF contributions from all your platform operators. The higher CPF contributions would help boost your CPF savings and strengthen your housing and retirement adequacy.You can receive up to 17% in monthly CPF contributions from your platform operator by 2029.Your Ordinary Account savings can be used for your housing loan, freeing up your cash for other needs.If you are above 65, your share of CPF contributions will decrease, but you receive higher total CPF contributions, due to the platform operator share of contributions.The table below provides a comparison for those who have opted in and those who did not opt in.Non-opt-inOpt-inShare of CPF contributionsConsist only your share of CPF contributions. There is no platform operator share of CPF contributions.View contribution rates >Consist of both you and your platform operators’ share of CPF contributions.The CPF contribution rates for both will gradually increase over five years to align with those of employees and employers, reaching up to 20% and 17% respectively by 2029.View contribution rates >Allocation of CPF contributionsMediSave Account onlyAll three CPF accounts:1. Ordinary Account - For housing2. Special Account - For retirement3. MediSave Account - For healthcareView allocation rates >Submission of CPF contributionsYour platform operator will deduct your share of CPF contributions from your earnings and submit them to CPF Board every monthly.You can opt-in for increased CPF contributions via theplatform worker opt-in form.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-check-if-i-have-opted-in-to-increase-my-cpf-contributions-as-a-platform-worker",
        "question": "How do I check if I have opted in to increase my CPF contributions as a platform worker?",
        "answer": "You can use theOpt-in Status Checkerto confirm whether you are in the mandatory cohort or have opted in.If you wish to opt in, you can opt in using theplatform worker Opt-in Form.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-opt-in-as-a-platform-worker-and-how-soon-will-it-take-effect",
        "question": "How do I opt in to increase my CPF contributions as a platform worker and how soon will it take effect?",
        "answer": "You can opt in using theplatform worker opt-in form.If you opt inon or beforethe 15thof a month, the increased contributions will start from the next month.If you opt inafterthe 15thof a month, the increased contributions will start two months later.For example, if you opt in on 15 April, the increased contributions will start from 1 May. If you opt in on 16 April, the increased contributions will start from 1 June.You can use theOpt-in Status Checkerto confirm whether you have opted in and view your opt-in effective month.Note: For opted-in platform workers joining anewplatform operator, the increased CPF contributions will apply depending on when you onboard the new platform operator. If you onboard on or before the 15thof the month, the increased CPF contributions will be made in the following month. If you onboard after the 15thof the month, the increased contributions will be made two months after. For example:If you onboard on 14thFebruary, your increased contributions will apply from 1stMarch. Non-opt-in contribution rates will apply for the month of February.If you onboard on 16thFebruary, your increased contributions will apply from 1stApril. Non-opt-in contribution rates will apply for the month of February and March.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/is-there-a-deadline-to-opt-in-as-a-platform-worker-for-increased-cpf-contribution",
        "question": "Is there a deadline to opt in as a platform worker for increased CPF contribution?",
        "answer": "There is no deadline to opt in. You can consider your decision carefully based on your personal circumstances, before opting in to the increased CPF contributions. The decision to opt in cannot be reversed.You are encouraged to opt in early as this will allow you to have a longer time to grow your CPF savings for your house and retirement needs. If eligible, you can also benefit from the Platform Workers CPF Transition Support.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-am-i-not-able-to-reverse-my-decision-after-i-have-opted-in-to-increase-my-cpf-contributions-as-a-platform-worker",
        "question": "Why am I not able to reverse my decision after I have opted in to increase my CPF contributions as a platform worker?",
        "answer": "Opting in is a concession given to help you increase your CPF contributions. By doing so, you will receive higher overall income, considering the contributions from platform operators. Staying committed to the CPF contributions will also ensure that your CPF savings will accumulate interest over time, thereby building up your housing and retirement adequacy in the long run.Allowing opt-outs will not help build up your housing and retirement adequacy in the long run. It is also not practical for platform operators to track the status of workers and apply the different rates of CPF contributions if workers opt in and out multiple times. This may incur additional business costs for platform operators and make implementation more complicated overall.As there is no deadline to opt in, you can carefully consider your decision based on your personal circumstances, before opting in to increase your CPF contributions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-do-not-opt-in-to-increase-my-cpf-contributions-as-a-platform-worker-will-i-still-receive-cpf-contributions-from-my-platform-operator",
        "question": "If I do not opt in to increase my CPF contributions as a platform worker, will I still receive CPF contributions from my platform operator?",
        "answer": "You will continue to be required to make CPF MediSave contributions, but will not receive the platform operator’s share of CPF contributions.Your platform operator will deduct only your share of CPF contributions from your net earnings and submit these CPF contributions every month. These will be allocated to your MediSave account only.You will not receive the platform operator’s share of CPF contributions and there is no allocation to your Ordinary and Special Accounts.You can refer to thecontributionandallocationtables here.You can use theplatform worker CPF Contribution Calculatorto check the contributions you will receive.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-do-not-opt-in-to-increase-my-cpf-contributions-as-a-platform-worker-will-i-be-subject-to-the-same-cpf-contribution-rate-as-today",
        "question": "If I do not opt in to increase my CPF contributions as a platform worker, will I be subject to the same CPF contribution rate as today?",
        "answer": "The maximum CPF contribution rate for platform workers who do not opt in will remain at 8% to 10.5%, depending on their age and income. They will also only need to make MediSave contribution if they earn above $500 in a month from a platform.Some platform workers may see a difference in CPF contribution rate due to changes in the way CPF contribution is computed and collected. Today, platform workers’ earnings are aggregated across platforms and assessed annually when computing the applicable MediSave contribution. Moving forward, platform operators will be making CPF contribution on a monthly basis and based on earnings on each platform.CPF contribution rates are tiered based on income – a platform worker earning below $750 will have a lower CPF contribution rate. Overall, whether platform workers’ CPF contribution rate is lower or higher as compared to today depends on their individual circumstances. For example, if platform workers have multiple income streams from different platforms, and if their income for each platform is low, platform workers will be subject to the lower CPF contribution that is now applied on a per platform basis.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-need-to-inform-my-platform-operator-once-i-have-opted-in-to-increase-my-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "Do I need to inform my platform operator once I have opted in to increase my CPF contributions?",
        "answer": "You do not need to inform your platform operator once you have opted in to increase your CPF contributions.Your platform operator will confirm your opt-in status with CPF Board directly.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-i-still-be-considered-opted-in-if-i-stop-doing-platform-work-for-a-period-of-time-or-change-platform-operator-after-opting-in",
        "question": "Will I still be considered opted-in if I stop doing platform work for a period of time or change platform operator after opting-in?",
        "answer": "Yes, your opt-in status is permanent after opting in and applies to all platform operators you work with.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-calculate-my-cpf-contributions-based-on-net-earnings-as-a-platform-worker",
        "question": "How do I calculate my CPF contributions based on net earnings as a platform worker?",
        "answer": "Your CPF contribution is calculated based on your net earnings (afterfixed expense deduction amount) and thecontribution rateapplicable to your age, earnings and opt-in status.IllustrationStep 1: Determine your gross earnings: $3,000Step 2: Apply your Fixed Expense Deduction Amount (FEDA): 60% expense for carsStep 3: Compute your net earnings: $3,000 x (1-60%) = $1,200Step 4: Key in your net earnings intoplatform worker CPF Contribution Calculatorto find out your contributions and allocation.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-fixed-expense-deduction-amount",
        "question": "What is the Fixed Expense Deduction Amount?",
        "answer": "Your CPF contributions will be computed based on your net earnings, derived from your gross earnings less a Fixed Expense Deduction Amount (FEDA).The FEDA depends on the mode of transportation you use for platform work.Mode of TransportFEDACars, Vans, Lorries, Trucks60%Motorcycles, Power-assisted Bicycles, Motorised Personal Mobility Devices35%Bicycles, Walkers (Including use of public transport)20%Your net earnings is given by gross earnings less FEDA. For example:Gross earnings: $3,000FEDA: 60% for carsNet earnings: $3,000 x (1-60%) = $1,200",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-fixed-expense-deduction-amount-used-to-calculate-net-earnings-for-platform-workers",
        "question": "Why is Fixed Expense Deduction Amount used to calculate net earnings for platform workers?",
        "answer": "Unlike employees, platform workers may incur significant work expenses which are not reimbursed (e.g. fuel cost). Hence, the computation of CPF will be based on net earnings after taking into consideration such expenses. The net earnings will be based on gross earnings minus the Fixed Expense Deduction Amount (FEDA). The use of FEDA reflects expenses for the vast majority of platform workers.The FEDA takes reference from the Fixed Expense Deduction Ratio developed by IRAS for the computation of net earnings for tax purposes. This is based on actual expense ratios, including industry feedback and surveys on the expenses of workers. Some of the common allowable business expenses incurred by delivery workers and PHC/ taxi drivers include:Rental costsFuel/charging costsRepairs and maintenance costsParkingService fees paid to operatorsMobile phone subscription planRoad taxThe use of FEDA provides significant convenience for both you and your platform operators. You will not have to keep receipts to track and compute actual expenses for your platform work and submit them to your platform operators. Your platform operators will not have to incur additional operating costs to re-compute the CPF contribution based on actual expenses.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-declare-actual-expenses-different-from-fixed-expense-deduction-amount-will-my-cpf-contributions-be-adjusted",
        "question": "Can I declare actual expenses different from Fixed Expense Deduction Amount? Will my CPF contributions be adjusted?",
        "answer": "For the convenience of both platform workers and platform operators, CPF contributions will be based on gross earnings less Fixed Expense Deduction Amount (FEDA), and are not based on declared expenses.This benefits both platform workers and platform operators as you will not have to keep receipts to track and compute actual expenses for your platform work and submit them to your platform operators. Your platform operators will also not have to incur additional operating costs to re-compute the CPF contribution based on actual expenses.FEDA is applied to all platform workers to simplify the computation of CPF contribution for both platform operators and platform workers, regardless of income levels and delivery modes. As such, we will not adjust the CPF contributions based on declared expenses.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-the-fixed-expense-deduction-amount-be-applied-if-i-use-different-modes-of-transport",
        "question": "How will the Fixed Expense Deduction Amount be applied if I use different modes of transport?",
        "answer": "The Fixed Expense Deduction Amount (FEDA) used for calculation of CPF will be based on the mode of transport for the respective job(s) completed.For example:Example 1:Platform worker X uses a bicycle when working for platform operator A, and a car when working for platform operator B.Platform operator A will use the FEDA of 20% to compute the platform worker's net earnings for CPF contributions.Platform operator B will use the FEDA of 60% to compute the platform worker's net earnings for CPF contributions.Example 2:Platform worker Y uses motorcycle from 1 to 15 Jan, and switches to bicycle from 16 to 31 Jan.For jobs completed on 1 to 15 Jan on motorcycle, the platform operator will use the FEDA of 35% to compute the platform worker's net earnings for CPF contributions.For jobs completed on 16 to 31 Jan on bicycle, the platform operator will use the FEDA of 20% to compute the platform worker's net earnings for CPF contributions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-platform-fee-components-included-in-gross-earnings-that-attract-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "What are the platform fee components included in gross earnings that attract CPF contributions?",
        "answer": "In general, payments or benefits which are meant to supplement platform workers’ earnings will attract CPF contribution. This is the same principle for employees who may receive various benefits from employers.However, payments from platform operators meant to reimburse additional expenses already incurred by workers will not be subject to CPF contribution. For example, this can include reimbursements for fuel due to cancelled jobs, and cleaning expenses if customers made a mess in the vehicle.IllustrationCPF contributionsare payableon cash payments that are:fees directly related to your provision of the platform services and/or supplement your earnings (e.g. extended delivery, Sentosa delivery, pin drop fees, order cancellation fee if it is meant to provide earnings to riders, etc)incentives related to the rider’s provision or good performance of platform service, or to reward riders for continued provision of services (e.g. tips, welcome back incentive, new rider incentive, do X get $Y. Any additional cash gifts will also attract CPF if they are related to the provision or performance of the platform service)CPF contributionsarenotpayableon payments that are:not in cash. Any vouchers, or payments-in-kind do not attract CPF.unrelated to the provision or performance of platform service (e.g. referral incentives, incentives for participating in Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) activities, engagement events and focus groups, etc), reimbursement of expenses (e.g. reimbursement for training programme such as safety courses, or order cancellation fee if this is meant to reimburse expenses you incurred to reach a destination)",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-should-tips-especially-tips-in-cash-attract-cpf-contribution",
        "question": "Why should tips, especially tips in cash, attract CPF contribution?",
        "answer": "Platform workers may receive tips from customers through the platform app or in cash. There should be no difference in approach to different forms of tips paid for fairness.In general, we align with the employee-employer model, for all tips to attract CPF contribution. Tips given to hotel and restaurant employees attract CPF contribution today, even if given in cash.Platform operators may make deductions for cash transactions in the same way they deduct for their commissions. Platform operators will need to transfer both the platform operator’s share and platform worker’s share of CPF contributions by 14thof the subsequent month.If platform operators are unable to recover the full platform worker’s share of CPF contributions from platform workers by 14thof the subsequent month, and this is not due to platform operators’ negligence, platform operators may seek consent from platform workers to recover within six months.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/are-cpf-contributions-payable-on-reimbursements-to-platform-workers-for-expenses",
        "question": "Are CPF contributions payable on reimbursements to platform workers for expenses?",
        "answer": "CPF contributions are not payable on payments from platform operators meant to reimburse additional expenses already incurred by workers. For example, this can include reimbursements for fuel due to cancelled jobs, and cleaning expenses if customers made a mess in the vehicle.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-if-i-have-incentives-accrued-across-a-few-months-but-only-paid-later-when-will-the-payments-attract-cpf-contribution",
        "question": "What happens if I have incentives accrued across a few months but only paid later? When will the payments attract CPF contribution?",
        "answer": "Platform earnings and incentives attract CPF contribution when they are due and payable, not when they are accrued.For example, the CPF contributions on an incentive payment in June that is for trips done in May will be computed together with the rest of the June earnings.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-there-no-monthly-earnings-ceiling-for-cpf-contributions-for-platform-workers",
        "question": "Why is there no monthly earnings ceiling for CPF contributions for platform workers?",
        "answer": "A monthly earnings ceiling would not be as relevant for platform workers, who generally do not have a basic monthly wage and are more likely to see high month-to-month variation in earnings.For example, take a platform worker who earns $4,000 in January and $8,000 in February. If a monthly cap of $6,000 is applied, the worker would receive CPF contributions for the full $4,000 earned in January, but would only receive CPF contributions for $6,000 out of the $8,000 earned in February. Thus, the worker would receive less CPF than an employee who has a regular monthly salary of $6,000 per month, and would have received CPF contributions on $6,000 across both months.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/does-the-cpf-annual-ceiling-apply-to-my-net-earnings-as-a-platform-worker",
        "question": "Does the CPF annual ceiling apply to my net earnings as a platform worker?",
        "answer": "Yes, you will be subject to the same CPF annual ceiling of $102,000 as employees. You do not need to make any CPF contributions on net earnings exceeding $102,000 in a year.As CPF contributions are computed separately for each platform operator you work with, this annual ceiling applies on a per-platform basis.If your total net earnings for the year across all platforms have exceeded CPF annual ceiling of $102,000, you canapply for a refundon your share of the contributions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/are-cpf-contributions-payable-if-i-am-working-in-singapore-for-an-overseas-platform-operator",
        "question": "Are CPF contributions payable if I am working in Singapore for an overseas platform operator?",
        "answer": "CPF contributions are required on net earnings to any Singapore Citizen or Permanent Resident doing platform work in Singapore, even if the platform operator is located overseas. You should communicate your CPF rights clearly to the overseas platform operator before the start of your platform work to avoid subsequent disputes.You should also research your prospective platform operator to ensure that it has legitimate business presence in Singapore and is registered with Accounting and Corporate Regulatory Authority (ACRA). If your CPF contributions are not paid on time or discrepancies are found, please approach your platform operator for clarification immediately while documentary evidence is fresh. If your platform operator does not provide you with a satisfactory explanation, you can lodge a report with CPF Board or MOM.Do note that CPF Board may not be able to assist you in claims against an overseas platform operator with no presence in Singapore and who is not registered with ACRA. You may wish to exercise caution when working with such platform operators.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-work-for-multiple-platforms-how-will-cpf-contributions-be-calculated-for-each-platform",
        "question": "If I work for multiple platforms, how will CPF contributions be calculated for each platform?",
        "answer": "All your platform operators will calculate and contribute CPF for you separately (i.e. per-platform basis).For example, Mr Lim works for platform operator A having a net earning of $3,000 and platform operator B, having a net earning of $6,000. Platform operator A will contribute CPF contributions on the $3,000 while platform operator B will contribute CPF contributions on the $6,000.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/which-platform-operator-should-pay-my-cpf-if-there-is-a-subcontracting-arrangement",
        "question": "Which platform operator should pay my CPF if there is a subcontracting arrangement?",
        "answer": "If you are a platform worker, the company that satisfies the definition of platform operator in relation to the work you do is responsible for paying your CPF contributions.If unsure, pleasewrite to us.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-am-working-for-more-than-one-platform-operator-can-i-choose-to-contribute-cpf-on-the-earnings-from-only-one-of-my-platform-operators",
        "question": "If I am working for more than one platform operator, can I choose to contribute CPF on the earnings from only one of my platform operators?",
        "answer": "No, CPF contributions will be made by all platform operators you work with (i.e. per-platform basis).However, if your total net earnings for the year across all platforms have exceeded CPF annual ceiling of $102,000, you canapply for a refund on your share of the contributions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-apply-for-refund-on-cpf-contributions-paid-above-the-cpf-annual-ceiling-of-102-000",
        "question": "Can I apply for refund on CPF contributions paid above the CPF annual ceiling of $102,000?",
        "answer": "If your total net earnings under a single platform operator exceed $102,000, your platform operator will apply for a refund on the excess CPF contributions from CPF Board. After receiving the refund, your platform operator will refund your share of excess CPF contributions to you.If your total earnings acrossmultipleplatform operators exceed $102,000, you can apply for a refund on your share of the contributions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-still-need-to-declare-my-income-to-iras-and-contribute-medisave-in-the-following-year-for-my-self-employed-work",
        "question": "Do I still need to declare my income to IRAS and contribute MediSave in the following year for my self-employed work?",
        "answer": "From 2025, if you are only receiving platform earnings in the year, platform operators would have deducted and paid the CPF contributions on your platform earnings for you every month. Therefore, you do not need to make your own MediSave contributions on such platform earnings in the following year.If you derive self-employed income from non-platform work (e.g. giving tuition, or taxi street-hail jobs), you will still need to pay MediSave contributions on these sources of income in the following year on your own, as per status quo, after you have declared your net trade income to IRAS. CPF Board will notify you of the MediSave contributions you need to make.For tax purposes, you will still need to declare your net trade income derived from platform work and any non-platform work in the year as a self-employed person (SEP) toIRAS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-my-platform-operator-s-contributions-be-used-to-offset-outstanding-medisave-contributions-from-my-past-self-employed-work",
        "question": "Can my platform operator’s contributions be used to offset outstanding MediSave contributions from my past self-employed work?",
        "answer": "Your CPF contributions (including platform operator’s share, if any) are meant for platform work done from 2025.You will need to make separate arrangements to settle any outstanding MediSave contributions on past income earned as a self-employed person.You may reach out to CPFB to arrange affordableinstalment planson your past MediSave obligations.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/as-a-taxi-driver-who-takes-both-ride-hail-and-street-hail-jobs-how-should-i-make-cpf-contributions-for-my-earnings",
        "question": "As a taxi driver who takes both ride-hail and street-hail jobs, how should I make CPF contributions for my earnings?",
        "answer": "You will need to make CPF contributions on ride-hail and street-hail earnings separately.For ride-hail earnings, platform operators will deduct and make CPF contributions for you.For street-hail earnings, you will need to contribute MediSave on your own in the following year after you have declared your net trade income to IRAS. CPF Board will inform you of your MediSave payable once IRAS has assessed your income.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-am-concurrently-a-full-time-employee-doing-platform-work-do-i-still-need-to-make-cpf-contributions-on-platform-earnings",
        "question": "If I am concurrently a full-time employee doing platform work, do I still need to make CPF contributions on platform earnings?",
        "answer": "Yes, your platform operator will deduct the required CPF contributions from your net earnings from platform work. There is no change to your CPF contributions as an employee. Your employer must still deduct and make CPF contributions for you.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-am-concurrently-a-full-time-employee-doing-platform-work-will-my-employers-be-notified-of-my-platform-work-because-of-the-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "If I am concurrently a full-time employee doing platform work, will my employers be notified of my platform work because of the CPF contributions?",
        "answer": "No. Your employers will not be notified of your CPF contributions from platform work.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-ensure-that-the-cpf-contributions-i-received-are-accurate",
        "question": "How can I ensure that the CPF contributions I received are accurate?",
        "answer": "You can use theplatform worker CPF Contribution Calculatorto check if your CPF contributions are correct by keying in yournet earnings.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/where-can-i-view-the-cpf-contributions-made-by-my-platform-operator",
        "question": "Where can I view the CPF contributions made by my platform operator?",
        "answer": "To view details of your CPF contributions on platform work,you can select the filter “Employment Contributions” under the Transaction History, which you can access after logging in to the CPF website using your Singpass. Your platform worker CPF contributions will be indicated as “[Platform operator name] (Platform)”.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-i-receive-a-notification-informing-me-that-my-cpf-contributions-have-been-credited-by-my-platform-operators",
        "question": "Will I receive a notification informing me that my CPF contributions have been credited by my platform operators?",
        "answer": "Yes, you will receive a CPF Contribution Alert. The CPF Contribution Alert is a notification service to inform CPF members, including platform workers, when their monthly CPF contributions are credited. For example, you will be notified when your CPF contributions for the month of March 2025 have been credited any day between 1 March 2025 to 30 April 2025.CPF members can receive the notification via:their registeredemail address; orpush notification via CPF Mobile app. CPF members will need toenable personalised notificationswithin the mobile app’s settings to start receiving the Alert.With the CPF Contribution Alert, you can conveniently verify the CPF contributions paid by your platform operator against your earnings slip.If there are any discrepancies or if you have any clarifications, please approach your platform operator immediately so that any error can be rectified early while documentary evidence is fresh. If CPF contributions were paid in error, your platform operator will need to submit an adjustment or refund request immediately, and no later than one year from the payment date.Find outmore information on the CPF Contribution Alert.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-is-the-platform-worker-s-share-of-cpf-contributions-on-my-cpf-contribution-alert-derived",
        "question": "How is the platform worker’s share of CPF contributions on my CPF Contribution Alert derived?",
        "answer": "Your platform worker’s share of CPF contributions on the CPF Contribution Alert is derived by applying the applicable CPF contribution rate to the total CPF contributions made by your platform operator.You will receive one Contribution Alert for each contribution made by your platform operator(s). As the platform worker’s share of CPF contributions indicated on the CPF Contribution Alert is meant to be indicative, please use theplatform worker CPF Contribution Calculatorto determine the exact breakdown of your platform worker's share of CPF contributions based on your net earnings per month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-do-if-my-platform-operator-did-not-pay-me-the-correct-amount-of-earnings-and-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "What should I do if my platform operator did not pay me the correct amount of earnings and CPF contributions?",
        "answer": "ThePlatform Workers Actrequires your platform operator to provide you with an itemised earnings slip, which will include any deductions from your earnings. You should verify the CPF paid as declared by your platform operator against the deductions shown in your earnings slip.If there are any discrepancies or if you have any clarifications, please approach your platform operator immediately so that any errors can be rectified early while documentary evidence is fresh. Your platform operator is expected to self-rectify any errors immediately.If you were not paid the right amount of earnings, you should approach your union if your platform operator is unionised or if you are a union member for advice. If you are not a union member, you could approach the Tripartite Alliance for Dispute Management (TADM) for advice.Once TADM has concluded assessing your claims and determined the earnings due to you, you can lodge a report with CPF Board. The Board will compute the CPF contributions payable.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-do-if-my-platform-operator-did-not-pay-my-cpf-contributions-on-time",
        "question": "What should I do if my platform operator did not pay my CPF contributions on time?",
        "answer": "If you are not paid your CPF contributions on time, you should approach your platform operator for an explanation and ask when your platform operator will be making the payment.If your platform operator does not provide you with a satisfactory response, you can lodge a report with CPF Board.The Board takes a serious view of platform operators who default on CPF contributions. The due date for CPF contributions is on the last day of the calendar month. Enforcement action would be taken against platform operators who fail to pay by the 14th of the following month (or the next working day if the 14th falls on a Saturday, Sunday or Public Holiday). This includes imposing late payment interest charged at 1.5% per month commencing from the first day after the due date. In cases where the company is in financial difficulty, CPF arrears may not always be recoverable despite our enforcement efforts.You mayfind outmore on your rights and platform operators’ obligations under the CPF Act and the Platform Workers Act.If you face difficulty servicing your Housing Development Board (HDB) loans, you may contactHDBto explore possible alternative housing repayment options.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-i-lose-out-on-interest-on-my-cpf-contributions-if-my-platform-operator-pays-my-cpf-contributions-late",
        "question": "Will I lose out on interest on my CPF contributions if my platform operator pays my CPF contributions late?",
        "answer": "You will not lose out on the interest when your platform operator pays late. The interest will be credited to you when CPF Board recovers the CPF arrears from your platform operator.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-to-my-outstanding-cpf-contributions-if-my-platform-operator-is-made-a-bankrupt-or-is-under-liquidation-or-winding-up",
        "question": "What happens to my outstanding CPF contributions if my platform operator is made a bankrupt, or is under liquidation or winding up?",
        "answer": "In the event that a platform operator is made a bankrupt, or is under liquidation or winding up, an Official Assignee or Official Receiver/Liquidator respectively, will be appointed by the High Court, company’s shareholders or creditors (depending on the company’s situation). The Board will file the claims for owed CPF contributions for affected platform workers with the Official Assignee or Official Receiver/Liquidator, as the case may be.If the platform operator is made a bankrupt, the Official Assignee will investigate into the conduct and affairs of the bankrupt and also recover and realise his assets for distribution to the bankrupt’s creditors. For a company that is under liquidation or winding up, the Official Receiver/Liquidator will investigate into the affairs and assets of the company, the conduct of its officers (including the company directors) and the claims of creditors and third parties.Any proceeds realised by the Official Assignee or Official Receiver/Liquidator will be paid in the following order in accordance with the law:costs and expenses incurred by the Official Assignee or Official Receiver/Liquidator, costs of applicant for the bankruptcy or winding up order,salary (including allowance or reimbursement),retrenchment benefits or ex-gratia payments under employment contracts,amounts due in respect of workmen’s compensation under the Work Injury Compensation Act,employee’s superannuation or provident funds (e.g. CPF)employee's remuneration in respect of vacation leave, etcplatform workers’ earningsplatform workers’ Work Injury Compensationplatform workers’ superannuation or provident funds (e.g. CPF)The bankruptcy, liquidation or winding up process will take time, and could take years to complete for complex cases. If you wish to know more about the bankruptcy, liquidation or winding up process, you can visitMinistry of Law – Insolvency Office website.It is your platform operators’ obligation to pay the CPF contributions for you. However, if your platform operator is made a bankrupt, or is under liquidation or winding up, the owed CPF contributions may not be recovered despite the Board’s actions. To find out the status of the bankruptcy administration, liquidation or winding up, you can contact the Official Assignee or Official Receiver/Liquidator directly.We would like to take this opportunity to advise you that if your platform operator is in financial difficulties, while CPF Board will continue to take enforcement actions, you should be mentally prepared that the CPF owed may not be recoverable.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-voluntary-contributions-can-i-make-as-a-platform-worker",
        "question": "How much voluntary contributions can I make as a platform worker?",
        "answer": "The maximum amount you can voluntarily contribute is the difference between the CPF Annual Limit of $37,740 and the mandatory CPF contributions made for the calendar year.Do remember to consider your mandatory CPF contributions which you will be receiving for the calendar year, before making voluntary contributions. If the total mandatory CPF contributions and voluntary contributions exceed the CPF Annual Limit in the calendar year, any excess voluntary contributions will be refunded without interest in the following year.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-tax-relief-will-i-get-for-cpf-contributions-made-as-a-platform-worker",
        "question": "How much tax relief will I get for CPF contributions made as a platform worker?",
        "answer": "If you are mandated or have opted in for increased CPF contributions:you will be allowed tax relief for your share of the mandatory CPF contributions. You will not have to pay tax on your platform operators’ share of mandatory CPF contributions.during the transitional period from 2025 to 2028, tax relief will also be allowed on voluntary CPF contributions to all three accounts, subject to a cap(based on the difference in the contribution rate in 2029, and at the contribution rate as at 31 December of the relevant year in which the voluntary contribution is made).once the mandatory CPF contribution rates have fully aligned with that for employees by 2029, only mandatory CPF contributions will be eligible for tax relief, similar to employees who do not enjoy tax relief for their voluntary CPF contributions to three CPF accounts.If you are not mandated and do not opt in for increased CPF contributions, you will enjoy the same tax relief as self-employed persons. If you make voluntary CPF contributions to all three CPF accounts, both your mandatory and voluntary CPF contributions will continue to be eligible for tax relief of up to 37% of your net trade income or $37,740, whichever is lower.Regardless of your opt-in status, you are eligible for CPF cash top-up relief if your platform operator makes cash top-ups on your behalf to your Retirement Account/ Special Account/ MediSave Account. This is aligned with the current treatment for employees.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-is-a-self-employed-person",
        "question": "Who is a self-employed person?",
        "answer": "A self-employed person (SEP) is someone who performs work for others under a contract for service.If you earn an income by buying and selling goods or from providing professional or personal services, you’re an SEP. Examples of SEPs include hawkers, taxi drivers, freelancers, sole proprietors or a partner in a partnership.Visit theInland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) websiteto read more on the definition of an SEP.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/where-can-i-find-the-application-forms-pertaining-to-self-employed-matters",
        "question": "Where can I find the application forms pertaining to self-employed matters?",
        "answer": "You can find the list of application forms applicable to the Self-Employed Scheme atCPF website> Tools and services > Forms and e-applications > Growing Your Savings >CPF contributions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-need-to-register-myself-as-a-self-employed-person",
        "question": "Do I need to register myself as a self-employed person?",
        "answer": "You do not need to register your self-employed status with CPF Board.You will be considered a self-employed person if you:Declare your net trade income to the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS);Declare your net trade income to CPF Board*; orMake MediSave contributions under Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) Scheme.*for Work Year 2022 (WY2022) and earlier",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-long-does-it-take-to-process-applications-relating-to-the-self-employed-scheme",
        "question": "How long does it take to process applications relating to the Self-Employed Scheme?",
        "answer": "The applications relating to the Self-Employed Scheme will generally be processed within the service standards as stated in the table below. We strive to process all submitted applications within the service standard and will let you know if more time is needed.ServiceNormal Processing TimeManage your MediSave payableOnline: 12 working daysManual: 15 working daysRefund of CPF/MediSave contributions by self-employed personOnline: 12 working daysManual: 15 working daysThis includes time needed to liaise with other parties or seek clarification on your refund application.Adjust self-employed contributionsMake full payment for your MediSave payablesa.  Payment via PayNow / OCBC Digital: Will generally be processed almost instantlyb. Cash: 10 working daysNote: Please note that cheque payment is no longer accepted for Self-Employed contributions with effect from 1 January 2024.Self-employed person income declaration formOnline: 8 working daysManual: 10 working days",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-declare-my-annual-net-trade-income-online-as-a-self-employed-person",
        "question": "How do I declare my annual net trade income online as a self-employed person?",
        "answer": "For Work Year 2023 (WY2023) onwardsAll Net Trade Income (NTI) declarations for Work Year 2023 (Year of Assessment 2024) can be made with the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) by filing a tax return. There is no need to file separate declarations with CPF Board.If you receive a notification (via letter/form/SMS) to file tax from IRAS or you meet the requirement to file tax (i.e. NTI above $6,000 and/or Total Income above $22,000), please complete and submit the tax return to IRAS directly. The income tax filing period is from 1 March to 18 April annually.If you do not receive a notification from IRAS or do not meet the requirement to file tax, you can declare your self-employed net trade income (NTI) to IRAS viamyTax Portalwhich will be available from 1 March to 31 October annually for taxpayers to e-File tax returns.Once IRAS has assessed your income for the year, your assessed NTI will be transmitted to the Board. You can check your updated NTI records by logging in to the Self-employment dashboard with your Singpass.For Work Year 2022 (WY2022) or earlierIf you were not issued a Notice of Assessment (NOA) by IRAS and wish to declare NTI for work years prior to 2023, you canwrite to ususing your Singpass.If you have declared your NTI with IRAS, you need not declare your income again to CPF Board.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-if-i-had-declared-my-net-trade-income-nti-wrongly-as-a-self-employed-person-or-employee-income",
        "question": "What if I had declared my net trade income (NTI) wrongly as a self-employed person or employee income?",
        "answer": "If you have wrongly declared your net trade income (NTI) to the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS), please visit the IRAS website atwww.iras.gov.sg, call them at 1800-356 8300, or write to them via myTax Mail onmyTax Portalusing your Singpass. Once IRAS has assessed your income for that year, you will receive a revised Notice of Computation (NOC) informing you of the revised MediSave payable. IRAS will also transmit the assessed NTI records to the CPF Board.If you have wrongly declared your NTI to the Board for Work Year 2022 or earlier, pleasewrite to ususing your Singpass.Once the Board has received your income declaration, you can check your updated NTI records by logging in to the Self-employment dashboard with your Singpass.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-registered-with-the-accounting-and-corporate-regulatory-authority-acra-as-a-partner-for-my-business-am-i-considered-a-self-employed-person-or-an-employee-of-the-partnership",
        "question": "I am registered with the Accounting and Corporate Regulatory Authority (ACRA) as a partner for my business. Am I considered a self-employed person or an employee of the partnership?",
        "answer": "For more information on Partnerships, please visit theInland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) website.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-a-board-member-director-am-i-considered-a-self-employed-person-and-do-i-have-to-contribute-to-my-cpf",
        "question": "I am a Board Member/ Director. Am I considered a self-employed person, and do I have to contribute to my CPF?",
        "answer": "It depends on the nature of your relationship with the company, and the nature of the moneys received.If you’re engaged as a Board Member or Director under a contract of employment (or Contract of Service) with the company, you’ll have to contribute to your CPF as an employee.If you’re engaged in a business, profession or vocation of providing services as a Board Member or Director to companies, you’ll have to contribute to your MediSave as a self-employed person (SEP).Please visit theInland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) websitefor the differences in treatment between employees and SEPs.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-deregister-my-self-employed-status-with-cpf-board-if-i-am-no-longer-self-employed",
        "question": "How do I deregister my self-employed status with CPF Board if I am no longer self-employed?",
        "answer": "You do not need to deregister your self-employed status with CPF Board.You will only need to make MediSave contributions if you earn an annual Net Trade Income (NTI) of more than $6,000. Your MediSave payable will be computed based on your age and NTI declared.If you are no longer in self-employment, please note that you will still need to settle any outstanding MediSave payable, as it is compulsory under the CPF Act to contribute to your MediSave Account for the years that you were self-employed.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-not-a-self-employed-person-why-did-i-receive-a-notice-of-computation-noc-from-iras",
        "question": "I am not a self-employed person. Why did I receive a Notice of Computation (NOC) from IRAS?",
        "answer": "You are registered as a self-employed in our records as the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) had transmitted your net trade income to the Board, under your occupation as a Commission Agent. Examples of Commission Agents are Property Agents, Insurance Agents, Multi-Level Marketing Members, etc. Please note that if you are receiving commission for your services, you are considered a self-employed person (SEP).SEPs will receive a Notice of Computation (NOC) from IRAS informing them of the MediSave payable (if any), after IRAS has completed the income assessment for the year.If you disagree/require further clarification on the assessed income by IRAS, you can email them through the securedMyTax Mail. Should IRAS re-classify your income, your self-employed status and MediSave payable (if any) will also be updated accordingly.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-declare-my-net-trade-income-from-work-year-2023-year-of-assessment-2024-onwards",
        "question": "How can I declare my net trade income from Work Year 2023 (Year of Assessment 2024) onwards?",
        "answer": "For Work Year 2023 (WY2023) onwardsAll Net Trade Income (NTI) declarations for Work Year 2023 (Year of Assessment 2024) can be made with the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) by filing a tax return. There is no need to file separate declarations with CPF Board.If you receive a notification (via letter/form/SMS) to file tax from IRAS, or you meet the requirement to file tax (i.e. NTI above $6,000 and/or Total Income above $22,000), please complete and submit the tax return to IRAS directly. The income tax filing period is from 1 March to 18 April annually.If you do not receive a notification from IRAS or do not meet the requirement to file tax, you can declare your self-employed net trade income (NTI) to IRAS viamyTax Portalwhich will be available from 1 March to 31 October annually for taxpayers to e-File tax returns.Once IRAS has assessed your income for the year, your assessed NTI will be transmitted to the Board. You can check your updated NTI records by logging in to the Self-employment dashboard with your Singpass.If you have declared your NTI with IRAS, you need not declare your income again to CPF Board.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-i-know-when-my-digital-notice-of-cpf-contributions-for-self-employed-persons-is-ready-for-viewing",
        "question": "How will I know when my digital notice of CPF contributions for self-employed persons is ready for viewing?",
        "answer": "You will receive an email notification to view your digital notice of CPF contributions for self-employed persons via the self-employment dashboard when it is ready. If you do not have a registered email with CPF Board, you will receive an SMS notification instead. If you do not have a registered email address or mobile number, your notice will be sent to you in hardcopy at your residential address.To ensure you receive prompt alerts when your notice of CPF contributions for self-employed persons is ready, please update your contact details via theaccount services pageafter logging in with your Singpass.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-will-cpf-board-start-issuing-the-notice-of-cpf-contributions-for-self-employed-persons-digitally",
        "question": "When will CPF Board start issuing the notice of CPF contributions for self-employed persons digitally?",
        "answer": "Since 1 November 2024, CPF Board has been issuing the notice of CPF contributions for self-employed persons digitally.You will receive an email or SMS notification to view your digital notice via theself-employment dashboardwhen it is ready.If you wish to receive a hardcopy notice instead, please update your notification preference by completing thenotification preference form. Your updated notification preference will take effect for any subsequent notice of CPF contributions for self-employed persons.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-do-if-i-wish-to-receive-the-notice-of-cpf-contributions-for-self-employed-persons-in-hardcopy",
        "question": "What should I do if I wish to receive the notice of CPF contributions for self-employed persons in hardcopy?",
        "answer": "If you wish to receive your notice of CPF contributions for self-employed persons via hardcopy instead, you may update your notification preference via thenotification preference formusing your Singpass. The hardcopy notice will be mailed to you at your residential address.Your updated notification preference will take effect for any subsequent notice of CPF contributions thereafter.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-previously-chosen-to-receive-my-notice-of-cpf-contributions-for-self-employed-persons-in-hardcopy-can-I-still-change-my-preference",
        "question": "I have previously chosen to receive my notice of CPF contributions for self-employed persons in hardcopy. Can I still change my preference?",
        "answer": "Yes. Regardless of your current preference, you can update your preference anytime by completing thenotification preference form.Your updated notification preference will take effect for any subsequent notice of CPF contributions for self-employed persons thereafter.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-updated-my-preference-via-the-notification-preference-form-does-this-preference-apply-to-other-notifications-sent-by-cpf-board",
        "question": "I have updated my preference via the notification preference form. Does this preference apply to other notifications sent by CPF Board?",
        "answer": "The notification preference only applies to the notice of CPF contributions for self-employed persons. Your updated notification preference will take effect for any subsequent notice of CPF contributions thereafter.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-period-for-income-declaration-to-iras",
        "question": "What is the period for income declaration to IRAS?",
        "answer": "If you receive a notification (via letter/form/SMS) to file tax from IRAS, or you meet the requirement to file tax (i.e. NTI above $6,000 and/or Total Income above $22,000), please complete and submit the tax return to IRAS directly. The income tax filing period is from 1 March to 18 April annually.If you do not receive a notification from IRAS or do not meet the requirement to file tax, you can declare your self-employed net trade income (NTI) to IRAS viamyTax Portalwhich will be available from 1 March to 31 October annually for taxpayers to e-File tax returns.Once IRAS has assessed your income for the year, your assessed NTI will be transmitted to the Board. You can check your updated NTI records by logging in to the Self-employment dashboard with your Singpass.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-used-to-declare-my-income-to-cpfb-to-determine-my-wis-excess-caye-contributions-for-the-year-why-is-cpfb-no-longer-accepting-income-declarations",
        "question": "I used to declare my income to CPFB to determine my Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)/excess Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions for the year. Why is CPFB no longer accepting income declarations?",
        "answer": "The Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) has been appointed as the single collecting agency for all SEPs’ income information from Work Year 2023 (or Year of Assessment 2024). This means that all SEPs will now declare their net trade income (NTI), including all other sources of income derived from Work Year 2023, to IRAS. SEPs who receive a notification (via letter/form/SMS) to file tax from IRAS or meet the requirement to file tax (i.e. NTI above $6,000 and/or Total Income above $22,000), will need to complete and submit the tax return to IRAS directly. The income tax filing period is from 1 March to 18 April annually.SEPs who do not receive a notification from IRAS or do not meet the requirement to file tax may declare their self-employed net trade income (NTI), including all other sources of income derived from Work Year 2023, to IRAS viamyTax Portalwhich will be available from 1 March to 31 October annually for taxpayers to e-File tax returns.SEPs will receive a Notice of Computation (NOC) from IRAS if they are required to make MediSave contributions, after IRAS has issued a Notice of Assessment for the relevant Year of Assessment.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-if-my-net-trade-income-for-the-year-is-zero-or-negative",
        "question": "What if my net trade income for the year is zero or negative?",
        "answer": "If your net trade income (NTI) is zero or negative for the year, you do not need to make any MediSave contribution for the year.You will still be required to pay your outstanding MediSave payable for the years you were self-employed.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-net-trade-income",
        "question": "What is net trade income?",
        "answer": "Net trade income is your gross trade income minus all allowable business expenses, capital allowances and trade losses as determined by the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-more-than-one-source-of-trade-income-do-i-have-to-contribute-to-medisave-for-all-of-them",
        "question": "I have more than one source of trade income. Do I have to contribute to MediSave for all of them?",
        "answer": "Your MediSave contributions are based on the annual net trade income (NTI) from all your trades. If you have a yearly NTI of more than $6,000 from all your trades, you’re required to make contributions to your MediSave Account.You can refer to thisexampleof how MediSave payable is computed on multiple sources of NTI.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-apply-to-adjust-my-cpf-contributions-from-the-firm-s-account-to-a-self-employed-person-s-account",
        "question": "How do I apply to adjust my CPF Contributions from the firm's account to a self-employed person's account?",
        "answer": "You may submit an online application viamy cpfdigital servicesusing Singpass to adjust your CPF Contributions from the firm’s account to your self-employed account.The adjustment request must be made within one year from the date of payment.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-a-self-employed-person-can-i-contribute-to-my-medisave-together-with-my-employees-cpf-using-the-cpf-payment-form-cpf-91",
        "question": "I am a self-employed person. Can I contribute to my MediSave together with my employees' CPF using the CPF Payment Form (CPF 91)?",
        "answer": "You’re required to make your MediSave payable separately from your employees' CPF. This is because payments made using the CPF Payment Form (CPF 91) will be credited as employer contributions and will not be recognized as self-employed payments.If you would like to make CPF contributions as a self-employed person, there arevarious waysto do so.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-benefits-of-contributing-to-medisave-by-giro",
        "question": "What are the benefits of contributing to MediSave by GIRO?",
        "answer": "GIRO allows you to contribute to your MediSave Account over a period of 12 monthly instalments. It is most convenient as the contributions are automatically deducted from your bank account and you can easily monitor them. Contributing to MediSave by GIRO also provides a hassle-free licence application and renewal process.You may apply to pay via GIRO online (list of participating banks) or by mail (for other banks).Payment modeDetailsGIROUsingmy cpfdigital services (list of participating banks)Log in with your Singpass.Submit theSet up GIRO for MediSave contributionsapplication.Check the status of your GIRO application via Activities.Mail (for other banks)Download and complete theApply for GIRO for MediSave Contributionsform (FORM SE GIRO (PDF, 0.2MB)).Mail it to the address printed overleaf of the GIRO application form.We will notify you of your GIRO application status once the bank has processed it.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-make-my-medisave-contributions",
        "question": "How can I make my MediSave contributions?",
        "answer": "There are several ways you can contribute to your MediSave. The most convenient way is via GIRO, which allows automatic monthly deductions from your bank account.Payment modeDetailsGIROUsingmy cpfdigital services (list of participating banks)Log in with your Singpass.Submit theSet up GIRO for MediSave contributionsapplication.Check the status of your GIRO application via Activities.Mail (for other banks)Download and complete theApply for GIRO for MediSave Contributionsform (FORM SE GIRO (PDF, 0.2MB)).Mail it to the address printed overleaf of the GIRO application form.We will notify you of your GIRO application status once the bank has processed it.PayNow QRRequest an instalment plan or contribute to your MediSave payable in full via theManage your MediSave payableform.Cash/ NETS/ CashCardMake MediSave contributions (any amount) via cash, NETS or CashCard at any SingPost branch.You may view your MediSave contributions on the Self-employment dashboard. To accessmy cpfDigital Services – Self-employment dashboard, please log in to theCPF websiteusing your Singpass.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-check-whether-i-have-any-medisave-payable-as-a-self-employed-person",
        "question": "How can I check whether I have any MediSave payable as a self-employed person?",
        "answer": "You can check your MediSave payable by logging in to theSelf-employment dashboardusing your Singpass.You can apply for yourSingpass onlineif you do not have one.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-apply-for-a-licence-renew-my-licence-if-i-have-outstanding-medisave-payable",
        "question": "Can I apply for a licence/renew my licence if I have outstanding MediSave payable?",
        "answer": "Licensing authorities will only process your licence application/renewal if your MediSave payable is up-to-date, that is, you have either paid your MediSave in full or have an active GIRO arrangement with the Board to settle your MediSave payable via instalments.You can check your MediSave payable statement, pay your MediSave contributions in full or request for an instalment plan on theSelf-employment dashboard. To accessmy cpfDigital Services – Self-employment dashboard, please log in to theCPF websiteusing your Singpass.You can apply for yourSingpass onlineif you do not have one. You may wish to note that you will be cleared for licence application/renewal after making a full payment or upon your first successful GIRO deduction.Refer to thisguidefor step-by-step instructions on retrieving information on your eligibility for licence application/ renewal.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-do-not-earn-any-net-trade-income-for-the-year-can-i-renew-my-licence",
        "question": "If I do not earn any net trade income for the year, can I renew my licence?",
        "answer": "You can renew your licence so long as there is no outstanding MediSave payable or you have signed up to pay your MediSave payable via monthly GIRO instalments.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-do-not-intend-to-renew-my-licence-do-i-need-to-settle-my-outstanding-medisave-payable",
        "question": "If I do not intend to renew my licence, do I need to settle my outstanding MediSave payable?",
        "answer": "You’re required to pay your outstanding MediSave payable even if you do not intend to renew your licence.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-medisave-important-for-self-employed-persons",
        "question": "Why is MediSave important for self-employed persons?",
        "answer": "MediSave can be used for healthcare needs, such as to pay for MediShield Life premiums or hospitalisation cost. It is therefore important that self-employed persons set aside a portion of their income to build up their MediSave savings, in anticipation of their future healthcare needs, especially during old age when they have stopped working.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-benefits-do-self-employed-persons-enjoy-from-making-medisave-contributions",
        "question": "What benefits do self-employed persons enjoy from making MediSave contributions?",
        "answer": "When you contribute to MediSave, you enjoy:Up to 6% interest1per annum on your MediSave savingsSavings in the MediSave Account earn 4% interest1per annum, and the first $60,000 of your combined CPF balances earns an additional 1% interest per annum. Members aged 55 and above will also enjoy an additional 1% interest per annum on the first $30,000 of their combined CPF balance from 1 January 2016.Tax relief of up to 37% of your annual net trade income (NTI), the CPF Annual Limit of $37,740 or the actual amount contributed by you, whichever is lower. No tax relief is given if your assessed NTI for the year of assessment is zero or negative.Use of MediSave savingsto pay for a variety of medical expensesHassle-free licence application and renewalYou may also be eligible forWorkfare Income Supplement (WIS)payouts of up to $2,800 annually.1Based on the current 4% interest rate floor for MediSave savings. Refer toCPF interest ratesfor the current rates.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-still-have-to-contribute-to-my-medisave-if-i-am-both-a-self-employed-person-as-well-as-an-employee-working-in-another-company",
        "question": "Do I still have to contribute to my MediSave if I am both a self-employed person as well as an employee working in another company?",
        "answer": "If you earn an annualnet trade incomeof more than $6,000, you are required to contribute to your MediSave Account as a self-employed person (SEP).CPF contribution is based on your total income. Therefore, an SEP who is also an employee at the same time, is required to contribute to MediSave as an SEP. This is the same for employees who hold more than one job and are required to pay CPF contributions for all the wages they receive.However, you can apply to limit the MediSave payable on your self-employed income if your total employment income (excluding Additional Wages*) for the year exceeds the maximum total annual income. You may refer to thisFAQfor more information on the conditions for this application.*Additional Wages are wage supplements which are not granted wholly and exclusively for the month. Examples are the annual bonus, leave pay, incentive and other payments made at intervals of more than a month.To limit your MediSave contributions, you maywrite to us.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-still-have-to-contribute-to-medisave-as-a-self-employed-person-even-though-my-medisave-balance-has-reached-the-basic-healthcare-sum-bhs",
        "question": "Do I still have to contribute to MediSave as a self-employed person even though my MediSave balance has reached the Basic Healthcare Sum (BHS)?",
        "answer": "As a self-employed person (SEP), you are still required to make MediSave contributions even if you have met the Basic Healthcare Sum (BHS). This is the same for employees.The MediSave amount above the BHS will be transferred to your CPF Special Account (SA) or Retirement Account (RA), which have interest rates equal or higher than that of the MediSave Account. The BHS cap and overflow arrangement are intentionally planned to avoid over savings in MediSave and to supplement your retirement savings. These overflows which end up in your SA or RA can be withdrawn according to the withdrawal guidelines. For members who have met the Full Retirement Sum in their SA or RA, the savings in excess of the BHS will be transferred to the Ordinary Account (OA). Savings in the OA can be used for other purposes such as housing repayment.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-do-i-still-need-to-contribute-to-medisave-even-though-i-already-have-enough-savings-for-my-healthcare-needs",
        "question": "Why do I still need to contribute to MediSave even though I already have enough savings for my healthcare needs?",
        "answer": "With rising healthcare costs, it is important to have enough savings for your healthcare needs. Contributing regularly to MediSave will help you build up your savings over your working life. These savings can help you meet your own as well as your loved ones’ hospitalisation expenses under unforeseen circumstances.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-do-i-still-need-to-contribute-to-medisave-as-a-self-employed-person-even-though-i-have-already-bought-insurance-for-myself",
        "question": "Why do I still need to contribute to MediSave as a self-employed person even though I have already bought insurance for myself?",
        "answer": "All working Singapore residents are required to contribute to their MediSave as a form of savings for their own and their loved ones’ healthcare needs.Many Singaporeans have bought private hospital insurance plans in the form of Integrated Shield Plans, or IPs. IPs comprise of two parts – MediShield Life (MSL) which is a universal basic health insurance plan, and additional private insurance coverage. MediSave can be used to pay the premiums for both MSL and private insurance, up to the current withdrawal limit.Hence, private medical insurance serves to complement rather than replace your MediSave savings.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-substantial-balances-in-my-ordinary-and-special-accounts-can-i-use-the-available-funds-to-offset-my-medisave-payable",
        "question": "I have substantial balances in my Ordinary and Special Accounts. Can I use the available funds to offset my MediSave payable?",
        "answer": "The three CPF accounts, Ordinary, Special and MediSave Accounts, serve different purposes. While Ordinary and Special Account savings are meant for retirement, your MediSave Account savings are for your healthcare needs. Thus, the balances in your Ordinary and Special accounts cannot be used to settle your MediSave payable.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-conditions-for-applying-to-limit-my-medisave-payable-as-a-self-employed-person",
        "question": "What are the conditions for applying to limit my MediSave payable as a self-employed person?",
        "answer": "You can apply to limit your MediSave payable if your total employment income (excluding Additional Wages) for the year exceeds the maximum total annual income.Additional Wages are wage supplements which are not granted wholly and exclusively for the month. Examples are the annual bonus, leave pay, incentive and other payments made at intervals of more than a month.Please refer to the table below for the total employment income (excluding Additional Wages) that qualifies you to limit your MediSave contributions as a self-employed person.YearMaximum Total Annual Income(excluding Additional Wages)1993 - 2003$72,0002004$66,0002005$60,0002006 - 2010$54,0002011$56,0002012 - 2015$60,0002016 - 2022$72,0002023$73,2002024$81,6002025$88,8002026 onwards$96,000",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-a-partnership-firm-do-all-partners-need-to-make-medisave-contributions-before-renewing-the-business-licence",
        "question": "I have a partnership firm. Do all partners need to make MediSave contributions before renewing the business licence?",
        "answer": "All partners (if they derive trade income) must fulfil their MediSave payable before the business licence can be renewed.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-have-to-pay-my-medisave-payable-when-i-am-no-longer-self-employed",
        "question": "Do I have to pay my MediSave payable when I am no longer self-employed?",
        "answer": "You’re still required to settle any outstanding MediSave payable, as it is compulsory under the CPF Act to contribute to your MediSave Account for the years that you were self-employed.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-holding-two-types-of-licences-e-g-lta-and-acra-do-i-have-to-contribute-to-medisave-for-both-licences",
        "question": "I am holding two types of licences (e.g. LTA and ACRA). Do I have to contribute to MediSave for both licences?",
        "answer": "The MediSave payable is based on your annual net trade income (NTI) derived as a self-employed person and not the number of licences. If you have a total yearly NTI of more than $6,000 from your licence(s), you are required to make contributions to your MediSave Account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-check-if-i-am-eligible-for-licence-application-or-renewal",
        "question": "How can I check if I am eligible for licence application or renewal?",
        "answer": "It depends on whether you are a self-employed person or a non-self-employed person.For self-employed personsYou can check if you are eligible for licence application or renewal by logging in to theSelf-employment dashboardusing your Singpass. You can apply for yourSingpass onlineif you do not have one.Your licensing agency, real estate company or financial institution may request for a copy of your MediSave payable statement. To retrieve your MediSave payable statement, click the PDF function icon at the top right of the MediSave payable statement after logging into Singpass.Refer to thisguidefor step-by-step instructions on retrieving your MediSave payable statement.For non-self-employed personsYou can check if you are eligible for licence application by logging in to theSelf-employment dashboardusing your Singpass through ‘Check your status’ under Hassle-Free licence application/ renewal. You can apply for yourSingpass onlineif you do not have one.You will be able to view a message indicating your licence application eligibility. Your licensing agency, real estate company or financial institution may request for a screenshot of the message to facilitate your application.Refer to thisguidefor step-by-step instructions on retrieving information on your eligibility for licence application.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-do-not-have-outstanding-medisave-payable-as-a-self-employed-person-can-i-make-medisave-contributions-to-offset-my-future-payables",
        "question": "I do not have outstanding MediSave payable as a self-employed person. Can I make MediSave contributions to offset my future payables?",
        "answer": "You may make MediSave contributions to offset your future payables, up to the prevailing CPF Annual Limit.The total CPF contributions (voluntary and mandatory CPF contributions) made for the calendar year should not exceed the prevailing CPF Annual Limit. Any contributions made in excess of the CPF Annual Limit will be refunded without interest.The Board must receive the MediSave contributions by the last working day of the year for them to be counted towards the year’s CPF Annual Limit. Backdating of MediSave contributions to previous years is not allowed.You can enjoytax reliefon your MediSave contributions, if eligible, based on your annual net trade income.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-outstanding-medisave-payable-why-am-i-not-allowed-to-make-partial-payment-to-offset-my-medisave-payable-under-the-mmsp-form",
        "question": "I have outstanding MediSave payable. Why am I not allowed to make partial payment to offset my MediSave payable under the Manage your MediSave Payable form (MMSP)?",
        "answer": "This is to encourage and make it easier for self-employed persons to be up-to-date with their MediSave payable. You can conveniently request instalment plan or make full payment for your MediSave payable viaManage your MediSave Payable(MMSP). This allows for hassle-free licence application/renewal while being up-to-date with your MediSave payable.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-medisave-contribution-rates-for-self-employed-persons-seps",
        "question": "What are the MediSave contribution rates for self-employed persons (SEPs)?",
        "answer": "Your MediSave payable is based on your age and net trade income for the year. You can use theSelf-Employed MediSave Contribution Calculatorto calculate the amount of MediSave you need to contribute.View the MediSave rates applicable for2026(PDF, 75KB).View the MediSave rates applicable for2025(PDF, 74KB).View the MediSave rates applicable for2024(PDF, 74KB).View the MediSave rates applicable for2023(PDF, 74KB).View the MediSave rates applicable for the years2016 to 2022(PDF, 0.2MB).View the MediSave rates applicable for2015(PDF, 23KB).View the MediSave rates applicable for2014(PDF, 60KB).View the MediSave rates applicable for2013(PDF, 54KB).View the MediSave rates applicable for2012(PDF, 52KB).View the MediSave rates applicable for2011(PDF, 28KB).View the MediSave rates applicable for2010(PDF, 28KB).View the MediSave rates applicable forthe years 2007 to 2009(PDF, 19KB).View the MediSave rates applicable forthe years 1992 to 2006(PDF, 19KB).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-made-a-top-up-to-my-cpf-accounts-do-i-still-have-to-make-medisave-contributions-to-offset-my-medisave-payable",
        "question": "I have made a top-up to my CPF accounts, do I still have to make MediSave contributions to offset my MediSave payable?",
        "answer": "The contributions allocated to your MediSave Account via your top up to CPF accounts will not be used to offset your MediSave payable.If you want to make MediSave contributions to offset your outstanding (via instalment plan or full payment) or future MediSave payable, you may do so via theManage your MediSave Payableform.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-outstanding-medisave-payable-why-am-i-not-able-to-make-voluntary-top-ups-to-my-or-my-loved-ones-cpf-accounts",
        "question": "I have outstanding MediSave payable. Why am I not able to make voluntary top-ups to my or my loved ones' CPF accounts?",
        "answer": "Self-employed persons making top ups to their MediSave accounts or on another person’s behalf are required to be up-to-date with their MediSave payable (paid in full or on an active GIRO plan).You can conveniently request instalment plan or make full payment for your MediSave payable via theManage your MediSave payable form. You will be able to make voluntary top-ups to your or your loved ones’ CPF Accounts when you are up-to-date with your MediSave payable.Conversely, you will be able to receive voluntary top-ups from your loved ones if they are up-to-date with their MediSave payable (if applicable).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-cut-off-date-for-self-employed-cpf-contributions-to-be-eligible-for-tax-relief",
        "question": "What is the cut-off date for self-employed MediSave contributions to be eligible for tax relief?",
        "answer": "To be eligible for tax relief for the year, theMediSavecontributions made by self-employed persons must be credited to their CPF accounts by the last working day of the year.If you have madeMediSavecontributions during the year, the contribution amounts will be automatically transmitted to the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) for tax relief in the following year.There is no tax relief for yourMediSaveCPF contributions if your assessed net trade income for the year of assessmentis zero or negative.For more details on tax deductions, please visit theIRAS websiteor call the Individual Income Tax / Property Tax Helpline at 1800-356-8300.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-made-a-voluntary-top-up-why-does-the-voluntary-contribution-allocated-to-my-medisave-account-not-offset-my-medisave-payable",
        "question": "I have made a voluntary top-up to my CPF accounts, why does the voluntary contribution allocated to my MediSave account not offset my MediSave payable?",
        "answer": "With effect from 29 May 2024, the member and self-employed person’s “Contribute to my three CPF accounts” forms have been combined and renamed as “Top up CPF accounts”. This is to simplify the process in making voluntary top-ups, regardless of whether you are earning income as a self-employed person. You will continue to enjoy self-employed tax relief on these voluntary top-ups if you meet theeligibility criteria.As these top-ups are voluntary in nature, the voluntary contribution allocated to your MediSave Account will not be used to offset your mandatory MediSave payable, and consequently will not meet the MediSave requirement for Workfare for self-employed persons. The intent is for self-employed persons to prioritise their mandatory MediSave contributions over voluntary contributions, and help self-employed persons to first set aside sufficient savings for their healthcare needs. Self-employed persons who wish to make mandatory contributions towards their MediSave payable, and to qualify for Workfare, should do so via theManage your MediSave payable, instead of making voluntary contributions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-enjoy-tax-relief-as-a-self-employed-person-when-i-contribute-to-my-medisave-account-to-offset-my-outstanding-medisave-payable-or-pre-pay-my-future-medisave-payable",
        "question": "Can I enjoy tax relief as a self-employed person when I contribute to my MediSave Account to offset my outstanding MediSave payable, pre-pay my future MediSave payable or make voluntary top-ups to my CPF accounts?",
        "answer": "Self-employed persons (SEPs) can enjoy tax relief on their MediSave or CPF contributions based on their annual net trade income (NTI). However, there is no tax relief for your MediSave or CPF contributions if your assessed NTI for the year of assessment is zero or negative.You can enjoy tax relief on your MediSave or CPF contributions based on whichever is lower:37% of assessable income; orCPF Annual Limit of $37,740; orActual amount contributed by youPlease note that there will be a personal income tax relief cap of $80,000 which will apply from Year of Assessment 2018. This cap applies to the total amount of all tax reliefs claimed, including any relief on voluntary contributions made on or after 1 January 2017.As accepted MediSave or CPF contributions cannot be refunded, you should evaluate whether you would benefit from tax relief on your voluntary CPF top-ups and make an informed decision. Please visit theInland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS)website for more information.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-make-payment-for-my-medisave-payable",
        "question": "How do I make payment for my MediSave payable?",
        "answer": "If you would like tomake payment for your MediSave payable, you may follow the steps below:Read and accept the Disclaimer, and click “Start”.Login with your Singpass.Select“Make full payment” to pay your outstanding MediSave payable in full; or“Request new instalment plan” if you wish to request an instalment plan for your outstanding MediSave payable.If you have selected “Make full payment”:Read and accept the “Terms and Conditions”, and click “Submit”.Make payment by scanning the PayNow QR with your PayNow participating bank’s app. Please note that the transaction amount is capped at your PayNow limit with your bank.Note: If you do not have outstanding MediSave payable and wish to pre-pay your future MediSave payable incurred as a self-employed person, you may do so by entering the amount you wish to contribute.  The amount that you can pre-pay is subject to the Annual Limit. This option will only be available if you are eligible to pre-pay your future MediSave payables.If you have selected “Request new instalment plan”:Key in your current monthly income,Select plan offered. You may be prompted to indicate your preferred monthly instalment amount and to upload supporting documents showing your income and expenses. When you are done, click “Next”.Read and accept the “Terms and Conditions” and click “Submit”.Note: If you are not on a GIRO arrangement for your MediSave payable, you will be required tosign up for GIROto pay the MediSave contributions via instalments. Your instalment plan will only take effect after we have processed your application, and your GIRO application has been approved by your bank.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-is-the-deadline-to-make-my-medisave-contributions",
        "question": "When is the deadline to make my MediSave contributions?",
        "answer": "(a) For self-employed persons (SEPs) who were issued a Notice of Assessment (NOA)/ Non-tax advice by the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS):Amount of ContributionsPayable ByComputed based on your age and Net Trade Income (NTI) assessed by IRAS. You will be issued with a “Notice of Computation (NOC) of CPF Contributions (MediSave)” from IRAS30 days from the date of issue of the NOC(b) For SEPs who were not issued a Notice of Assessment (NOA)/ Non-tax advice by IRAS:For Relevant Years 2020 onwardsAmount of ContributionsPayable ByComputed based on your age and declared NTI to CPF Board30 days from the date of issue of Notice of Contribution from CPF BoardFor Relevant Years 2019 and earlierAmount of ContributionsPayable ByComputed based on your age and declared NTI to CPF Board31 May of the following year",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-does-cpf-board-take-self-employed-persons-to-court-for-not-contributing-to-their-medisave",
        "question": "Why does CPF Board take self-employed persons to court for not contributing to their MediSave?",
        "answer": "Self-employed persons (SEPs) are required under the CPF Act to contribute to their MediSave. This ensures that SEPs have enough MediSave savings for their healthcare needs, especially during old age when they have stopped working. SEPs without enough MediSave savings and MediShield Life cover may need to tap on other sources of funds such as their family members’ MediSave savings should they be hospitalised.The CPF Board will continue to be flexible towards those with genuine financial difficulties. SEPs can requestinstalment plansto settle the outstanding amounts over a reasonable period. The CPF Board will only take recalcitrant defaulters to court as the last resort.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-approach-taken-by-cpf-board-in-enforcing-medisave-contributions-from-self-employed-persons",
        "question": "What is the approach taken by CPF Board in enforcing MediSave contributions from self-employed persons?",
        "answer": "Each year, self-employed persons (SEPs) are notified by the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) via the Notice of Computation (NOC) to pay their MediSave payable in full or by monthly instalments through GIRO. The CPF Board may enforce payments from SEPs only if they have failed to make payments after repeated reminders.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-if-self-employed-persons-do-not-respond-to-the-notice-of-computation-noc",
        "question": "What if self-employed persons do not respond to the Notice of Computation (NOC)?",
        "answer": "If self-employed persons (SEPs) do not respond to the NOC, the CPF Board may issue them a Letter of Demand and Offer which requires them to pay up their outstanding MediSave contributions, together with the payment of the composition amount offered. If there is still no payment, the Board may issue them a Notice to Attend Court (NTA). A sample is appended.NTA for offences before 31 Dec 2021 (PDF, 0.1MB)NTA for offences on or after 31 Dec 2021 (PDF, 0.1MB)SEPs who are brought to court may face a fine of up to $5,000 or imprisonment of up to 6 months or both for first time offenders, and up to $10,000 or imprisonment of up to 12 months or both for subsequent offences.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-drive-and-save-das-scheme",
        "question": "What is the Drive and Save (DAS) Scheme?",
        "answer": "The Drive and Save (DAS) Scheme is a tripartite co-contribution scheme initiated by the National Taxi Association (NTA) and the taxi industry, and supported by the Ministry of Manpower and CPF Board. DAS aims to enhance the welfare of all taxi principal hirers.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-is-eligible-for-the-drive-and-save-das-scheme",
        "question": "Who is eligible for the Drive and Save (DAS) Scheme?",
        "answer": "Under the Drive and Save (DAS) Scheme, all taxi principal hirers who make regular contributions1to their MediSave Account are eligible to receive co-contributions from participating taxi operators. Only contributions that can be used to offset MediSave payable are eligible for DAS co-contributions.If you have outstanding MediSave payable, you may be eligible for DAS co-contributions from participating taxi operators if you make full payment or be on a monthly GIRO instalment plan of at least $20 for your MediSave payable.If you do not have outstanding MediSave payable, you may be eligible for DAS co-contributions from participating taxi operators if you pre-pay your future MediSave payable by contributing at least $20 to your MediSave Account monthly.1You may make MediSave contributions as a self-employed person viaManage your MediSave payableorGIRO.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-register-for-the-drive-and-save-das-scheme",
        "question": "How do I register for the Drive and Save (DAS) Scheme?",
        "answer": "No registration is required for the Drive and Save (DAS) Scheme.Taxi principal hirers who contribute1at least $20 monthly to their MediSave Account will be eligible to receive2a co-contribution of $20 monthly from participating taxi operators.1You may make MediSave contributions as a self-employed person viaManage your MediSave payableorGIRO.2Eligibility for co-contribution is subject to terms and conditions determined by your taxi operator.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-sources-of-medisave-contributions-are-eligible-for-drive-and-save-das-co-contribution",
        "question": "What sources of MediSave contributions are eligible for Drive and Save (DAS) co-contribution?",
        "answer": "MediSave contributions1made by the taxi principal hirer to offset MediSave payable will qualify him for Drive and Save (DAS) co-contribution. CPF contributions received as an employee (from both employer and self) for taxi principal hirers who are concurrently employed, as well as government top-ups are excluded.1You may make MediSave contributions as a self-employed person viaManage your MediSave payableorGIRO.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-i-receive-drive-and-save-das-co-contributions-if-i-make-a-lump-sum-payment",
        "question": "Will I receive Drive and Save (DAS) co-contributions if I make a lump sum payment?",
        "answer": "You will receive Drive and Save (DAS) co-contributions of $20 monthly if you have contributed1at least $240 into your MediSave Account in the past 12 months.1You may make MediSave contributions as a self-employed person viaManage your MediSave payableorGIRO.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-taxi-principal-hirers-who-are-not-liable-to-make-a-medisave-contribution-qualify-for-das-co-con-from-their-taxi-operators",
        "question": "Can taxi principal hirers who are not liable to make a MediSave contribution qualify for Drive and Save (DAS) co-contribution from their taxi operators?",
        "answer": "Taxi principal hirers who do not have outstanding MediSave payable can still receive Drive and Save co-contributions if they make contributions to pre-pay their future MediSave payable1:A contribution of at least $20 to their MediSave Account monthly, orA lump sum MediSave contribution of at least $240 in the past 12 months.1Taxi principal hirers may make MediSave contributions to pre-pay their MediSave payable as self-employed persons viaManage your MediSave payable.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-does-each-taxi-operator-know-the-drive-and-save-das-co-contribution-amount",
        "question": "How does each taxi operator know the Drive and Save (DAS) co-contribution amount?",
        "answer": "CPF Board will inform participating taxi operators of taxi principal hirers who qualify1for Drive and Save (DAS) co-contributions monthly. The amount of contribution made by hirers will not be revealed.Please note that eligibility for co-contribution is subject to terms and conditions determined by taxi operators.1Taxi principal hirers may make MediSave contributions as self-employed persons viaManage your MediSave payableorGIRO.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-participate-in-the-drive-and-save-das-scheme-will-my-taxi-vocational-licence-tdvl-be-automatically-renewed",
        "question": "If I participate in the Drive and Save (DAS) Scheme, will my Taxi Driver Vocational Licence (TDVL) be automatically renewed?",
        "answer": "No, Taxi Driver Vocational Licences (TDVL) will not be automatically renewed upon participation in the Drive and Save (DAS) Scheme.Taxi principal hirers must have fully paid their MediSave payable or are making monthly payments via GIRO to renew their TDVLs.MediSave contributions1and co-contributions from taxi operators will offset mandatory MediSave contributions under the Self-Employed Scheme.1Taxi principal hirers may make MediSave contributions as self-employed persons viaManage your MediSave payableorGIRO.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-does-regular-medisave-co-contributions-received-under-the-drive-and-save-das-benefit-me",
        "question": "How does regular MediSave co-contributions received under the Drive and Save (DAS) Scheme benefit me?",
        "answer": "Under the Drive and Save (DAS) Scheme, the regular MediSave co-contributions from your taxi operator can:Offset your mandatory MediSave contributions under the Self-Employed SchemeEarn up to 6%1interest per annum (p.a.) on your MediSave savings.This includes an additional 1% interest p.a. on the first $60,000 of your combined balances (with up to $20,000 from the Ordinary Account).CPF members aged 55 and above will also earn an additional 1% interest p.a. on the first $30,000 of their combined CPF balances.Pay MediShield Life/Integrated Shield Plan premiums for you and your loved ones (spouse, children, parents, grandparents, or siblings)Qualify2to receive Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) payouts in cash and in your MediSave Account1Based on the current 4% interest rate floor for MediSave savings. Refer tocpf.gov.sg/interestratesfor the current rates.2Terms and conditions apply. Refer tocpf.gov.sg/wisfor more information.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-settle-my-outstanding-medisave-payable-by-instalments-through-giro",
        "question": "Can I settle my outstanding MediSave payable by instalments through GIRO?",
        "answer": "You can settle your outstanding MediSave payable by instalments through GIRO.If your bank account is withthe participating banks, please complete theSet up GIRO for MediSave contributionsusing your Singpass. You will be re-directed to the bank’s ibanking portal to complete the application. You can check the status of your online application throughmy cpfdigital services - Activitieswith your Singpass.If you wish to use an account from other banks, please download and submit the“Apply for GIRO for MediSave Contributions” (FORM SE GIRO)(PDF, 0.2MB) to the CPF Board. Deduction will be made from the existing bank account until the new GIRO arrangement takes effect.After your GIRO application is approved, we will inform you about your monthly instalment amounts via a notification. You can also view your GIRO instalment plan details via theSelf-employment dashboardafter logging in with your Singpass.If you are facing financial difficulties and need to defer your MediSave contributions, please contact us via ourOnline Enquiry Form.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-terminate-my-giro-arrangement-as-a-self-employed-person",
        "question": "How do I terminate my GIRO arrangement as a self-employed person?",
        "answer": "You may submit an online applicationTerminate GIRO for MediSave contributionsusing your Singpass if you wish to terminate your GIRO arrangement as a self-employed person.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-request-an-instalment-plan-for-my-medisave-contributions",
        "question": "How do I request an instalment plan for my MediSave contributions?",
        "answer": "You can request for an instalment plan for your MediSave contributions via theManage your MediSave payableform.Please note that your request is subject to the Board’s approval. You may be required to provide additional information or supporting documents, if necessary.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-status-of-my-request-to-make-self-employed-medisave-contributions-via-monthly-instalments",
        "question": "What is the status of my request to make self-employed MediSave contributions via monthly instalments?",
        "answer": "We will keep you informed about the status of your request to make self-employed MediSave contributions via monthly instalments, once it has been processed.Please note our normal processing time:·         Requests made via online appeal: generally 12 working days·         Manual transactions: generally 15 working daysYou can check the status of your request by clicking on thislink.You can view your approved GIRO instalment plan details on theSelf-employment dashboard. To accessmy cpfDigital Services – Self-employment dashboard, please log in to theCPF websiteusing your Singpass.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-was-my-medisave-instalment-amount-changed",
        "question": "Why was my MediSave instalment amount changed?",
        "answer": "The instalment amount for self-employed contributions will change if the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) has assessed/reassessed your net trade income.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-long-does-it-take-to-process-applications-relating-to-giro-matters",
        "question": "How long does it take to process applications relating to GIRO matters?",
        "answer": "Online applications to set up/terminate GIRO for MediSave contributions submitted by the 15thof the month will take effect in the same month. Otherwise, the GIRO arrangement will take effect from the following month.For example, if you submit an online application on 15 June to set up a GIRO arrangement, your first GIRO deduction will take place on *25 June. If you submit the online application on 16 June, your first GIRO deduction will take place on *25 July.Hardcopy applications to set up GIRO arrangement will require up to 21 working days to process. If processed by the 15thof the month, the first GIRO deduction will take place in the same month. Otherwise, the first GIRO deduction will take place from the following month.If you had requested to terminate your GIRO arrangement via your bank, please inform us so that we can update your GIRO details accordingly.*If the 25this a Saturday, Sunday, or Public Holiday, the amount will be deducted on the next working day.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-change-my-bank-account-for-giro-instalments-for-my-medisave-contributions",
        "question": "How do I change my bank account for GIRO instalments for my MediSave contributions?",
        "answer": "If your bank account is withthe participating banks, please complete theSet up GIRO for MediSave contributionsusing your Singpass. You will be re-directed to the bank's ibanking portal to complete the application. You can check the status of your online application throughmy cpfdigital services - Activitieswith your Singpass.If you would like to use an account from other banks, please download and submit theApply for GIRO for MediSave Contributions(FORM SE GIRO) (PDF, 0.2MB) to the Board. Deduction will be made from the existing bank account until the new GIRO arrangement takes effect.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-contribute-as-you-earn-caye",
        "question": "What is Contribute As You Earn (CAYE)?",
        "answer": "Under the Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) scheme, a MediSave contribution is required as and when a self-employed person (SEP) earns a service fee. Every time a service fee is paid to the SEP, the corporate service buyers (CSBs) or intermediaries making the payment will first deduct and credit a portion of the service fee to the SEP’s MediSave Account, before paying the remainder of the service fee to the SEP.CAYE does not change the amount of MediSave contributions SEPs have to make based on their net trade income.SEPs who provide services to government agencies are automatically enrolled into CAYE.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/as-a-self-employed-person-how-will-i-benefit-from-participating-in-contribute-as-you-earn-caye",
        "question": "As a self-employed person, how will I benefit from participating in Contribute As You Earn (CAYE)?",
        "answer": "Through making smaller and more regular MediSave contributions as and when you receive a service fee, Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) makes saving for your healthcare needs through your MediSave Account (MA) easier. MediSave savings can be used to pay for your out-of-pocket healthcare expenses and MediShield Life premiums.As a self-employed person (SEP), there are many issues that require your attention. CAYE is an easy and hassle-free way to help free up more of your time. For your convenience, your CAYE contributions are automatically deposited into your MA whenever you get paid. This would also be helpful for SEPs whose income may be seasonal. CAYE can also help grow your money as you can start to earn an interest of up to 5% on your MediSave savings earlier.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-participating-in-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-affect-my-medisave-contributions-payable",
        "question": "How will participating in Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) affect my MediSave contributions payable?",
        "answer": "Self-employed persons (SEPs) are required to contribute to their MediSave Account (MA) if their annual Net Trade Income (NTI) is more than $6,000. Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) does not change the amount of MediSave contributions you have to make based on your NTI. The only change concerns how the contributions are made. Under CAYE, the agency/company you provided a service to will help you contribute into your MA each time it makes a service payment to you.Your CAYE contributions are based on your estimated annual revenue and expenses. Thus, CAYE contributions are an estimate of your MediSave payable. After you declare your NTI for the year, your MediSave payable will be computed.If your total Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions are higher than your MediSave payable for the latest year, your excess CAYE contributions will be used to offset your outstanding MediSave payable from previous years1. Any remaining CAYE contributions will then be refunded to you.If your total CAYE contributions are lower than your MediSave payable, you’ll be required to top up the remaining amount. You’ll be notified accordingly, and you can choose to make payment via lump-sum payment(s) or sign up for GIRO instalments.1This will take effect for CAYE contributions made from 2023. Pleasewrite to usif you do not wish to use your CAYE contributions to offset your outstanding MediSave payable from previous years.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/as-a-self-employed-person-how-will-the-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-scheme-affect-me",
        "question": "As a self-employed person, how will the Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) scheme affect me?",
        "answer": "Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) helps you save for your healthcare needs through smaller and more regular MediSave contributions each time you receive a payment. There is no change to your MediSave contributions payable as it would still be based on your actual Net Trade Income.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-if-i-am-in-financial-hardship-and-is-unable-to-set-aside-monies-for-medisave-via-the-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-scheme",
        "question": "What if I am in financial hardship and is unable to set aside monies for MediSave via the Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) scheme?",
        "answer": "We understand that some self-employed persons (SEPs) may be facing financial difficulties and may not be able to cope with Contribute As You Earn (CAYE). Thus, if you do not have outstanding MediSave payable or are contributing via GIRO instalments, you may set your CAYE contribution rate to 0%. This means that you’ll receive your service payment in full, and CAYE contribution will not be deducted from your service payment. Pleasewrite to usif you wish to apply for a 0% CAYE contribution rate. CPF Board will assess your eligibility and inform you of the outcome in writing.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-must-participate-in-contribute-as-you-earn-caye",
        "question": "Who must participate in Contribute As You Earn (CAYE)?",
        "answer": "SEPs who are individual freelancers or sole proprietors and were awarded jobs with Government agencies will automatically be enrolled into CAYE.Private companies are also encouraged to voluntarily onboard CAYE to help the SEPs who they have contracted with, save for their healthcare and retirement needs in an easier manner.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/as-a-self-employed-person-who-provides-services-to-government-agencies-how-will-i-be-enrolled-into-contribute-as-you-earn-caye",
        "question": "As a self-employed person who provides services to Government agencies, how will I be enrolled into Contribute As You Earn (CAYE)?",
        "answer": "You’ll be automatically enrolled into Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) when you receive a service payment from a Government agency you have provided services to as a self-employed person (SEP). You’ll receive a notification from CPF Board when you receive your first payment via CAYE. Subsequently, you’ll also receive a notification each time you receive a payment via CAYE.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-already-contributed-up-to-the-basic-healthcare-sum-bhs-why-am-i-still-required-to-participate-in-contribute-as-you-earn-caye",
        "question": "I have already contributed up to the Basic Healthcare Sum (BHS). Why am I still required to participate in Contribute As You Earn (CAYE)?",
        "answer": "As a self-employed person, you’re still required to make MediSave contributions even if you have met the Basic Healthcare Sum (BHS). This is the same for employees.The MediSave amount above the BHS will be transferred to your CPF Special Account (SA)* or Retirement Account (RA). The BHS cap and overflow arrangement are intentionally planned to avoid over savings in MediSave and to supplement your retirement savings. These overflows which end up in your SA or RA can be withdrawn according to thewithdrawal guidelines. If you’ve met the Full Retirement Sum in your SA or RA, the savings in excess of the BHS will be transferred to your Ordinary Account (OA). Savings in the OA can be used for other purposes such as housing repayment.*The SA will be closed for members aged 55 and above from early 2025. Read morehere.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-contributed-up-to-the-maximum-mandatory-contributions-for-the-year-do-i-still-have-to-make-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-contributions",
        "question": "I have contributed up to the maximum mandatory contributions for the year. Do I still have to make Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions?",
        "answer": "If you’ve made Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions up to the maximum MediSave payable for the year, your applicable CAYE contribution rate will be 0%. This means that you will receive your service fee in full, and CAYE contribution will no longer be deducted from your service fee.However, you’ll still be required to make good your outstanding MediSave payable (if any) via lump-sum payment(s) or GIRO instalment plan.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-self-employed-persons-who-provide-services-to-the-private-sector-be-mandated-to-participate-in-contribute-as-you-earn-caye",
        "question": "Will self-employed persons who provide services to the private sector be mandated to participate in Contribute As You Earn (CAYE)?",
        "answer": "The Government, as a service buyer, has piloted Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) since 1 January 2020. There are currently no plans to extend CAYE into the private sector. Nonetheless, companies in the private sector are encouraged to voluntarily adopt CAYE.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-if-i-prefer-making-medisave-contributions-through-the-current-payment-modes-e-g-giro",
        "question": "What if I prefer making MediSave contributions through the current payment modes (e.g. GIRO)?",
        "answer": "The small and regular MediSave contributions made through Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) help self-employed persons (SEPs) to reduce the MediSave contributions payable in the following year (after SEPs declare their Net Trade Income and have their MediSave payable computed).If you’ve made your MediSave contributions in full or are on GIRO instalment plan, you’ll be allowed to set your CAYE contribution rate to 0% and receive your service fee in full.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-if-i-do-not-wish-to-participate-in-contribute-as-you-earn-caye",
        "question": "What if I do not wish to participate in Contribute As You Earn (CAYE)?",
        "answer": "Self-employed persons (SEPs) who have completed a job with Government agencies will be automatically enrolled into CAYE. CAYE will not apply to SEPs who completed jobs with the private sector.The CAYE scheme helps SEPs save for their healthcare needs through smaller and more regular MediSave contributions each time they receive a service payment. This helps to reduce the MediSave payable in the following year (after SEPs declare their Net Trade Income and have their MediSave payable computed). CAYE will help with the upkeep of current MediSave obligations and prevent snowballing of the payable.You can choose to set your CAYE contribution rate to 0% if you’ve made your MediSave contributions in full or are on GIRO instalment plan.If you’re in financial hardship and unable to set aside monies for your CAYE contributions, you maywrite to us. We will assess your request and inform you of the outcome in writing.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/under-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-how-much-medisave-contribution-would-i-have-to-make-from-my-service-fee",
        "question": "Under Contribute As You Earn (CAYE), how much MediSave contribution would I have to make from my service fee?",
        "answer": "Under Contribute As You Earn (CAYE), the amount of MediSave contribution deducted from your service fee is based on your estimated annual revenue and expenses for the year.Your CAYE contribution rate is determined by the following formula:CAYE contribution rate =(A x B) / CwhereAis the MediSave contribution rate for your estimated annual Net Trade Income (NTI)1and age for the year;Bis your estimated annual NTI1for the year2; andCis your estimated annual revenue for the year21Your estimated annual NTI is derived using your estimated annual revenue less estimated annual expenses for the year.2If you did not provide your estimated annual revenue and expenses for the year, it will be based on your actual revenue and expenses assessed by IRAS two years ago.A floor CAYE contribution rate of 2% will apply if you have earned more than $6,000 two years ago.To ensure that your CAYE contribution rate reflects your business outlook for the year accurately, please estimate your revenue and expenses by logging in to theSelf-employment dashboardusing your Singpass, underContribute As You Earn > Update contribution rate. You can adjust your CAYE contribution rate as and when there are changes to your estimated revenue and expenses. Generally, your updated rate will apply to payments made from the next day.Otherwise, a personalised default CAYE contribution rate computed based on your NTI assessed by the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) two years ago will apply.Example on how the CAYE contribution rate will be computed",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-estimate-my-annual-revenue-and-expenses-for-the-year",
        "question": "How do I estimate my annual revenue and expenses for the year?",
        "answer": "You can estimate your annual revenue and expenses for the current year based on the actual revenue and expenses you earned last year. You can adjust your estimated annual revenue and expenses whenever you foresee any changes in revenue (e.g. increase in number of jobs in the current year) or expenses (e.g. increase in business cost, including the cost to engage other to assist in your jobs).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-adjust-my-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-contribution-rate",
        "question": "How do I adjust my Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contribution rate?",
        "answer": "If there are changes to your estimated revenue or expenses for the year, you may update and re-compute your Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contribution rate by logging in to theSelf-employment dashboardusing your Singpass, underContribute As You Earn > Update contribution rate. Generally, your updated CAYE contribution rate will apply to payments made from the next day.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-should-i-adjust-my-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-contribution-rate",
        "question": "When should I adjust my Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contribution rate?",
        "answer": "You can adjust your Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contribution rate by updating your estimated revenue or expense whenever you foresee any changes in revenue (e.g. increase in number of jobs in the current year) or expenses (e.g. increase in business cost, including the cost to engage other to assist in your jobs).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-adjusted-my-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-contribution-rate-when-will-the-updated-rate-take-effect",
        "question": "I have adjusted my Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contribution rate. When will the updated rate take effect?",
        "answer": "Generally, your updated Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contribution rate will apply to service fees paid from the next day.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-different-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-contribution-rates-applied-to-different-service-fees",
        "question": "Why are different Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contribution rates applied to different service fees?",
        "answer": "Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contribution rates may change when you (i) update your CAYE contribution rate or (ii) are no longer required to make CAYE contributions. Generally, the updated CAYE contribution rate will apply to service fees paid from the next day.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-the-estimated-income-that-i-have-provided-for-the-computation-of-my-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-contribution-rate-be-used-as-the-income-to-compute-my-medisave-payable-for-the-year",
        "question": "Will the estimated income that I have provided for the computation of my Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contribution rate be used as the income to compute my MediSave payable for the year?",
        "answer": "The income information you provided for Contribute As You Earn  (CAYE) is only used to compute the CAYE contribution rate. It will not be used as your actual income to compute your MediSave payable for the year.You’ll still need to declare your Net Trade Income (NTI) to the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) or CPF Board the following year. Your MediSave payable for the year will then be computed based on that NTI.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-do-i-contact-for-further-details-on-my-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-contributions-and-net-service-fee-payment-amount",
        "question": "Who do I contact for further details on my Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions and net service fee payment amount?",
        "answer": "To view your Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions and other payment details, you may log in to theSelf-employment dashboardusing your Singpass, underContribute As You Earn > Show all payments. You can alsocontact us through these channels.For more details on the net service fee, please contact the company or agency you have contracted with directly. If there are any non-payment, short payment or late payment of service fees, you may wish to take up the dispute directly with your buyer and seek mediation through theTripartite Alliance for Dispute Management (TADM)or other industry facilitated mediation services.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-does-the-company-i-contracted-with-know-my-net-trade-income-information-and-or-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-contribution-rate",
        "question": "How does the company I contracted with know my Net Trade Income information and/or Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contribution rate?",
        "answer": "The company which you have contracted with will not have access to your Net Trade Income information. CPF Board will only inform the company of the amount that they would have to deduct from your service fee and transmit to your MediSave Account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-do-if-the-company-i-contracted-with-did-not-pay-my-service-fees",
        "question": "What should I do if the company I contracted with did not pay my service fees?",
        "answer": "For any disputes on non-payment, short payment or late payment of service fees, you may wish to take up the dispute directly with the company or agency you have contracted with and seek mediation through theTripartite Alliance for Dispute Management (TADM)or other industry facilitated mediation services.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-know-if-the-caye-contribution-amount-and-net-service-fee-payment-amount-are-made-correctly",
        "question": "How do I know if the Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contribution amount and net service fee payment amount are made correctly?",
        "answer": "You can check your payment records by logging in to theSelf-employment dashboardusing your Singpass, underContribute As You Earn > Show all payments.If you’ve previously informed CPF Board of your contact details, you’ll also receive a notification whenever a contribution to your MediSave Account has been made via Contribute As You Earn (CAYE). If you wish to update your contact details, you can do so via logging on tomy cpfdigital servicesusing your Singpass.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-if-the-medisave-contributions-i-made-via-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-are-higher-than-my-medisave-payable-for-the-year",
        "question": "What happens if the MediSave contributions I made via Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) are higher than my MediSave payable for the year?",
        "answer": "If you have outstanding MediSave payable from previous years, your excess CAYE contributions will be used to offset those payables1. Any excess thereafter will be refunded to you. You can also choose to retain the excess CAYE contributions in your MediSave Account (MA).Example:Based on his estimated income of $22,000 for 2023, Sam contributed $2,200 via CAYE. In the following year, he declared that he earned a lower Net Trade Income of $19,000 for 2023. As such, Sam’s MediSave payable for his work done in 2023 is $1,900. Hence, he has excess CAYE contributions of $300 for the year. Sam also has an outstanding MediSave payable of $100 incurred in 2022 which would be offset by the excess CAYE contributions, leaving a final excess amount of $200. This amount will be refunded to him2. He can also choose to keep this $200 in his MA.This example is illustrated within the table below:Estimated 2023 NTI$22,000CAYE contributions in 2023$2,200(After 2023 NTI declaration)Declared 2023 NTI$19,000MediSave payable for work done in 2023$1,900Outstanding MediSave payable for 2022$100Amount Sam will receive as a refund$200(i.e. $2,200 - $1,900 - $100)1This will take effect for CAYE contributions made from 2023. Pleasewrite to usif you do not wish to use your CAYE contributions to offset your outstanding MediSave payable from previous years.2Sam may also choose not to use his CAYE contributions to offset his outstanding MediSave payable of $100 incurred in 2022. In this case, he will be refunded $300 instead.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-if-the-medisave-contributions-i-made-via-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-are-lower-than-my-medisave-payable-for-the-year",
        "question": "What happens if the MediSave contributions I made via Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) are lower than my MediSave payable for the year?",
        "answer": "If your total CAYE contributions are lower than your MediSave payable for the latest year, you will be required to top up the remaining amount. You’ll be notified accordingly, and you can choose to make payment via a lump-sum payment(s) or sign up for monthly GIRO instalments.Example:Based on his estimated income of $21,000 for 2023, Sam contributed $2,100 via CAYE. In the following year, he declared that he earned a higher NTI of $30,000 for 2023. As such, Sam’s MediSave payable for his work done in 2023 is $3,000. Sam will have to top up the shortfall of $900.This example is illustrated within the table below:Estimated 2023 NTI$21,000CAYE contributions in 2023$2,100(After 2023 NTI declaration)Declared 2023 NTI$30,000MediSave payable for work done in 2023$3,000Shortfall Sam has to top up$900(i.e. $3,000 - $2,100)",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-i-get-into-trouble-if-my-actual-income-declared-to-the-inland-revenue-authority-of-singapore-iras-cpf-board-in-the-following-year-is-different-from-the-income-estimated-on-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-digital-services",
        "question": "Will I get into trouble if my actual income declared to the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS)/ CPF Board in the following year is different from the income estimated on Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) digital services?",
        "answer": "No, as the revenue and expenses information on Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) digital services is an estimate of your business outlook for the year. You are still required to declare your actual Net Trade Income to the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS)/ CPF Board to compute your MediSave payable for the year.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-do-i-still-have-outstanding-medisave-payable-when-i-am-already-on-contribute-as-you-earn-caye",
        "question": "Why do I still have outstanding MediSave payable when I am already on Contribute As You Earn (CAYE)?",
        "answer": "Your Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions is an estimate of your MediSave payable for the year and may be lower or higher than your MediSave payable for the year. If your CAYE contributions are lower than your MediSave payable for the year, you’ll be required to top up the shortfall. You’ll also be required to make MediSave contributions for any outstanding MediSave payable incurred in previous years.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-choose-to-retain-my-excess-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-contributions-in-my-medisave-account",
        "question": "Can I choose to retain my excess Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions in my MediSave Account?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can choose to retain your excess Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions in your MediSave Account. You may apply to do so by logging in to theSelf-employment dashboardusing your Singpass.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-use-my-excess-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-contributions-to-offset-my-outstanding-medisave-payable",
        "question": "Can I use my excess Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions to offset my outstanding MediSave payable?",
        "answer": "CAYE contributions in excess of your MediSave payable for the year will be automatically used to offset your outstanding MediSave payable from previous years, if any1. Any excess thereafter will be refunded to your bank account.You can also choose to boost your healthcare savings by retaining the excess CAYE contributions in your MediSave Account to earn up to 5% interest per annum, and to offset future MediSave payable. To do so, please apply via theSelf-employment dashboardusing your Singpass.1This will take effect for CAYE contributions made from 2023. Pleasewrite to usif you do not wish to use your CAYE contributions to offset your outstanding MediSave payable from previous years.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-do-i-still-need-to-declare-my-income-to-the-inland-revenue-authority-of-singapore-iras-cpf-board-when-i-have-already-done-so-on-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-digital-services",
        "question": "Why do I still need to declare my income to the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS)/ CPF Board when I have already done so on Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) digital services?",
        "answer": "The revenue and expenses information on the Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) digital services is an estimate of your business outlook for the year and used only to compute your CAYE contribution rate. It is not a declaration of your actual Net Trade Income (NTI) and you are still required to declare your actual NTI in the following year to the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) / CPF Board to compute your mandatory MediSave payable.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-renew-my-licence-if-i-have-been-making-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-contributions",
        "question": "Can I renew my licence if I have been making Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions?",
        "answer": "You can renew your licence so long as you have no outstanding MediSave payable or are on a monthly GIRO instalment plan.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-do-i-need-to-make-other-payment-arrangements-in-order-to-renew-my-licence-when-i-am-already-on-contribute-as-you-earn-caye",
        "question": "Why do I need to make other payment arrangements in order to renew my licence when I am already on Contribute As You Earn (CAYE)?",
        "answer": "Your Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions are only based on an estimate of your MediSave payable for the current year. To renew your licence, you will need to pay your MediSave payable incurred in previous years via lump-sum payment(s) or monthly GIRO instalments.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/where-can-i-find-guides-on-how-to-make-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-transactions",
        "question": "Where can I find guides on how to make Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) transactions?",
        "answer": "If you need assistance on how to make Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) transactions, you can refer to theCAYE step-by-step guide, or you canwrite to us.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/does-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-contributions-qualify-for-tax-relief",
        "question": "Does Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions qualify for tax relief?",
        "answer": "Similar to other forms of self-employed CPF contributions, Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions will qualify for tax relief based on the date of payment. CAYE contributions made in a calendar year will qualify for tax relief in the following year. For example, relief on CAYE contributions made between 1 January 2024 and 31 December 2024 will qualify for tax relief in the Year of Assessment (YA) 2025 subject to the assessable net trade income (NTI) for this YA.The CPF relief allowable to self-employed persons (SEPs) for his MediSave and voluntary CPF contributions, including CAYE contributions, will be capped at 37% of his NTI assessed or CPF relief cap of $37,740 or the actual amount contributed by SEP whichever is the lowest. There is no tax relief for your mandatory or voluntary CPF contributions if your assessed NTI for the year of assessment is zero or negative.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-the-contribute-as-you-earn-caye-scheme-affect-my-income-declaration-to-iras-for-tax-purposes",
        "question": "How will the Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) scheme affect my income declaration to IRAS for tax purposes?",
        "answer": "There will be no change to Self-Employed Person (SEP)’s declaration of income for tax purposes. SEPs should continue to declare his annual income earned up to 31stDecember of the preceding year in the Income Tax Return for the current Year of Assessment (YA). For example, the SEP needs to declare his gross income for services provided between 1 January 2024 and 31 December 2024 in Income Tax Return for YA2025, even if it is invoiced only in January 2025. This is regardless of when the Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions for the said services are made.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-cant-i-find-the-bank-account-input-details-on-vendors-gov",
        "question": "Why can't I find the bank account input details on Vendors@Gov?",
        "answer": "From early June 2024, you will only be able to select PayNow (excluding PayNow Mobile Number and Virtual Payments Address) as the mode of payment.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-choose-to-continue-to-submit-my-bank-account-details-to-receive-payments-for-government-service-instead-of-paynow",
        "question": "Can I choose to continue to submit my bank account details to receive payments for government service instead of PayNow (excluding PayNow Mobile Number and Virtual Payments Address), and what do I need to do to ensure I can continue to receive my service fee payments?",
        "answer": "You will only be able to use the bank account registered to your PayNow to receive service fee payments.Please ensure that you have registered for PayNow (excluding PayNow Mobile Number and Virtual Payments Address) so that you receive your service fee payments promptly. If not, you will not be able to receive your service fee payments from early June 2024.We encourage you to check with your bank to ensure your details are updated or if you need more information on how to sign up for PayNow (excluding PayNow Mobile Number and Virtual Payments Address).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-paynow-excluding-paynow-mobile-number-and-virtual-payments-address-the-default-mode-of-bank-payments-moving-forward",
        "question": "Why is PayNow (excluding PayNow Mobile Number and Virtual Payments Address) the default mode of bank payments moving forward?",
        "answer": "PayNow (excluding PayNow Mobile Number and Virtual Payments Address) aligns with the government's drive for digital transformation and the Smart Nation initiative, as it promotes the adoption of digital payment. It also provides citizens a more secured mode of payment as they do not need to provide their bank account details to receive their service fee payments.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-will-i-need-to-be-registered-for-paynow-to-continue-receiving-my-net-service-fee-payments-without-delay",
        "question": "When will I need to be registered for PayNow to continue receiving my net service fee payments without delay?",
        "answer": "PayNow (excluding PayNow Mobile Number and Virtual Payments Address) will be the default payment mode from early June 2024. Please ensure that you are registered for PayNow (excluding PayNow Mobile Number and Virtual Payments Address) so that you receive your service fee payments promptly.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-cpf-interest-rates",
        "question": "What are the CPF interest rates?",
        "answer": "CPF Interest Rates (1 January 2025 to 31 March 2025)Ordinary AccountSpecial, MediSave and Retirement AccountInterest Rate2.5%4%To help boost retirement savings, the Government pays extra interest on the first $60,000 of your combined CPF balances, which is capped at $20,000 for Ordinary Account (OA). Please refer to details on extra interest in the table below.AgeExtra interestBelow 55 years old1% per annum on the first $60,000 (capped at $20,000 for OA)55 years old and above2% per annum on the first $30,000, 1% per annum on the next $30,000(capped at $20,000 for OA)Extra interest earned on OA savings go into your Special Account (SA) or Retirement Account (RA) to enhance your retirement savings. If you are participating in the CPF LIFE scheme, you will still earn the extra interest on your combined CPF balances, including the savings used for CPF LIFE.Please refer to the respective links for more information on theCPF interest ratesandhistorical CPF interest rates(PDF, 0.15MB).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-are-cpf-interest-rates-determined",
        "question": "How are CPF interest rates determined?",
        "answer": "Savings in the Ordinary Account (OA) earn the 3-month average of major local banks’ interest rates, subject to the legislated minimum interest of 2.5% per annum. This is reviewed quarterly.Savings in the Special, MediSave and Retirement Account (SMRA) earn the 12-month average yield of 10-year Singapore Government Securities (10YSGS) plus 1%, subject to the current floor interest rate of 4% per annum. This is reviewed quarterly.Please refer to theCPF interest ratesandMOF websitefor more information.Computation of CPF OA Interest Rate and HDB Mortgage Rate for1 January 2025 to 31 March 2025Average banks' interest rate from August 2024 to October 20240.45% (see note)CPF OA interest rate for January 2025 to March 20252.50% per annum(legislated minimum rate)Plus:Fee to cover Cost of Loan Administration0.10%HDB mortgage rate for January 2025 to March 20252.60% per annumNote:12-month deposit rate(% per annum)Savings Rate(% per annum)Average(% per annum)Month / YearDBS1OCBC2UOB3DBS4OCBC5UOB6Using the 80FD:20SD formula31 Aug 20240.05000.10001.50000.05000.05000.05000.450030 Sep 20240.05000.10001.50000.05000.05000.05000.450031 Oct 20240.05000.10001.50000.05000.05000.05000.45001Balances of $20,000 to < $50,0002Balances > $20,000 to $50,0003Balances < $50,0004Balances > $10,000 to $100,000 (AUTO-SAVE Account)5Entire Account Balance (EASI-SAVE Account)6Balances > $15,000 to $100,000 (UNIPLUS Account)Computation of CPF SMRA Interest Rate for1 January 2025 to 31 March 2025Average yield of 10YSGS from November 2023 to October 20242.99%Plus: 1.00%1.00%Computed CPF SMRA interest rate for January 2025 to March 20253.99%CPF SMRA interest rate floor for January 2025 to March 20254.00%CPF SMRA interest rate for January 2025 to March 20254.00% per annumSource: Yields of 10-Year Singapore Government Securities are obtained frommas.gov.sg/bonds-and-bills",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-extra-interest-can-i-earn-on-my-cpf-savings",
        "question": "How much extra interest can I earn on my CPF savings?",
        "answer": "To help boost retirement savings, the Government pays extra interest on the first $60,000 of your combined CPF balances, which is capped at $20,000 for Ordinary Account (OA). Extra interest is structured so that all CPF members benefit, and members with lower balances benefit more. The amount of extra interest paid to you would depend on your combined CPF balances and age.If you are below 55 years old, you will earn an extra interest of 1% per annum on the first $60,000 of your combined CPF balances (capped at $20,000 for OA). The extra interest earned on your Special Account (SA) and MediSave Account (MA) balances will go to the respective accounts, while the extra interest earned on your OA balances will go into your SA to enhance your retirement savings.If you are 55 years old and above, you will earn an extra interest of 2% per annum on the first $30,000 and 1% per annum on the next $30,000 of your combined CPF balances (capped at $20,000 for OA). The extra interest earned on your Retirement Account (RA), SA and MA balances will go to the respective accounts, while the extra interest earned on your OA balances will go into your RA to enhance your retirement savings. If you have joined the CPF LIFE scheme, the extra interest earned will be paid into your RA or accumulated with the interest earned on the CPF LIFE premiums of all CPF LIFE members.How is my combined CPF balance computed?Your accounts are used to compute your combined CPF balances in the following order:- 1st: Retirement Account (RA), including any CPF LIFE premium balance- 2nd: OA, with a cap of $20,000*- 3rd: Special Account (SA)- 4th: MediSave Account (MA)*A cap of $20,000 from OA is imposed because OA savings are short-term in nature and can be withdrawn on demand for a few purposes such as housing and education.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-is-my-cpf-interest-computed-and-credited-into-my-accounts",
        "question": "How is my CPF interest computed and credited into my accounts?",
        "answer": "CPF interest is computed monthly. It is credited to your respective accounts by the following year and compounded annually.CPF balances used for interest computation are affected by the transactions in your account. For instance, contributions (including refunds) received this month start earning interest next month. Withdrawals/deductions in this month will not earn interest from this month onwards.There are strict procedures in place to ensure the accuracy of members’ CPF accounts and transactions (including interest payments). To further ensure that our system is sound and robust, our statutory auditor performs regular reviews of formulas and computations in our systems for accuracy, and conducts independent verifications of the transactions and account balances.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-the-interest-rates-on-savings-in-the-special-medisave-and-retirement-accounts-be-maintained-at-a-floor-rate",
        "question": "Will the interest rates on savings in the Special, MediSave and Retirement Account be maintained at a floor rate?",
        "answer": "To help CPF members grow their savings, the Government has decided to further extend the 4% floor rate for interest earned on all Special, MediSave and Retirement Account (SMRA) savings for another year until 31 December 2025.SMRA savings will earn a minimum 4% interest rate per annum until 31 December 2025.Please refer to our FAQ onhow CPF interest rates are determinedfor more information.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-know-about-topping-up-my-retirement-savings",
        "question": "What should I know about topping up my retirement savings?",
        "answer": "Here are the 3 things you need to know about topping up your retirement savings. Tax relief is subject toterms and conditions..",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-should-i-top-up-my-retirement-savings",
        "question": "Why should I top up my retirement savings?",
        "answer": "There are several reasons why you should consider topping up your retirement savings:1. Higher monthly payouts in retirementBy topping up your Special Account (SA) (if you are below 55) or Retirement Account (RA) (if you are 55 or above), you are growing your retirement savings and will enjoyhigher monthly payoutswhen you retire.2. Risk-free interest rates* of up to 6% per annumBy topping up your SA or RA, you can earn risk-freeinterest rates* of up to 6% per annumon your savings.For instance, if you save $100 a month for 15 years on your own, you would have saved $18,000. On the other hand, if you top up $100 a month to your SA or RA for the same amount of time, you would have saved over $24,000*. If you continue to top up for another 10 years, your savings would grow even more, reaching over $50,000* with compound interest.3. Enjoy tax relief and matching grant for cash top-upsBy topping up with cash, you can also benefit from:Tax relief of up to $16,000.Terms and conditions apply.Matching dollar-for-dollar grant from the Government if you are eligible for theMatched Retirement Savings Scheme.Terms and conditions apply.*Based on the current 4%interest ratefloor on Special and Retirement Account monies.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-the-top-ups-to-my-retirement-savings-be-used",
        "question": "How will the top-ups to my retirement savings be used?",
        "answer": "Top-up monies will form part of yourretirement sumand give youhigher monthly payouts in retirement. As such, top-up monies cannot be withdrawn as a lump sum, withdrawn from your Retirement Account savings using property, or transferred to your loved ones.Additionally, top-up monies cannot be used for other CPF schemes, such aswithdrawal for immediate retirement needs,withdrawal on exemption from setting aside a retirement sum, and other CPF schemes for education, investment, insurance, housing etc.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-top-up-using-cash-or-cpf-transfers",
        "question": "Can I top up using cash or CPF transfers?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can top up your retirement savings using cash or by making CPF transfers. Please take note thatCPF transfers do not qualify for tax relieformatching grant from the government under the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme.If you wish to increase your own or your loved ones' retirement savings, you can find out more here:Who you can make top-ups toWho you can receive top-ups fromHow much you can top up via cashHow much you can top up via CPF transfer",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-can-i-make-top-ups-to",
        "question": "Who can I make top-ups to?",
        "answer": "Cash top-upsYou can make cash top-ups to any Singapore Citizen or Permanent Resident.Find out the amount of cash top-ups you can make to a recipient.CPF transfersYou can only make CPF transfers to yourself or yourloved ones. CPF transfers can only be made to a Singapore Citizen or Permanent Resident.Find out the amount of CPF transfers you can make to yourself or your loved ones.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-can-i-receive-top-ups-from",
        "question": "Who can I receive top-ups from?",
        "answer": "Cash top-upsYou can receive cash top-ups from anyone, including yourself, your family, employers, platform operators or any member of the community.CPF transfersYou can receive CPF transfers only from yourself or yourloved ones.You must be a Singapore Citizen or Permanent Resident to receive a top-up.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-are-considered-my-loved-ones",
        "question": "Who are considered my loved ones?",
        "answer": "Your loved ones refer to your parents, parents-in-law, grandparents, grandparents-in-law, spouse and siblings.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/is-there-a-minimum-or-maximum-age-for-making-or-receiving-top-ups",
        "question": "Is there a minimum or maximum age for making or receiving top-ups?",
        "answer": "There is no maximum age for making or receiving top-ups.However, you will need to be at least 16 years old to be a giver of cash top-ups.You can make cash top-ups to a child who is not yet 16 years old, and you can find out how to do sohere.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-still-receive-top-ups-if-i-have-started-my-monthly-retirement-payouts",
        "question": "Can I still receive top-ups if I have started my monthly retirement payouts?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can receive top-ups as long as you have not reached thecurrent Enhanced Retirement Sum.Find outhow much top-ups you can receive.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-differences-between-topping-up-my-retirement-savings-making-a-voluntary-housing-refund-and-topping-up-my-medisave-account",
        "question": "What are the differences between topping up my retirement savings, making a Voluntary Housing Refund and topping up my MediSave Account?",
        "answer": "Find out what the differences between the various types of top-ups are below:Topping up your retirement savingsVoluntary Housing RefundTopping up your MediSave AccountTop up/refund toSpecial Account (SA) for members below 55; orRetirement Account (RA) for members 55 or above.Ordinary Account (OA); and/orRA for members 55 or above and have not met their Full Retirement Sum (FRS) in their RA.MediSave Account (MA)Eligibility for tax reliefYou can enjoy tax relief if you madecash top-ups to yourself or your loved ones up to the current FRS.However, please note that tax relief would not apply if you made a CPF transfer.You will not be eligible for tax relief.For non self-employed persons:You get to enjoytax relieffor voluntary top-ups to MA.If you are self-employed, you will enjoytax reliefon yourMediSave contributionsbased on your annual net trade income (NTI). There will be no tax relief for your MediSave contributions if your assessed NTI for the year of assessment is zero or negative.Top-up limitWhat is the maximum amount of top-ups I can receive?If you are below 55, you may top up your SA up to the current FRS.If you are 55 or above, you may top up your RA up to the current Enhanced Retirement Sum.You can check your top-up limit in yourRetirement Dashboard.Can I voluntarily refund a portion of the CPF savings I used for my property?You can make a refund of any amount, capped at the full principal amount you have withdrawn for the property, along with the accrued interest.You may check the amount that you can refund through theHome Ownership Dashboard.Do note that after making a full voluntary housing refund of the CPF savings withdrawn and accrued interest, all CPF withdrawals including monthly housing loan instalments (if any) for the property will stop.What is the voluntary top-up limit to my MediSave Account?The maximum amount you can voluntarily top up to your MA is the difference between yourBasic Healthcare Sum (BHS)and your current MA balance. Once your BHS has been reached, no further voluntary top-ups can be made to your MA. If you exceed your BHS from the top-up, the full amount of your top-up will be refunded to you.You can check your top-up limitwith these steps.WithdrawalTop-ups are meant to boost your retirement income. They will be streamed out to you as monthly payouts and cannot be used for other purposes.You can continue to use your OA savings for the current or next property after making a voluntary housing refund.However, if you would like to use your OA for the same property, after making a voluntary refund of the full principal amount used and the accrued interest, you will need to re-apply to use your CPF savings.After turning 55 and setting aside the FRS, you can withdraw the remaining balance in your OA and SA in full or in part at any time.From 55, you can make retirement withdrawals from your OA and SA in full or in part, at any time for your immediate needs, provided you have set aside your FRS.MA savings are meant for your healthcare needs and cannot be withdrawn as cash.ApplicationTop-ups can be made using cash and/or CPF transfers.How do I apply to make a top-up?Refund can only be made via cash.How can I make a voluntary refund of the housing amount withdrawn if I am not selling my property?Top-ups can only be made via cash.How can I top up to myself, my children or my loved ones’ MediSave Account?Click thislinkto find out what the CPF interest rates are.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-received-an-email-notification-on-topping-up-my-and-or-my-loved-ones-retirement-savings-how-do-i-know-if-the-notification-is-indeed-sent-by-cpf-board",
        "question": "I received an email notification on topping up my and/or my loved ones’ retirement savings. How do I know if the notification is indeed sent by CPF Board?",
        "answer": "Members will receive email notifications at the email address registered with the Board. You maycheck or update your email addresswhich you have earlier registered with us using your Singpass.To verify if the email you received is legitimate andavoid falling prey to phishing scams,Ensure that the sender's email address is correctly spelt and ends with \"@e.cpf.gov.sg\".Ensure that the hyperlinks or links you click on has a domain ending with “.gov.sg”.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-will-the-top-ups-received-in-my-cpf-special-retirement-account-start-to-earn-interest",
        "question": "When will the top-ups received in my CPF Special/Retirement Account start to earn interest?",
        "answer": "If you receive a cash top-up this month, it will start earning interest in the next month.For CPF transfers of existing CPF savings, you will start earning interest in your account from this month. However, if the CPF savings are fresh injections, it will start earning interest in your account from the next month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-am-55-and-would-like-to-make-a-cpf-transfer-in-what-order-will-my-savings-be-transferred",
        "question": "If I am 55 and would like to make a CPF transfer, in what order will my savings be transferred?",
        "answer": "CPF transfers to your Retirement Account (RA)If you are 55 or above, your CPF savings will be transferred to your RA in the following order:Special Account (SA)Ordinary Account (OA)CPF transfers to yourloved onesIf you are 55 or above, your CPF savings will betransferred to your loved onesin the following order:OASARA**If you use your RA savings for the transfer, you may no longer have enough savings to meet your Full Retirement Sum (FRS). In that case, the next time you apply for a withdrawal from your OA and SA, a portion or all of the savings will be used to meet your FRS in the RA.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-55-can-i-transfer-my-ordinary-account-savings-to-my-special-account-to-earn-a-higher-interest-rate",
        "question": "I am 55, can I transfer my Ordinary Account savings to my Special Account to earn a higher interest rate?",
        "answer": "No, you will not be able to make CPF transfers to your Special Account (SA) after you turn 55. Instead, your transfers will be made to your Retirement Account (RA), which was created for your retirement needs.Did you know?If you wish to earn higherintereston your Ordinary Account (OA) savings (which earns at least 2.5% interest* per annum) and boost your monthly payouts, you canmake a CPF transferto your RA (which earns at least 4% interest* per annum), up to the current Enhanced Retirement Sum. Do note that for CPF transfers to RA, your SA savings (if any) will be transferred first followed by your OA savings.* Based on the current interest rate floor on Ordinary and Retirement Account monies.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-am-i-not-allowed-to-transfer-my-cpf-savings-to-my-children",
        "question": "Why am I not allowed to transfer my CPF savings to my children?",
        "answer": "Your CPF savings are meant to support your retirement needs. Your children would be able to accumulate savings in their working years. Hence, it is more important to prioritise your own retirement savings and ensure that you have sufficient funds to support your retirement needs.Find outhow you can use cash to top up your child's CPF account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-am-i-not-allowed-to-do-a-cpf-transfer-to-my-extended-family-members-e-g-uncles-aunts-cousins",
        "question": "Why am I not allowed to do a CPF transfer to my extended family members (e.g. uncles/aunts/cousins)?",
        "answer": "The CPF system is meant to provide for and safeguard your individual retirement adequacy. Hence we must be careful when considering allowing CPF transfers to extended family members, beyond immediate family members such as your parents, spouse and siblings. Meanwhile, you can consider using cash to top up to your extended family member's CPF account instead.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-wish-to-make-both-a-cpf-transfer-and-a-cash-top-up-to-myself-my-loved-one-which-should-i-do-first",
        "question": "If I wish to make both a CPF transfer and a cash top-up to myself / my loved one, which should I do first?",
        "answer": "If you wish to enjoy tax relief on your cash top-up to help you or your loved one up to the Full Retirement Sum, please make the cash top-up first, before the CPF transfer. If you prefer using your CPF savings over cash, please make the CPF transfer first.You may wish to take note that only cash top-ups to self and loved ones within the Full Retirement Sum can enjoy tax relief. Learn more abouttax relief.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-is-the-best-time-to-top-up-to-grow-my-savings",
        "question": "When is the best time to top up to grow my savings?",
        "answer": "You should top up as early as possible to maximise the growth of your CPF savings through the power of compound interest.Additionally, you can earn more interest if you top up earlier in the year. For example, if you top up in January each year instead of in December, you can earn up to 20%* more interest on your top-ups in 10 years.* Based on the current 4%interest ratefloor on Special and Retirement Account monies and extra interest of up to 2% per annum on the first $60,000 of your combined CPF balances, with $8,000 annual top-up and $0 starting balance.Do top up early in the year to ensure that your top-ups are processed before the year end as the normal processing time may take longer in December if there is a surge in applications.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-check-my-top-up-limits",
        "question": "How can I check my top-up limits?",
        "answer": "You can check your top-up limit in yourRetirement Dashboard.Find outhow the top up limit is computed.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-maximum-amount-of-top-ups-i-can-receive",
        "question": "What is the maximum amount of top-ups I can receive?",
        "answer": "The maximum amount of top-ups you can receive depends on your age and amount of CPF savings you have. You can easily check your top-up limit in yourRetirement Dashboard.You can refer to theseexampleson how the maximum top-up amount is computed.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-am-i-not-able-to-top-up-my-special-retirement-account-beyond-the-current-full-retirement-sum-frs-below-55-or-enhanced-retirement-sum-ers-55-or-above",
        "question": "Why am I not able to top up my Special/Retirement Account beyond the current Full Retirement Sum (FRS) (below 55) or Enhanced Retirement Sum (ERS) (55 or above)?",
        "answer": "The CPF system is designed to cater to the basic retirement needs of the broad majority of Singaporeans.If you are below 55, you can top up your Special Account up to the current year’s Full Retirement Sum (FRS) to build up your retirement savings. If you wish to save beyond the FRS, you can choose to tap on theSupplementary Retirement Scheme, where contributions are also eligible for tax relief.If you are 55 or above, retirement becomes a higher priority. As such, members have the option to voluntarily top up beyond the FRS up to thecurrent year’s Enhanced Retirement Sum (ERS)for higher payouts. This could help the middle-income group better meet their retirement needs.Find out more aboutwhat the retirement sums are.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-cpf-savings-can-i-transfer-to-myself-or-my-loved-ones",
        "question": "How much CPF savings can I transfer to myself or my loved ones?",
        "answer": "You can easily check the maximum amount of CPF savings you can transfer in yourRetirement Dashboard.If you would like to learn more about how the amount shown on your Retirement Dashboard is computed, please refer to the table below.Do note that the actual amount of CPF savings you can transfer may also depend on your recipient's availabletop-up limit.Recipient of CPF TransferAvailable CPF Savings for TransferIf you are below 55If you are 55 or aboveSelfAny amount of your Ordinary Account (OA) savings to your Special Account (SA).Any amount of your Ordinary Account (OA) savings and Special Account (SA) savings to your Retirement Account (RA)*.SpouseYour OA savings after setting aside the current Basic Retirement Sum (BRS)1.Example(PDF, 72KB)Your CPF savings4after setting aside your Basic Retirement Sum (BRS)5.Example(PDF, 72KB)Parents and/or grandparentsIf you own a property3, you can transfer your OA savings after setting aside the current BRS1, provided you can meet the current Full Retirement Sum (FRS) with your OA savings, SA savings, the net amount withdrawn for investments2and property3.If you do not own a property3, you can transfer your OA savings after setting aside the current FRS1.Example(PDF, 91.7KB)If you own a property7, you can transfer your CPF savings4after setting aside your BRS5, provided you can meet your Full Retirement Sum (FRS) with your OA savings, SA savings, RA savings6, net amount withdrawn for investments2and property7.If you do not own a property7, you can transfer your CPF savings4after setting aside your FRS5.Example(PDF, 91.7KB)Siblings, parents-in-law and/or grandparents-in-lawYour OA savings after setting aside the current FRS1.Example(PDF, 25.9KB)Your OA savings after setting aside your FRS5.Example(PDF, 25.9KB)Find out what are theretirement sums applicable to you.*Your SA savings will be transferred first, followed by your OA savings.1Can be set aside using your OA savings, SA savings and net amount withdrawn for investments2.2Refers to amounts withdrawn for (i) an active investment account under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)-OA, and (ii) investments under the CPFIS-SA and discounted Singtel shares that have not been completely disposed of.3Refers to the CPF savings used for property, including accrued interest (P+I). If you have set aside the BRS and own a property bought using CPF savings, the P+I can be considered towards meeting the FRS for making CPF transfers to your parents and/or grandparents. The property you own must have remaining lease that can last you to at least 95 years old.4Your OA savings will be transferred first, followed by your SA and then your RA savings6, if applicable. You can write to CPF Board to specify the CPF accounts from which to transfer to your spouse, parents and/or grandparents. Please note that if you use your RA savings6for the transfer, the sum of your RA savings6and property7may be less than your FRS. As a result, when you make a withdrawal from your OA and SA, a portion of the savings will be used to meet your FRS in the RA.5Can be set aside using your OA savings, SA savings, RA savings6, and net amount withdrawn for investments2.6Refer to the cash set aside in the RA (excluding amounts such as interest earned, any government grants received), plus retirement withdrawals.7Refers to the CPF savings used for property, including accrued interest (P+I). If you have set aside the BRS and own a property bought using CPF savings, the P+I can be considered towards meeting the FRS for making CPF transfers to your parents and/or grandparents. The property you own must have remaining lease that can last you to at least 95 years old. If you have pledged your property for purposes of setting aside part of your retirement sum or to withdraw your retirement savings, the amount secured by the property can be considered towards meeting the FRS for this CPF transfer.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/is-there-a-limit-to-the-number-of-top-ups-i-can-make-or-receive-in-a-year",
        "question": "Is there a limit to the number of top-ups I can make or receive in a year?",
        "answer": "There is no limit to the number of top-ups you can make or receiveas long as the recipient can still receive top-ups.It is important to note that once you make a top-up, it cannot be reversed. Therefore, we advise you to review that you have sufficient cash or CPF savings for other expenses before making the top-up.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-top-up-my-retirement-savings-to-the-enhanced-retirement-sum-ers",
        "question": "Can I top up my retirement savings to the Enhanced Retirement Sum (ERS)?",
        "answer": "If you are aged 55 or above, you have the option to top up your Retirement Account (RA) up to thecurrent year’s Enhanced Retirement Sum (ERS)as retirement becomes an even higher priority.If you are aged below 55, you can start building up more retirement savings by topping up your Special Account up to thecurrent year’s Full Retirement Sum (FRS). Once you reach age 55, you can then choose to set aside more in your RA, up to the current year’s ERS.You can check your top-up limit on yourRetirement Dashboard.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-enhanced-retirement-sum-ers",
        "question": "What is the Enhanced Retirement Sum (ERS)?",
        "answer": "The Enhanced Retirement Sum (ERS) in 2025 is $426,000. This is the maximum amount that members aged 55 and above can top up their Retirement Accounts (RA) to in 2025. From 1 January 2025, the ERS amount is 4 times of the current year’s Basic Retirement Sum (BRS) and provides members the option to top up more for higher payouts.The ERS amount is not dependent on your age or the year you turn 55 years old. It increases yearly on 1 January. Here are the ERS amounts for 2025 to 2027:Year202520262027Enhanced Retirement Sum$426,000$440,800$456,400You can top up more to your RA every year when the ERS increases. To illustrate, a member aged 55 and above in 2025 would be able to top up to $426,000. In 2026, when the ERS is increased to $440,800 the member will be able to top up a further $14,800 (i.e. $440,800 - $426,000).You can top up your RA with cash or your Ordinary Account (OA) and Special Account (SA) savings. Topping up your RA allows you to receive higher monthly payouts in retirement. This allows members to get higher CPF LIFE monthly payouts of up to $3,300 for life from age 65 through CPF top-ups.Learn more about the payouts you can receive if you top up to the ERS.You may check the maximum amount you can top up on yourRetirement Dashboard.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/am-i-eligible-for-tax-reliefs-when-i-make-a-cash-top-up-to-my-my-loved-ones-retirement-savings",
        "question": "Am I eligible for tax reliefs when I make a cash top-up to my/my loved ones' retirement savings?",
        "answer": "You can enjoy tax relief if you are a Singapore Citizen or Permanent Resident and make cash top-ups*within the current year’s Full Retirement Sum for yourself, yourloved ones, employees or platform workers.Find out more aboutthe amount of tax relief you can enjoy.Find out more on theconditions to qualify for tax relief.*From 1 January 2025, givers of cash top-ups that attract the matching grant (up to $2,000 per year) under the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) will no longer receive tax relief. Find out more onhow this works.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-tax-relief-can-i-enjoy-when-i-make-cash-top-ups",
        "question": "How much tax relief can I enjoy when I make cash top-ups?",
        "answer": "You can enjoy an equivalent amount of tax relief for cash top-ups made in each calendar year of up to:$8,000 if you make a top-up to yourself; andan additional $8,000 if you make a cash top-up to yourloved ones.Please note that only cash top-ups up to the current year’s Full Retirement Sum (FRS) are eligible for tax relief.Log in with your Singpassto find out how much you can top up to yourself. If you make cash top-ups to your loved ones, please note that the tax relief does not apply to your recipients. Find out theconditions to qualify for tax relief.If your employer or platform operator made a cash top-up on your behalf, you could receive up to $8,000* of tax relief per calendar year. If you are an employer or platform operator making cash top-ups to your employees' or platform workers’ Special/ Retirement accounts, youmay claim tax deduction on the cash top-ups when filing your company’s income tax return.* Includes any tax relief that the employee or platform worker would enjoy for cash top-ups made to himself.From 1 January 2025, givers of cash top-ups that attract the matching grant (up to $2,000 per year) under the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) will no longer receive tax relief. Find out more onhow this works.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-conditions-for-me-to-enjoy-tax-relief",
        "question": "What are the conditions for me to enjoy tax relief?",
        "answer": "The conditions for you to enjoy tax relief when you make cash top-ups to yourself, your loved ones, employees or platform workers are as follows:You can enjoy tax relief of up to $8,000 if you make a top-up to yourself; and an additional $8,000 if you make a cash top-up to yourloved ones.For cash top-ups to self and your loved ones, tax relief is only up to the current year’s Full Retirement Sum (FRS).Log in with your Singpassto see how much you can top up to yourself.There is a personal income tax relief cap of $80,000, which applies to all tax reliefs, including tax relief on cash top-ups made to your CPF accounts.The tax relief cap will be shared for cash top-ups to Special Account (SA)/Retirement Account (RA) and/or cash top-ups to MediSave Account (MA) *. Find out more aboutthe amount of tax relief you can enjoy.If you make cash top-ups to your loved ones, please note that tax relief does not apply to your recipients.Your loved ones include parents, parents-in-law, grandparents, grandparents-in-law, spouse and siblings.If you are making cash top-ups to a spouse or sibling, you will only be eligible for the tax relief if the recipient's income in the previous year does not exceed $8,000 or if the recipient is handicapped^. In this instance, income would include income from bank interest, dividend and pension, investment income/rental income/directorship income. An example of a handicapped person is someone with visual-impairment, loss of hearing, loss of limb and dementia.If you are making a cash top-up to the SA/RA of your employee or platform worker on his behalf, you will be eligible for an equivalent amount of tax deductions for the cash top-ups made. While such a cash top-up will be included in your employee or platform worker's taxable income, your employee or platform worker will receive tax relief of up to $8,000 for cash top-ups made in each calendar year. The tax relief that your employee or platform worker will receive also takes into consideration any cash top-ups that he has made to his own SA/RA and MA.If you would like to make a CPF contribution to your employee or platform worker’s MA as an employer or platform operator, please do so under the Additional MediSave Contribution Scheme (AMCS) to be eligible for tax deduction on your contribution. AMCS contributions are tax-free for employees and platform workers.From 1 January 2025, givers of cash top-ups that attract the matching grant (up to $2,000 per year) under the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) will no longer receive tax relief. Find out more onhow this works.You can learn more abouttax relief.*The changes related to cash top-ups to MA do not apply to MA contributions made in the capacity of a self-employed person (SEP). If you would like to make MA contributions in the capacity of a SEP, visit theSelf-Employed Scheme pagefor more information on topping up your MA.^This refers to people who are incapacitated because of physical or mental infirmity.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-there-a-combined-tax-relief-cap-for-top-ups-to-the-special-account-retirement-account-and-medisave-account-from-1-january-2022",
        "question": "Why is there a combined tax relief cap for top-ups to the Special Account/Retirement Account and MediSave Account from 1 January 2022?",
        "answer": "Thecombined tax relieffor cash top-ups to the Special/Retirement Account and MediSave Account (MA) was introduced for greater consistency across CPF schemes. This allows members to better understand and take action to benefit from these schemes.The tax relief eligibility conditions for cash top-ups made before 1 January 2022 had differed1for top-ups to retirement savings and top-ups to MA. With this change2, the tax relief eligibility conditions for cash top-ups made on or after 1 January 2022 across both schemes have been aligned.1Before 1 January 2022, the tax relief eligibility conditions for cash top-ups differed between both scheme in terms of (i) tax beneficiary [giver for Retirement Sum Topping-Up (RSTU); recipient for Voluntary Contribution to MediSave Account (VCMA)]; and (ii) tax relief cap for top-ups to self/loved ones (capped at $7k/$7k for RSTU, tax relief cap for VCMA depended on both the Basic Healthcare Sum and the amount of mandatory CPF contributions for the year).2The changes related to cash top-ups to MA do not apply to MA contributions made as a self-employed person (SEP). If you would like to make MA contributions as a SEP, visit theSelf-Employed Scheme pagefor more information on topping up your MA.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-should-i-submit-my-top-up-application-if-i-want-to-be-eligible-for-tax-relief-in-the-next-assessment-year",
        "question": "When should I submit my top-up application if I want to be eligible for tax relief in the next assessment year?",
        "answer": "Your online top-up application and payment will need to reach us by 31 December of the year.It is important to note that the tax relief is granted based on the calendar year in which the top-up is made, regardless of the actual date of submission.We would also encourage you to top up earlier in the year. Find outwhy you should top up as early as possible.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-actions-do-i-need-to-take-to-file-and-claim-tax-relief-for-my-cash-top-up",
        "question": "What actions do I need to take to file and claim tax relief for my cash top-up?",
        "answer": "You do not need to file or claim tax relief for your cash top-up as we will automatically inform Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) if you have instructed to claim tax relief in your top-up application and are eligible.If you made a cash top-up to your spouse and/or sibling between 1 January 2024 and 16 February 2024 and wish to amend your instructions to claim tax relief for the top-up made due to the increase in income threshold from $4,000 to $8,000, you can refer tothis FAQ.Please note that only givers who make cash top-ups are eligible for tax relief. If you make cash top-ups to your loved ones, the tax relief does not apply to your receipients. Find outthe conditions to enjoy tax relief.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-personal-income-tax-relief-cap-and-why-is-there-a-cap-on-this-relief-for-cash-top-ups-made",
        "question": "What is the personal income tax relief cap and why is there a cap on this relief for cash top-ups made?",
        "answer": "Thepersonal income tax relief capsets a limit on the total amount of tax relief you can claim.Even though each relief serves a good purpose, some individuals may end up with a significantly reduced taxable income when multiple reliefs are combined. Therefore, tax relief on cash top-ups is also subjected to the personal income tax relief cap.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-find-out-if-i-have-reached-the-personal-income-tax-relief-cap",
        "question": "How can I find out if I have reached the personal income tax relief cap?",
        "answer": "You can use thetax calculatoron Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) website to find out if you have reached your personal income tax relief cap.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-there-no-tax-relief-for-top-ups-made-to-my-children-or-non-immediate-family",
        "question": "Why is there no tax relief for top-ups made to my children or non-immediate family?",
        "answer": "Tax relief is an incentive given to encourage members to build up retirement savings for themselves or their immediate family members, particularly older Singaporeans who may have less retirement savings.Your children have more time to accumulate savings in their working years for their own retirement needs. Hence, there is no tax relief for top-ups made to your children or non-immediate family members.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-cpf-transfers-not-eligible-for-tax-relief",
        "question": "Why are CPF transfers not eligible for tax relief?",
        "answer": "CPF contributions are tax-deductible. Therefore, when they are transferred from one CPF account to another, they will not enjoy tax benefits.Considertopping up using cashto enjoy tax relief while boosting your retirement payouts. Find outthe conditions to enjoy tax relief.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-cash-top-ups-beyond-full-retirement-sum-not-eligible-for-tax-relief",
        "question": "Why are cash top-ups beyond Full Retirement Sum not eligible for tax relief?",
        "answer": "Givers enjoy tax relief for cash top-ups up to the current Full Retirement Sum (FRS). This is in line with the intent of tax relief benefits to encourage cash top-ups to members with lower to average CPF retirement balances.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-an-employer-who-made-cash-top-ups-to-my-employees-platform-workers-cpf-accounts-on-their-behalf-how-do-i-claim-corporate-tax-deductions",
        "question": "I am an employer or platform operator who made cash top-ups to my employees or platform workers’ CPF Accounts on their behalf. How do I claim corporate tax deductions?",
        "answer": "Cash top-ups made to your employees or platform workers’ CPF Retirement Accounts/ Special Accounts, on the employees or platform workers’ behalf, are tax-deductible. You are able to claim tax deduction on the cash top-ups as part of your allowable business expenses when filing the income tax return (Form B) for self-employed person or (Form C-S/ Form C-S (Lite)/ Form C) for company.For more information, you may refer to the IRAS website onTop-Up of Employees’ CPF RetirementAccounts/ Special Accounts/ MediSave Accounts.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-apply-to-make-a-top-up",
        "question": "How do I apply to make a top-up?",
        "answer": "To make a top-up,you can refer to the following table:Application modePayment viaGuideWebRecurring cash top-upsvia GIROGuideOne-time cash top-upvia PayNow QRGuide(PDF, 0.1MB)Video GuideCPF transferGuideCPF Mobile appPayNow QROCBC DigitalEnglishChineseMalayTamilCPF transferGuideEmployers or platform operators who wish to make cash top-ups for their employees or platform workers canapply onlineusingCorppass. If you do not have Corppass, you maywrite to usfor an alternate application mode.* If you are making afirst-timeCPF transfer to your loved ones, find out thesupporting documents that you need to submit.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-long-does-it-take-to-process-my-top-up-application",
        "question": "How long does it take to process my top-up application?",
        "answer": "Please refer to the table for our normal processing time for processing top-up applications:Top-Up ViaPayment ModeNormal Processing timeProcessingDeduction and CreditingCashPayNow QROCBC DigitalAlmost instantlyOnline GIRO (participatingbankusers)Upon successful application to set up GIRO to make cash top-ups, please allowone day for your GIRO bank account to be updated in the Board's record.GIRO deduction will take effect from the following month upon successful application of your recurring cash top-ups.If you are updating your GIRO bank account,find out more on the GIRO deduction for your existing recurring top-up arrangements.We will deduct the monies from your bank account on the 15thof the month (or the next working day if 15thfalls on a Saturday, Sunday or Public Holiday).Your top-up will be credited within seven working days after we receive your payment.Note: Please ensure that you maintain sufficient funds in your bank account for GIRO deductions. Some banks may charge an administrative fee for each unsuccessful deduction.CPF Transfer-Five working days upon receipt of applicationIn some cases, we may require additional time to verify your application. We will contact you within five working days to request for more information.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-should-i-submit-my-application-for-my-top-up-to-be-processed-within-the-same-month",
        "question": "When should I submit my application for my top-up to be processed within the same month?",
        "answer": "If you are making a cash top-upBoth your application and payment should be made by the following timings:Payment modeWhen payment should be madePayNow QRWithin last day of the monthOCBC Digital (available for applications via CPF Mobile app only)Online GIROYour GIRO instruction will take effect in the same month If you submitboth:GIRO application; andStanding Instructionwithin the first seven days of the month.To have your cash top-up processed quickly, we encourage payment via PayNow QR or OCBC Digital. Your cash top-up will generally be creditedalmost instantlyupon successful payment.If you are making a CPF transferYou should submit your application before the 5thlast working day of the month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-fastest-way-to-make-a-cash-top-up",
        "question": "What is the fastest way to make a cash top-up?",
        "answer": "The fastest way to make a cash top-up would be via PayNow QR or OCBC Digital (for applications via CPF Mobile app oronline form). Your cash top-up will generally be creditedalmost instantlyupon successful payment.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-apply-for-internet-or-mobile-banking",
        "question": "How can I apply for internet or mobile banking?",
        "answer": "Applying for internet or mobile banking is easy and convenient. To get started, you can refer to thedigital banking resourcescompiled by Infocomm Media Development Authority (IMDA). This list provides a comprehensive guide on how to apply for internet or mobile banking with various banks in Singapore.You can also visit anySG Digital community hubto enjoy one-on-one guidance from IMDA’s digital ambassadors, who would be happy to assist you in setting up your internet or mobile banking account and answer any questions you may have.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-increase-my-internet-or-mobile-banking-transfer-limit",
        "question": "How can I increase my internet or mobile banking transfer limit?",
        "answer": "You can increase your internet or mobile banking transfer limit via your bank’s internet or mobile banking portal. Please refer to the guides below:Payment via PayNow:1.POSB/DBS– DigibankLanguageEnglishChineseMalayTamil2.UOB– UOB TMRWLanguageEnglishChineseMalayTamil3.OCBC– OCBC DigitalLanguageEnglishChineseMalayTamil4.Standard Chartered5.HSBC6.Maybank7.CitibankYou may also wish to refer to the list ofPayNow participating banks.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-supporting-documents-will-i-need-if-i-m-making-a-first-time-cpf-transfer-to-my-loved-ones",
        "question": "What supporting documents will I need if I'm making a first-time CPF transfer to my loved ones?",
        "answer": "For first-time CPF transfers to your loved ones, you will need to submit the following supporting documents in the top-up application.CPF transfer toSupporting documentsSpouseMarriage certificate, if your marriage is registered overseasParent(s)Your birth certificateGrandparent(s)Your and your parent(s)’s birth certificatesSibling(s)Your and your sibling(s)’s birth certificatesParent(s)-in-lawYour overseas marriage certificate* and your spouse’s birth certificate.Grandparent(s)-in-lawYour overseas marriage certificate, your spouse’s and your spouse’s parent(s)’s birth certificates*Not required if your marriage is registered in SingaporeSupporting documents are not required for cash top-ups.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-make-cash-top-ups-to-my-child-s-cpf-retirement-savings",
        "question": "How can I make cash top-ups to my child's CPF retirement savings?",
        "answer": "To make cash top-ups to your child's CPF retirement savings (regardless his or her age), simply:1. Indicate your identification number as the giver of the cash top-up in the application2. Indicate your child's identification number as the recipient3. Select the relationship as \"Others\"Do note that givers of cash top-ups need to be at least 16 years old andcash top-ups to children will not qualify for tax relief.Find out more about the types ofcash top-ups which can enjoy tax relief.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-making-a-top-up-to-myself-from-overseas-how-can-i-set-up-a-singpass-account-if-i-do-not-have-a-mobile-phone-number-registered-in-singapore",
        "question": "I am making a top-up to myself from overseas. How can I set up a Singpass account if I do not have a mobile phone number registered in Singapore?",
        "answer": "If you wish to set up a Singpass account for your top-up application but do not have a mobile phone number registered in Singapore, you may contact theSingpass Helpdeskdirectly for assistance.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/my-child-is-below-16-years-old-how-do-i-transfer-his-ordinary-account-savings-to-his-special-account-on-his-behalf",
        "question": "My child is below 16 years old. How do I transfer his Ordinary Account savings to his Special Account on his behalf?",
        "answer": "If your child is below 16 years old and wishes to transfer his Ordinary Account savings to his Special Account, you can complete thisapplicationon his behalf.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-paynow-qr",
        "question": "What is PayNow QR?",
        "answer": "PayNow QR is a convenient and faster way for you to make payments by scanning a QR code using your mobile banking app. It is also secure as it adopts the same high security standards adopted by the Singapore banking industry for fund transfers such as FAST and GIRO.You can use PayNow QR if you have accounts with any of the following banks in Singapore: Citibank Singapore Limited, DBS Bank/POSB, HSBC, Maybank, OCBC Bank, Standard Chartered Bank, United Overseas Bank, Bank of China, and Industrial and Commercial Bank of China Limited.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-benefits-of-making-top-ups-via-the-paynow-qr",
        "question": "What are the benefits of making top-ups via the PayNow QR?",
        "answer": "Making top-ups via PayNow QR is hassle-free.All you need to do is scan the QR code provided at the end of your online application, and the required details such as payment amount and transaction type will be automatically included. You do not have to manually enter any details, so you can complete the payment quickly and conveniently.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-make-a-top-up-via-paynow-qr",
        "question": "How do I make a top-up via PayNow QR?",
        "answer": "To make a top-up via PayNow QR, you can follow these steps:1. Submit anonline applicationvia the CPF website2. Scan the PayNow QR code with your PayNow participating bank's appIt is important to make payment as soon as possible, as the QR code will expire at the end of the day of application. If the QR code expires, you will need to submit a new application and make payment using the new QR code generated at the end of the application.To guide you on making a top-up via PayNow QR, watch theinstructional videoin your preferred language.For POSB/DBS bank account holders, please refer to the top-up steps using Digibank.LanguageEnglishChineseMalayTamilFor UOB bank account holders, please refer to the top-up steps using UOB TMRW.LanguageEnglishChineseMalayTamilFor OCBC bank account holders, please refer to the top-up steps using OCBC Digital.LanguageEnglishChineseMalayTamilAlternatively, you can submit an application via CPF Mobile app. Similarly, the PayNow QR code will be generated at the acknowledgement page. You just need to save the QR code on your device and upload it to your PayNow participating bank's mobile app to make payment.To top up using PayNow via CPF Mobile app, you can refer to the steps listed below.LanguageEnglishChineseMalayTamil",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-maximum-amount-i-can-top-up-via-paynow-qr",
        "question": "What is the maximum amount I can top up via PayNow QR?",
        "answer": "The daily transaction limit with PayNow QR is capped at $200,000, which is further subject to monthly and daily transaction limits imposed by your bank.See guides on how to change your bank’s transfer limits if you need to do so.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-long-will-it-take-for-my-top-up-to-be-credited-via-paynow-qr",
        "question": "How long will it take for my top-up to be credited via PayNow QR?",
        "answer": "Top-ups via PayNow QR are generally credited almost instantly, upon successful payment.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-if-my-banking-app-is-unable-to-scan-the-paynow-qr-for-my-top-up-application",
        "question": "What if my banking app is unable to scan the PayNow QR for my top-up application?",
        "answer": "If you are having trouble scanning the PayNow QR code for your top-up application, you should reach out to your bank for assistance.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-if-i-scan-the-generated-paynow-qr-code-multiple-times",
        "question": "What happens if I scan the generated PayNow QR code multiple times?",
        "answer": "To ensure that your cash top-up is processed smoothly, please only scan the PayNow QR code and make payment once as the code is only valid for a single payment. For subsequent or duplicate payments made using the same QR code, the payment will be refunded.If you need to make another top-up, you will need to submit a new application and obtain a new PayNow QR code.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-made-a-paynow-qr-payment-but-i-am-not-able-to-see-an-immediate-update-to-my-cpf-balance-s-why-is-my-cpf-account-balance-s-not-updated-immediately",
        "question": "I have made a PayNow QR payment but I am not able to see an immediate update to my CPF balance(s). Why is my CPF account balance(s) not updated immediately?",
        "answer": "Such cases are extremely rare and may arise due to intermittent network connectivity issues beyond CPF Board's control. As a result, the status of your PayNow payment may be delayed, and your CPF account balance(s) may not be updated instantly. Please do not worry as your CPF account balance(s) will be updated within 3-5 working days and you will receive an email notification if you have registered your email address with us. Please check your CPF account balance(s)/E-form status again after 3-5 working days and alert us immediately if your payment is still not updated.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-make-regular-monthly-or-yearly-top-ups-conveniently-via-giro",
        "question": "How can I make recurring monthly or yearly top-ups conveniently via GIRO?",
        "answer": "You can make small and recurring cash top-ups via GIRO by following the steps below:Step 1:Set up a GIRO arrangementStep 2: Please allow one day for your GIRO bank account to be updated in the Board's record. Thereafter, please submit a request to makerecurring cash top-ups for retirement.Please note that you must completebothsteps for recurring cash top-ups via GIRO to be successful.Currently, the online application to set up a GIRO arrangement is only available for theseparticipating banks.If you encounter any difficulties in setting up GIRO, you maywrite to usfor assistance.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-revise-or-stop-my-giro-arrangement-for-my-top-up-application",
        "question": "How can I change or delete my recurring cash top-up arrangement?",
        "answer": "You canchangeyour existing recurring cash top-up arrangement such as the amount and frequency of top-ups by following the steps below:Delete your existing recurring cash top-up arrangement in theManage recurring cash top-ups for retirementform.Create a new recurring arrangement via the sameformwith your revised amount and/or frequency of the top-ups.You candeleteyour existing recurring cash top-up arrangement via theManage recurring cash top-ups for retirementform. Your application will generally be processed instantly upon submission.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-set-up-more-than-one-giro-arrangement-to-make-regular-top-ups",
        "question": "Can I set up more than one recurring cash top-up arrangement?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can make multiple recurring cash top-up arrangements for different recipients. You can add recurring top-up via theManage recurring cash top-ups for retirementform if you have already set up GIRO to make cash top-ups for retirement.If you have notset up GIROto make cash top-ups for retirement, you may do so via thislink.Please note that only one GIRO bank account can be used for your recurring cash top-up arrangements to your various top-up recipients.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-there-no-deductions-from-my-bank-account-for-my-top-up-even-though-i-have-set-up-a-giro-arrangement-online",
        "question": "Why are there no deductions from my bank account even though I have successfully made a recurring cash top-up arrangement?",
        "answer": "It could be due to one of the following reasons:If you have just made recurring cash top-up arrangements, the GIRO deduction might not have started yet. You may check the start month of your recurring cash top-up by accessing theManage recurring cash top-ups for retirementform, under “Who you are making recurring top-ups to”.If you have updated your GIRO bank account after 8th of the month, deductions will start from the following month instead of the current month.Find out more.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-is-the-deduction-date-of-my-recurring-cash-top-up-arrangements",
        "question": "When is the deduction date of my recurring cash top-up arrangements?",
        "answer": "The deduction from your bank account takes place on the 15th of the month (or the next working day if 15th falls on a Saturday, Sunday or Public Holiday).If you set up a new GIRO to make recurring cash top-ups:GIRO deduction for your recurring cash top-up will take effect from the following month upon successful application of your recurring top-ups.If you have updated your GIRO bank account for recurring cash top-ups:Deductions from your GIRO bank account for your recurring cash top-up(s) will take effect from the current month if you have updated your bank account before the 8th of the month. Otherwise, the deductions will be made from your new bank account from the following month.Note: Please ensure that you maintain sufficient funds in your bank account for GIRO deductions. Some banks may charge an administrative fee for each unsuccessful deduction.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-check-my-existing-recurring-cash-top-up-arrangements",
        "question": "How can I check my existing recurring cash top-up arrangements?",
        "answer": "You can check your existing recurring cash top-up arrangements, including the recipients, amount of cash top-ups, and frequency (monthly or yearly) by accessing theManage recurring cash top-ups for retirementform, under “Who you are making recurring top-ups to”.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-giro-bank-account-used-for-my-recurring-cash-top-up-arrangement",
        "question": "What is the GIRO bank account used for my recurring cash top-up arrangement?",
        "answer": "If you have an existing GIRO arrangement, you can view your current bank account used for your GIRO by accessingSet up GIRO for cash top-ups for retirement form, under “Select bank”.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-the-deduction-still-happening-after-i-have-successfully-deleted-my-recurring-cash-top-up-arrangement",
        "question": "Why is the deduction still happening after I have successfully deleted my recurring cash top-up arrangement?",
        "answer": "To ensure that your deduction request takes effect from current month onwards, delete it at least three working days before the current monthdeduction. Else, the deduction will still proceed.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-update-or-terminate-my-giro-bank-account-for-recurring-cash-top-ups",
        "question": "How can I update or terminate my GIRO bank account for recurring cash top-ups?",
        "answer": "You canupdateyour GIRO bank account for your recurring cash top-up bysetting up a new GIRO arrangement. If you have existing recurring top-up arrangements, the deductions could still be from your previous GIRO bank account for the current month.Find out more.You canterminateyour GIRO arrangement for your recurring cash top-up by submittingthis form. All monthly and/or yearly GIRO deductions for top-ups to your recipient(s) will cease.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-check-the-status-of-my-cash-top-up-and-or-cpf-transfer-application",
        "question": "How can I check the status of my cash top-up and/or CPF transfer application?",
        "answer": "You can check the status of your online application viaActivities. Once your cash top-up and/or CPF transfer application is successful, you will be able to find the details of the transaction on yourRetirement Dashboardunder the Retirement Sum Topping-Up History section.If you have submittedmultipleapplications, you can also review the status of each application underActivities. This will help you identify which transactions have been successfully processed, and you can also submit a new application if necessary.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/my-top-up-is-not-reflected-in-my-cpf-account-was-the-top-up-unsuccessful",
        "question": "My top-up is not reflected in my CPF account. Was the top-up unsuccessful?",
        "answer": "If your top-up is not reflected in your CPF accounts after the expiry of ourusual processing time, it might be due to one of the following reasons:You may have missed out in making payment for your cash top-up application.Find out how to submit a new application.You may have missed out in submitting supporting documents for first-time CPF transfers to a loved one.Find out what the required supporting documents are.We may require additional time to verify your application. We will contact you within five working days to request for more information.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/where-can-i-find-records-of-past-top-ups-made-by-me",
        "question": "Where can I find records of past top-ups made by me?",
        "answer": "You can check the top-up applications made by you in the last five years on yourRetirement Dashboardunder the Retirement Savings Topping-Up History section. For records beyond five years, you can refer to thisFAQon how to retrieve your or your recipient’s last 10 years of Yearly Statement of Account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-made-top-ups-to-my-special-account-before-turning-55-what-will-happen-to-the-top-ups-when-i-turn-55",
        "question": "I made top-ups to my Special Account before turning 55. What will happen to the top-ups when I turn 55?",
        "answer": "When you turn 55, the top-ups made to your Special Account and accrued interest will betransferred to your Retirement Account (RA)up to your Full Retirement Sum (FRS).Please note that top-up monies are meant to build up your retirement savings and cannot be withdrawn for other purposes. Read more onhow the top-ups will be used.If you are 55 or above and have excess savings above your FRS, you can apply towithdraw them for your immediate needsanytime. Alternatively, you canmake top-upsto your RA (up to the current Enhanced Retirement Sum) to enjoy higher monthly payouts in retirement.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-withdraw-the-top-up-monies-if-i-have-the-full-retirement-sum-or-the-basic-retirement-sum-if-i-own-a-property",
        "question": "Can I withdraw the top-up monies if I have the Full Retirement Sum, or the Basic Retirement Sum if I own a property?",
        "answer": "You will not be able to withdraw the top-up monies as the higher interest rate and tax incentives are given to encourage members to build up their retirement savings. Allowing withdrawals after members have enjoyed these incentives would defeat the purpose of the topping-up scheme.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-my-monthly-payouts-change-after-topping-up",
        "question": "How will my monthly payouts change after topping up?",
        "answer": "If you are onCPF LIFE, topping up your Retirement Account will allow you to enjoy higher monthly payouts for life. If you arenot on CPF LIFE, the top-ups will generally allow you to receive higher payouts or receive payouts for a longer time.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-reverse-my-top-up",
        "question": "Can I reverse my top-up?",
        "answer": "No, cash top-ups and CPF transfers are irreversible. The top-ups/CPF transfers to your Special Account or Retirement Account savings earn a higherinterest rateas the savings are locked in for the long-term. This is similar to the market practice where the interest earned on fixed deposits is higher compared to interest earned on savings deposits that are withdrawable anytime.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-my-cash-top-ups-or-cpf-transfers-be-refunded-to-me-if-the-recipient-passes-away",
        "question": "Will my cash top-ups or CPF transfers be refunded to me if the recipient passes away?",
        "answer": "Cash top-ups and CPF transfers will generally be treated as gifts to the recipient. Any unused cash top-ups and CPF transfers will be paid to the recipient's nominees based on hisCPF nomination. This is subject tosafeguards to prevent premature withdrawals.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-to-my-unused-cpf-transfers-and-cash-top-ups-to-my-recipient-upon-his-demise-or-if-he-closes-his-cpf-account-upon-leaving-singapore",
        "question": "What happens to my unused CPF transfers and cash top-ups to my recipient upon his demise or if he closes his CPF account upon leaving Singapore?",
        "answer": "Cash top-ups and CPF transfers will generally be treated as gifts to the recipient. Any unused cash top-ups or CPF transfers will be paid to the recipient's beneficiaries upon his demise, or to the recipient himself if he closes his CPF account and withdraws his CPF savings upon leaving Singapore. This is subject tosafeguards to prevent premature withdrawals.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-does-cpf-board-guard-against-premeditated-early-cpf-withdrawals",
        "question": "How does CPF Board guard against premeditated early CPF withdrawals?",
        "answer": "There are policy safeguards to ensure givers' retirement adequacy before they can make CPF transfers to their loved ones. In addition, we have put in place a set of mechanisms to detect potential premature withdrawals. When such cases are detected, the CPF transfers will be refunded to the giver's CPF account, instead of being received by the recipient (for closure of CPF account upon leaving Singapore permanently) or the recipient's beneficiaries (for deceased cases) in cash.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-was-the-cash-top-up-to-my-my-loved-one-s-special-or-retirement-account-refunded-or-partially-refunded",
        "question": "Why was the cash top-up to my / my loved one's Special or Retirement Account refunded or partially refunded?",
        "answer": "Your top-up was refunded as you / your loved one had received other inflows at the same time as the cash top-up was made. These inflows had resulted in you / your loved one to meet the current Full Retirement Sum or Enhanced Retirement Sum (for members age 55 or above).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-transfer-my-top-ups-made-to-my-special-account-retirement-account-to-other-cpf-accounts-if-i-need-to-use-them-for-other-purposes-such-as-housing-or-healthcare",
        "question": "Can I transfer my top-ups made to my Special Account/ Retirement Account to other CPF accounts if I need to use them for other purposes such as housing or healthcare?",
        "answer": "No, such cash top-ups and CPF transfers are meant to boost your retirement savings to enable you to receive higher payouts. Hence, they cannot be used for other purposes or transferred to other CPF accounts such as your Ordinary Account or MediSave Account.Consider whether you would require the monies for other purposes (e.g. housing or healthcare expenses) before topping up to your Special Account/ Retirement Account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-made-a-cash-top-up-to-my-spouse-sibling-between-1-january-2024-and-16-february-2024-and-instructed-that-i-did-not-wish-to-claim-tax-relief-with-the-increase-in-income-threshold-from-4-000-to-8-000-how-can-i-amend-my-instruction-to-claim-tax-relief",
        "question": "I made a cash top-up to my spouse/sibling between 1 January 2024 and 16 February 2024 and instructed that I did not wish to claim tax relief. With the increase in income threshold from $4,000 to $8,000, how can I amend my instruction to claim tax relief?",
        "answer": "You cansubmit an applicationto amend your instructions to claim tax relief for top-ups made in 2024, if your recipient’s income in 2023 is between $4,000 and $8,000 (inclusive).If you indicated that you have a GIRO arrangement to make regular top-ups to your spouse or sibling in the application, your instructions for the GIRO arrangement will also be amended to claim tax relief for future GIRO top-ups.Please note thatother conditions to qualify for tax relief apply.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-set-up-a-giro-arrangement-to-make-top-ups-to-my-spouse-or-sibling-before-16-february-2024-with-the-increase-in-income-threshold-from-4-000-to-8-000-how-can-i-amend-my-instructions-for-the-giro-arrangement-to-claim-tax-relief",
        "question": "I have set up a GIRO arrangement to make top-ups to my spouse or sibling before 16 February 2024. With the increase in income threshold from $4,000 to $8,000, how can I amend my instructions for the GIRO arrangement to claim tax relief?",
        "answer": "The increase in income threshold for tax relief for cash top-ups to spouse or sibling will apply to cash top-ups made on 1 January 2024 or after. If you have a GIRO arrangement to make regular cash top-ups to your spouse or sibling and instructed to not claim tax relief previously, you cansubmit an applicationto amend your instructions to claim tax relief for top-ups from 2024 onwards.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-cannot-remember-if-i-had-instructed-that-i-want-don-t-want-to-claim-tax-relief-for-my-cash-top-ups-to-my-spouse-or-sibling-in-my-application-how-can-i-check",
        "question": "I cannot remember if I had instructed that I want/ don't want to claim tax relief for my cash top-ups to my spouse or sibling in my application. How can I check?",
        "answer": "You may check your past top-up applications by logging in to the CPF website and checking under “my cpf” > “Activities”.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-change-to-the-enhanced-retirement-sum-in-2025",
        "question": "What is the change to the Enhanced Retirement Sum in 2025?",
        "answer": "TheEnhanced Retirement Sum (ERS)was raised on 1 January 2025 from three times to four times of the Basic Retirement Sum (BRS). This provides CPF members aged 55 and above the option to voluntarily top up more to their Retirement Account (RA) for even higher monthly payouts in retirement.The ERS in 2025 is $426,000. This allows members to get higher CPF LIFE monthly payouts of up to $3,300 for life from age 65 through CPF top-ups.Learn more about the payouts you can receive.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-cpf-monthly-payout-can-i-receive-if-i-top-up-to-the-raised-enhanced-retirement-sum-in-2025",
        "question": "How much CPF monthly payout can I receive if I top up to the raised Enhanced Retirement Sum in 2025?",
        "answer": "It depends on several factors, including the age when one sets aside the Enhanced Retirement Sum (ERS) and when one starts payouts.The ERS in 2025 is $426,000.Illustrations on estimated monthly payouts for members who top up to ERS in 2025:Members who top up on reaching age 55 in 2025 can receive CPF LIFE monthly payouts of $3,100 – $3,300 for life from age 65.Members turning 65 in 2025 who had previously set aside their cohort Full Retirement Sum at age 55 can receive CPF LIFE monthly payouts of $2,500 – $2,700.You can use theMonthly payout estimatorto estimate your payouts if you top up to the raised ERS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-check-the-amount-that-i-can-top-up-to-my-retirement-account-to-reach-the-raised-enhanced-retirement-sum-in-2025",
        "question": "How can I check the amount that I can top up to my Retirement Account to reach the raised Enhanced Retirement Sum in 2025?",
        "answer": "You may check your top-up limit on yourRetirement Dashboardon 1 January 2025 once the Enhanced Retirement Sum is raised.Find outhow the top-up limit is computed.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/does-the-raising-of-the-enhanced-retirement-sum-ers-affect-my-basic-retirement-sum-brs-and-full-retirement-sum-frs",
        "question": "Does the raising of the Enhanced Retirement Sum (ERS) affect my Basic Retirement Sum (BRS) and Full Retirement Sum (FRS)?",
        "answer": "No, this will not affect yourBasic Retirement Sum (BRS) and Full Retirement Sum (FRS), which are determined when you turn age 55 and will remain the same for the rest of your life.If you are aged 55 and above, you can opt to top up more to your Retirement Account (RA), beyond your FRS, to receive higher monthly payouts in retirement. The maximum amount you can top up to your RA is the current year’sEnhanced Retirement Sum (ERS). With the raising of the ERS on 1 January 2025 from three times to 4 times of BRS, you will be able to top up more for even higher payouts.Find out more on how the BRS and FRS are determined.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-plan-to-top-up-my-retirement-account-to-the-raised-enhanced-retirement-sum-when-can-i-make-the-top-up",
        "question": "I plan to top up my Retirement Account to the raised Enhanced Retirement Sum. When can I make the top-up?",
        "answer": "You can make your top-up anytime from 1 January 2025 onwards, once the Enhanced Retirement Sum is raised.Find outhow you can check the amount that you can top up.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/with-the-closure-of-the-special-account-and-the-raising-of-the-enhanced-retirement-sum-how-much-is-the-maximum-amount-that-i-can-have-in-my-retirement-account",
        "question": "With the closure of the Special Account and the raising of the Enhanced Retirement Sum, how much is the maximum amount that I can have in my Retirement Account?",
        "answer": "From 1 January 2025, the Enhanced Retirement Sum (ERS) was raised to four times of the Basic Retirement Sum to allow members 55 and above to save more in the Retirement Account (RA) andreceive higher payouts, if they wish to do so.With the change, the ERS in 2025 is $426,0001, up from $308,700 in 2024. Hence, if you are aged 55 and above in 2025, you can save up to $426,000 in the RA. This allows members to get higher CPF LIFE monthly payouts of up to $3,300 for life from age 65 through CPF top-ups.Learn more about the payouts you can receive.As the ERS increases every January, you can make further top-ups every year for even higher payouts.1This is the limit for the savings set aside in the RA (excluding amounts such as interest earned, any government grants received, plus retirement withdrawals).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-does-the-closure-of-my-special-account-affect-the-amount-of-tax-relief-that-i-can-earn-when-i-top-up-my-retirement-account-in-cash",
        "question": "How does the closure of my Special Account affect the amount of tax relief that I can earn when I top up my Retirement Account in cash?",
        "answer": "Cash top-ups to your Retirement Account (RA) up to the current year’sFull Retirement Sum (FRS)can qualify for tax relief of up to $8,000 per year. This will continue even after your Special Account (SA) is closed.For information, when members turn 55, their savings in their SA and Ordinary Account (OA) are transferred to their RA, up to their applicable FRS. The applicable FRS is the FRS in year they turn 55 and remains fixed for them thereafter, even when the FRS increases each year. Hence, members who have met their applicable FRS may still qualify for tax relief on their top-ups as the current year’s FRS may be higher than their applicable FRS.Illustration:Mr Lim turns 55 in 2024. His applicable FRS is $205,800. Assume he has $200,000 transferred from his SA and OA to his RA when he turns 55. He decides to make a cash top-up of $5,800 to his RA to meet his FRS in 2024. He can qualify for tax relief for his $5,800 top-up.In 2025, Mr Lim’s SA will be closed and his SA savings will be transferred to his OA since he has met his applicable FRS. However, as the FRS for 2025 is $213,000, he can get a tax relief of up to $7,200 (i.e. $213,000 - $205,800) if he makes additional cash top-ups to his RA.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/with-the-closure-of-my-special-account-can-i-have-the-option-to-top-up-more-than-the-raised-enhanced-retirement-sum-ers",
        "question": "With the closure of my Special Account, can I have the option to top up more than the raised Enhanced Retirement Sum (ERS)?",
        "answer": "You are not able to top up more than the current year’sEnhanced Retirement Scheme (ERS)as the CPF system is designed to cater to the basic retirement needs of the broad majority of Singaporeans.With the raising of the ERS on 1 January 2025 from three times to four times of the Basic Retirement Sum (BRS) (that is $426,000 in 2025), more than 99% of CPF members aged 55 or above will be able to transfer all their Special Account savings to their Retirement Account to continue to earn the higher long-term interest rate and receive higher payouts, should they wish to do so.You may consider transferring the savings in excess of the raised ERS to your loved ones’ CPF accounts, keep them in your OA to continue to earn 2.5% interest each year while retaining the flexibility to withdraw anytime. Alternatively, you can invest them under the CPF Investment Scheme – Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA), if you have assessed that CPFIS is suitable for you.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-age-55-and-above-how-will-the-closure-of-special-account-sa-affect-my-eligibility-to-voluntarily-transfer-my-cpf-savings-to-top-up-my-own-loved-ones-retirement-savings",
        "question": "I am age 55 and above. How will the closure of Special Account (SA) affect my eligibility to voluntarily transfer my CPF savings to top up my own/loved ones' retirement savings?",
        "answer": "There are no changes to the eligibility rules on the transfer of CPF savings to top up your own/loved ones' retirement savings.When your Special Account is closed, your withdrawable SA savings (if any) will be transferred to your Ordinary Account (OA), and your available CPF savings for such top-ups will increase accordingly. You can check these amounts available for such top-ups via the Retirement Dashboard, after we complete the closure of your SA in the second half of January 2025.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme",
        "question": "What is the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?",
        "answer": "The Matched Retirement Savings Scheme aims to help senior Singapore Citizens with lower retirement savings save more and boost their retirement payouts.Eligible memberswill receive a matching grant for every dollar of cash top-ups received in their Retirement Account, up to $2,000 per year from 1 Jan 2025 (increased from $600). Matching grant is capped at $20,000 over an eligible members’ lifetime.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-benefits-of-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme",
        "question": "What are the benefits of the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?",
        "answer": "Under the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme, you will enjoy:Dollar-for-dollar matching grant for cash top-ups received, up to $2,000 per year and $20,000 in your lifetimeStable interest rates* up to 6% per annum on your cash top-upsCash top-ups and the matching grant will allow you to enjoy higher monthly payouts in retirementYour cash top-up made monthly for the year (12 months)Matching grant from the Government (next year)Increase in your retirement savings$50 / month$600 / year$1,200$88 / month$1,056 / year$2,112$168 / month$2,000 (Maximum) / year$4,016*Based on the current 4% interest rate floor on Retirement Account monies.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-does-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-work",
        "question": "How does the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme work?",
        "answer": "We will assess youreligibilityfor the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) annually and will notify you via email or post at the beginning of the year if you are eligible. You can also check your eligiblity via theMRSS eligiblity checkerandRetirement Dashboard.If you are eligible and have received cash top-ups by 31 Dec of the year, you will receive a matching grant in your Retirement Account at the beginning of the following year. You can top up any amount using PayNow or GIRO. Top-ups can be made by anyone, including yourself or your loved ones.Learn more on how to make a cash top-uphere.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-can-make-cash-top-ups-to-recipients-who-are-eligible-for-matched-retirement-savings-scheme",
        "question": "Who can make cash top-ups to recipients who are eligible for Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?",
        "answer": "Anyone, including yourself,loved ones, employers or members of the community, can help members who are eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme to receive the matching grant by making cash top-ups to their Retirement Account.Learn more on how to make a cash top-uphere.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-received-an-email-notification-on-topping-up-my-and-or-my-loved-ones-retirement-savings-how-do-i-know-if-the-notification-is-indeed-sent-by-cpf-board",
        "question": "I received an email notification on topping up my and/or my loved ones’ retirement savings. How do I know if the notification is indeed sent by CPF Board?",
        "answer": "Members will receive email notifications at the email address registered with the Board. You maycheck or update your email addresswhich you have earlier registered with us using your Singpass.To verify if the email you received is legitimate andavoid falling prey to phishing scams,Ensure that the sender's email address is correctly spelt and ends with \"@e.cpf.gov.sg\".Ensure that the hyperlinks or links you click on has a domain ending with “.gov.sg”.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-the-increase-in-the-annual-matching-grant-from-600-to-2-000-per-year-from-2025-help-seniors-better-meet-their-retirement-needs",
        "question": "How will the increase in the annual matching grant from $600 to $2,000 per year from 2025 help seniors better meet their retirement needs?",
        "answer": "Eligible seniors can top up more to their CPF retirement savings and receive the higher matching grant amount. Correspondingly, they will also receive higher monthly CPF payouts. For instance, a senior aged 55 in 2025 who makes a cash top-up of $2,000 per year over the next 10 years will see an increase in CPF retirement savings of at least $48,000 (inclusive of matching grants and CPF interest) in 2035, which translates to about a $260 increase in monthly CPF payouts*.*Estimation for a male member that starts payout at age 65 on the CPF LIFE Standard Plan.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-additional-resources-are-available-to-help-me-better-understand-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-mrss",
        "question": "What additional resources are available to help me better understand the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS)?",
        "answer": "You may refer to the table below for an infographic (available in English, Chinese, Malay and Tamil) and a video (with audio) which elaborate on the benefits of MRSS.To access these resources, you can click on the links below:InfographicVideoEnglishEnglishChinese (华文)Chinese (华文)Malay (Bahasa Melayu)Malay (Bahasa Melayu)Tamil (தமிழ்)Tamil (தமிழ்)",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-there-a-lifetime-cap-of-20-000-to-the-matching-grant-when-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-is-enhanced-from-2025",
        "question": "Why is there a lifetime cap of $20,000 to the matching grant when the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme is enhanced from 2025?",
        "answer": "The Matched Retirement Savings Scheme is targeted at seniors with lesser means and lower retirement savings to help them save more for retirement. The enhancements to provide $2,000 matching grant annually, capped at $20,000 over a lifetime, are a significant increase from the current scheme, and can increase eligible seniors’ CPF savings by at least $48,000 in 10 years, which translates to about a $260 increase in monthly CPF payouts*.While it may not help all eligible seniors meet the Basic Retirement Sum, it is part of a broader set of schemes providing retirement adequacy support. Other schemes, such as the Majulah Package and the Silver Support Scheme, will also help boost the retirement adequacy of seniors.*Estimation for a male member who starts payout at age 65 on the CPF LIFE Standard Plan.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-is-eligible-for-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme",
        "question": "Who is eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?",
        "answer": "You will be eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) for the year if you are aSingapore Citizenand meet the following criteria.​Age55 or above as of 31stDecember of the year​Retirement Account (RA) Savings*#​Less than $106,500^.​Average Monthly Income#​Not more than $4,000.This covers majority of senior workers.​Annual Value of Residence#​Not more than $21,000.​Property Ownership#​Own not more than one property.* RA savings refer to the cash set aside in the RA (excluding amounts such as interest earned, any governments grants received), plus retirement withdrawals. If you are turning 55 in the assessment year and your RA has not been created at the time we assess your eligibility, your total Special Account and Ordinary Account savings will be used for the eligiblity assessment instead.^ Basic Retirement Sum for 2025.# We assess the eligiblity based on the previous year's data because these are the latest data available.Find outhow you can check your eligibility for the MRSS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-check-if-i-am-eligible-for-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme",
        "question": "How do I check if I am eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?",
        "answer": "You can check your eligibility for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) via theMRSS eligibility checker(no Singpass login required) andRetirement Dashboard.To view more details on the grant amount that you will receive in the beginning of the next year, you may log in to your Retirement Dashboard.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-will-my-eligibility-for-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-be-assessed-and-do-i-need-to-apply",
        "question": "When will my eligibility for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme be assessed and do I need to apply?",
        "answer": "We will assess youreligibilityfor the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) annually at the beginning of the year. You do not need to apply.If you are eligible, we will notify you via email or post. You can also check your eligibility through theMRSS eligibility checker(no Singpass login required) andRetirement Dashboard.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-am-i-not-eligible-for-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-if-my-retirement-savings-are-above-the-current-basic-retirement-sum",
        "question": "Why am I not eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme if my retirement savings are above the current Basic Retirement Sum?",
        "answer": "The Matched Retirement Savings Scheme is designed to help senior Singapore Citizens with lower retirement savings save more and boost their retirement payouts. If your retirement savings are more than the current Basic Retirement Sum, you will not be eligible for the scheme as it is intended to provide additional support to those who need it the most.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-i-be-eligible-for-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-if-i-am-turning-55-later-this-year",
        "question": "Will I be eligible for Matched Retirement Savings Scheme if I am turning 55 later this year?",
        "answer": "Yes, you will be eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme as long as you are 55 years old in the assessment year and meet theeligibility criteria.If you are turning 55 this year and your Retirement Account has not been created at the time we assess your eligibility, your total Special Account and Ordinary Account savings will be used for the eligibility assessment instead.You can check your eligibility for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) via theMRSS eligiblity checker(no Singpass required) andRetirement Dashboard.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-am-eligible-for-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-this-year-will-i-be-automatically-eligible-in-the-following-years",
        "question": "If I am eligible for Matched Retirement Savings Scheme this year, will I be automatically eligible in the following years?",
        "answer": "No, your eligibility for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme is assessed annually. We will notify you at the beginning of the year if you are eligible.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-eligible-for-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-this-year-will-i-still-be-eligible-if-there-are-changes-to-my-circumstance-during-the-year",
        "question": "I am eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme this year. Will I still be eligible if there are changes to my circumstance during the year?",
        "answer": "Yes, you will still be eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) for the year even if your circumstances change (e.g. increase in monthly income) during the year. Your eligibility for MRSS will be assessed next year based on your new circumstances.However, do note that renouncing your Singapore citizenship during the year will make you ineligible for the scheme and matching grant.Find out about theconditions which you need to meetto receive and keep the matching grant.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-am-i-not-eligible-for-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-if-my-average-monthly-income-is-above-4-000",
        "question": "Why am I not eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme if my monthly income is above $4,000.",
        "answer": "The Matched Retirement Savings Scheme is designed to help senior Singapore Citizens with lower retirement savings save more and boost their retirement payouts. The average monthly income of $4,000 will cover most senior workers. If your average monthly income is above $4,000, you will not be eligible for the scheme as it is intended to provide additional support to those who need it the most.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-was-ineligible-for-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-for-the-past-few-years-after-turning-71-years-old-with-the-lifting-of-the-age-cap-of-70-from-2025-will-my-eligibility-be-revised-for-the-past-few-years",
        "question": "I was ineligible for Matched Retirement Savings Scheme for the past few years after turning 71 years old. With the lifting of the age cap of 70 from 2025, will my eligibility be revised for the past few years?",
        "answer": "No, the enhancements start from 2025. With the lifting of the age cap, eligible seniors above 70 can make cash top-ups and receive the same amount of Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) matching grant as those aged 55 to 70. The Government has also increased the annual matching grant amount to $2,000, compared to $600 before.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-am-i-not-eligible-for-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-if-i-am-below-55-years-old",
        "question": "Why am I not eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme if I am below 55 years old?",
        "answer": "The Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) helps boost the retirement payouts of older Singaporean Citizens aged 55 and above with lower retirement savings, who have a shorter runway to build up more retirement savings. MRSS is extended to them to help accumulate retirement savings.For those who are younger and have a longer runway to build their retirement savings, the Government provides various other support. These include the Workfare Income Supplement, which supplements the income and retirement savings of lower-wage workers, and the Retirement Sum Topping-Up scheme (RSTU), which provide tax relief on cash top-ups. These schemes boost retirement savings, allowing members to benefit from compounding interest and higher monthly payouts in retirement.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-do-i-need-to-do-to-receive-the-matching-grant-under-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme",
        "question": "What do I need to do to receive the matching grant under the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?",
        "answer": "To receive the matching grant, simply make your cash top up by 31 Dec of the year of eligibility.You can top up any amount using PayNow. For greater convenience, consider setting a GIRO arrangement to make small and regular top-ups. Top-ups can be made by anyone, including yourself or your loved ones.Your cash top-up made monthly for the year (12 months)Matching grant from the Government (next year)Increase in your retirement savings$50 / month$600 / year$1,200$88 / month$1,056 / year$2,112$168 / month$2,000 (Maximum) / year$4,016The matching grant will be credited to your RA in the beginning of next year. Matching grant is subjected to a lifetime limit of $20,000. Top-ups that attract MRSS matching grant will not qualify for tax relief.Learn more on how to make a cash top-uphere.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-make-a-cash-top-up-to-receive-the-matching-grant-under-matched-retirement-savings-scheme",
        "question": "How do I make a cash top-up to receive the matching grant under Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?",
        "answer": "You can make a cash top-up to yourself or your loved ones’ Retirement Account (RA) via theCPF website or CPF mobile app. Your cash top-up will generally be credited almost instantly upon successful payment.Considermaking regular monthly or yearly cash top-ups conveniently via GIRO, without the hassle of completing the application form every time you top up.You may want to check whether you or your loved ones areeligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Schemebefore making a cash top-up.To make a top-up, you can refer to the following table:Application modePayment viaGuideWebRecurring cash top-upsvia GIROGuideOne-time cash top-upvia PayNow QRGuide(PDF, 0.1MB)Video GuideCPF Mobile appPayNow QROCBC DigitalEnglishChineseMalayTamilCPF transferGuide",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/is-there-a-minimum-amount-i-need-to-top-up-to-be-eligible-for-the-matching-grant",
        "question": "Is there a minimum amount I need to top up to be eligible for the matching grant?",
        "answer": "There is no minimum amount of cash top-up needed to be eligible for the matching grant. However, the more you top up, the more grant you can receive, subject to an annual limit of $2,000 and a lifetime limit of $20,000.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-turning-55-later-this-year-how-can-i-top-up-if-my-retirement-account-has-not-been-created-yet",
        "question": "I am turning 55 later this year. How can I top up if my Retirement Account has not been created yet?",
        "answer": "If your Retirement Account has not been created yet, you can top up to your Special Account (SA). Cash top-ups to your SA will be considered for matching grants under the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-cpf-transfers-not-eligible-for-the-matching-grant-under-matched-retirement-savings-scheme",
        "question": "Why are CPF transfers not eligible for the matching grant under Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?",
        "answer": "The Matched Retirement Savings Scheme is designed to encourage cash top-ups to senior Singapore Citizens with lower retirement savings to help them save more. Thus, only cash top-ups to eligible members will be matched.Members making CPF transfers can still benefit from the higher interest rate in the Retirement Account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-there-an-annual-cap-of-2-000-of-matching-grant-would-the-government-consider-allowing-eligible-members-to-top-up-20-000-at-once-and-receive-the-lifetime-matching-grant-of-20-000",
        "question": "Why is there an annual cap of $2,000 of matching grant. Would the Government consider allowing eligible members to top up $20,000 at once and receive the lifetime matching grant of $20,000?",
        "answer": "The Matched Retirement Savings Scheme is targeted at seniors with lower retirement savings to help them save more for retirement. As member’s circumstances such as income and housing can change over time, the annual cap ensures that the scheme will help seniors who require the support over a longer period.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-tax-relief-removed-for-cash-top-ups-that-attract-matching-grant-under-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-from-2025",
        "question": "Why is tax relief removed for cash top-ups that attract matching grant under the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme from 2025?",
        "answer": "As the cash top-ups serve to boost the retirement adequacy of seniors through the matching grant, tax relief is removed for cash top-ups which attract the matching grant. This is because the matching grant is already a benefit extended by the Government. Givers may continue to enjoy tax relief of up to $16,000 a year for cash top-ups that do not attract the MRSS matching grant, if they meet the criteria under the Retirement Sum Topping-Up Scheme (e.g., if the recipient has not met the current Full Retirement Sum).Learn more onhow the matching grant and tax relief are determined.Find out more on theconditions to qualify for tax relief.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-incentives-are-there-for-me-to-top-up-to-my-loved-ones-under-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-when-the-tax-relief-is-removed-from-2025",
        "question": "What incentives are there for me to top up to my loved ones under the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme when the tax relief is removed from 2025?",
        "answer": "Topping up to your loved ones’ CPF accounts helps them to build up more retirement savings and increases their monthly payouts in retirement. From 1 January 2025, recipients of cash top-ups who are eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) can also receive a matching grant of up to $2,000 per year (an increase from $600 per year) from the Government, which will further boost their retirement savings.You may continue to enjoy tax relief of up to $16,000 a year for eligible cash top-ups that do not attract MRSS matching grants ($8,000 per year for top-ups to yourself and another $8,000 per year for top-ups to your loved ones).Learn more onhow this works.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-missed-the-deadline-to-top-up-for-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-grant-last-year-can-i-make-a-top-up-this-year-for-last-year-s-grant",
        "question": "I missed the deadline to top up for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme grant last year. Can I make a top-up this year for last year's grant?",
        "answer": "No, to qualify for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS) grant, the cash top-up must be made by 31 December in the year of eligibility. This is stated in the eligibility notification sent at the beginning of the year of eligibility, and on the website.You can still make a top-up to earn interest rates* of up to 6% per annum and boost your monthly payouts. You can also enjoy tax relief of up to $16,000 for cash top-ups made to yourself and your loved ones in each calendar year. Please note that cash top-ups which attract MRSS grant will not qualify for tax relief.*Based on the current 4% interest rate floor on Special and Retirement Account monies.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/from-2025-how-are-the-matching-grants-and-tax-relief-determined-for-my-cash-top-ups-made-to-a-senior-eligible-for-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme",
        "question": "From 2025, how are the matching grants and tax relief determined for my cash top-ups made to a senior eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?",
        "answer": "From 1 January 2025, if you are making a cash top-up to a recipient eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme (MRSS), your cash top-up of $2,000 will first enable your recipient to enjoy the matching grant of up to $2,000 per year from the Government, and will thus not be eligible for tax relief. You can continue to enjoy tax relief of up to $16,000 a year for your cash top-ups that do not attract the MRSS matching grant ($8,000 per year for top-ups to yourself and another $8,000 per year for top-ups to your loved ones).For example, if you make a cash top-up of $3,000 to your MRSS-eligible loved one, your loved one will first enjoy a matching grant of $2,000 from the Government, and you will be eligible for $1,000 of tax relief on your cash top-up that did not attract the matching grant.Find out more on theconditions to qualify for tax relief.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-make-the-top-up-by-cash-or-nets-under-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme",
        "question": "Can I make the top-up by cash or NETS under the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?",
        "answer": "No, you can use PayNow or GIRO instead to make a cash top-up to yourself or your loved ones’ Retirement Account (RA).For PayNow, your cash top-up will generally be credited almost instantly upon successful payment.Consider making regular monthly or yearly cash top-ups conveniently via GIRO, without the hassle of completing the application form every time you top up.You may refer to this FAQ“How do I make a cash top-up to receive the matching grant under Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?”for the guide on how to top up.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-change-or-delete-my-recurring-cash-top-up-arrangement-to-receive-the-matching-grant-under-matched-retirement-saving-scheme",
        "question": "How do I change or delete my recurring cash top-up arrangement to receive the matching grant under Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?",
        "answer": "If you want tochangeyour existing recurring cash top-up arrangement such as the amount and frequency, you can follow the steps below:Delete your existing recurring cash top-up arrangement in theManage recurring cash top-ups for retirementform.Create a new recurring arrangement via the sameformwith your revised amount and/or frequency of the top-ups.If you want todeleteyour existing recurring cash top-up arrangement, you can do so via theManage recurring cash top-ups for retirementform. Your application will generally be processed instantly upon submission.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-check-my-existing-recurring-cash-top-up-arrangements-for-the-matched-retirement-savings-scheme",
        "question": "How can I check my existing recurring cash top-up arrangements for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme?",
        "answer": "You can check your existing recurring cash top-up arrangements, including the recipients, amount of cash top-ups, and frequency (monthly or yearly) by accessing theManage recurring cash top-ups for retirementform, under “Who you are making recurring top-ups to”.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-have-to-top-up-in-a-lump-sum-to-be-eligible-for-the-matching-grant",
        "question": "Do I have to top up in a lump sum to be eligible for the matching grant?",
        "answer": "No, you can also make multiple smaller cash top-ups throughout the year. The matching grant is based on the total amount of top-ups you have received in the year, up to $2,000 per year.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-check-if-the-matching-grant-has-been-credited-to-me",
        "question": "How can I check if the matching grant has been credited to me?",
        "answer": "If you had made your cash top up by 31 Dec of the year of eligibility, the matching grant will be credited to your Retirement Account (RA) in the beginning of the next year. To find out if your matching grant has been credited, you can check yourTransaction Historyby logging in with your Singpass, or check your Transaction History in the CPF Mobile app.Please also note that the matching grant is subjected to a lifetime limit of $20,000. Top-ups that attract MRSS matching grant will not qualify for tax relief.The matching grant will be credited to your RA in the beginning of the next year.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-withdraw-the-matching-grant",
        "question": "Can I withdraw the matching grant?",
        "answer": "No, the top-up and matching grant are meant to boost your retirement savings for higher monthly payouts, hence they cannot be withdrawn in a lump sum. They will be paid out to you as part of your monthly payouts in retirement.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-if-i-pass-away-before-receiving-the-matching-grant",
        "question": "What if I pass away before receiving the matching grant?",
        "answer": "If you pass away, your matching grant will still be credited to your CPF account and paid out to yourbeneficiariestogether with any remaining CPF savings.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-i-still-receive-the-full-matching-grant-of-2000-if-my-retirement-savings-exceed-the-current-basic-retirement-sum-after-topping-up",
        "question": "Will I still receive the full matching grant of $2,000 if my retirement savings exceed the current Basic Retirement Sum after topping up?",
        "answer": "Yes, you will receive the full matching grant of $2,000 as long as you are eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme for the year, and the total amount of cash top-ups you received was at least $2,000.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-will-i-receive-the-matching-grant",
        "question": "When will I receive the matching grant?",
        "answer": "If you are eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme and have received cash top-ups in that year, you can expect to receive the matching grant in your Retirement Account at the beginning of the following year.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-conditions-must-i-meet-in-order-to-receive-and-retain-the-matching-grant",
        "question": "What conditions must I meet in order to receive and retain the matching grant?",
        "answer": "To receive and retain the matching grant, you must:be eligible for the Matched Retirement Savings Scheme for the year;have received cash top-ups during the year; andstill be a Singapore Citizen when the matching grant is credited to your Retirement Account (RA) at the beginning of the following year.Do note that cash top-ups are irreversible. Read more about theirreversibilitycondition.In an unlikely event where the cash top-up is reversed and you had already received the matching grant, the grant and any interest earned on it will be recovered from your CPF account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-received-matched-retirement-savings-scheme-matching-grants-in-the-past-before-the-20-000-lifetime-cap-took-effect-in-2025-will-the-past-matching-grants-count-towards-this-20-000-lifetime-cap",
        "question": "I received Matched Retirement Savings Scheme matching grants in the past, before the $20,000 lifetime cap took effect in 2025. Will the past matching grants count towards this $20,000 lifetime cap?",
        "answer": "The lifetime cap will only be applied from 2025 onwards. Matching grants received in the past for cash top-ups made prior to 2025, will not count towards the $20,000 lifetime cap.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-check-the-amount-of-matching-grant-that-i-will-receive",
        "question": "How do I check the amount of matching grant that I will receive?",
        "answer": "To find out the grant amount that you will receive in the beginning of the next year on the cash top-ups which you had received, you can log in to yourRetirement Dashboard.In addition, the Dashboard will provide you with the remaining grant amount, if any, which you can receive if you make further top-ups.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-voluntary-top-up-limit-to-my-three-cpf-accounts",
        "question": "What is the voluntary top-up limit to my three CPF accounts?",
        "answer": "The maximum amount you can voluntarily top up is the difference between the CPF Annual Limit of $37,740 and the mandatory CPF contributions made for the calendar year.Do remember to consider your mandatory CPF contributions which you will be receiving for the calendar year, before making voluntary top-ups. If the total mandatory CPF contributions and voluntary top-ups exceed the CPF Annual Limit in the calendar year, any excess voluntary top-ups will be refunded without interest in the following year.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-check-my-voluntary-top-up-limit-to-my-cpf-accounts",
        "question": "How do I check my voluntary top-up limit to my CPF accounts?",
        "answer": "When you make a cash top-up online, you will be shown the amount of top-up you can receive before you reach the top-up limit.You can follow these steps to check how much you can top up to your CPF accounts:Go to theTop up CPF accounts formLog in with your SingpassSelect “I wish to make a top-up to Myself” under “Recipient details”Your top-up limit will then be displayed.If the total mandatory CPF contributions and voluntary top-ups exceed the CPF Annual Limit in the calendar year, the excess voluntary top-ups will be refunded without interest the following year. Therefore, do remember to consider your mandatory CPF contributions which you will be receiving for the calendar year, before making voluntary top-ups.If you are making a top-up on another person’s behalf, please check with your recipient directly on the amount he can receive.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/is-my-voluntary-top-up-to-the-3-cpf-accounts-reversible",
        "question": "Is my voluntary top-up to the 3 CPF accounts  reversible?",
        "answer": "Voluntary top-ups made are irreversible.However, if the total mandatory CPF contributions and voluntary top-ups exceed the CPF Annual Limit in the calendar year, any excess voluntary top-ups will be refunded without interest. Therefore, do remember to consider your mandatory CPF contributions which you will be receiving for the calendar year, before making voluntary top-ups.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-top-up-to-myself-my-children-or-my-loved-ones-cpf-accounts",
        "question": "How can I top up to myself, my children or my loved ones' CPF accounts?",
        "answer": "You can make a top up viaTop up CPF accountsusing PayNow QR1.You will be prompted to key in your Recipient's NRIC/CPF Account Number if you are making a top-up on another person’s behalf.All applications and payments should reach CPF Board by the last day of the calendar year for it to be counted as the year’s CPF Annual Limit. Backdating of top-ups to previous years is not allowed.Tax relief is only applicable to self-employed persons, based on their assessable net trade income for the year of assessment.Find out more about tax relief for self-employed persons.You can find out more on whichvoluntary top-upis applicable to you.To make cash top-ups to yourself or a loved one on another person’s behalf, you are required to be up-to-date with your MediSave payable (paid in full or on an active GIRO plan) under theSelf-Employed Scheme. You may make payment for your MediSave payable via thepayment modes.Self-employed persons who meet theeligibility criteriawill continue to enjoy self-employed tax relief. However, the contributions allocated to your MediSave account will no longer be used to offset your MediSave payable (if any).1Subsequent or duplicate payments made using the same PayNow QR code will be refunded. To ensure that your cash top-ups are processed successfully, please only scan the PayNow QR code and make payment once. You will need to submit a new application each time you wish to make another top-up.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-there-a-limit-set-for-my-top-up-to-cpf-accounts",
        "question": "Why is there a limit set for my top-up to CPF accounts?",
        "answer": "There is a limit set as the CPF system is generally meant to cater to the needs of up to 80thpercentile of workers in Singapore. Higher income earners would have other means to supplement their retirement income.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-long-does-it-take-to-process-voluntary-top-ups-applications-to-my-cpf-accounts",
        "question": "How long does it take to process voluntary top-ups applications to my CPF accounts?",
        "answer": "The application relating to voluntary top-ups to CPF accounts will be processed as stated in the table below.ServiceProcessing TimeTop up CPF accountsAlmost immediatelyIf the top-up amount is not reflected in your CPF accounts, please check your CPF account balance after five working days as more time may be needed to process the transaction. Such cases may arise due to intermittent network connectivity issues beyond CPF Board's control.Please alert us immediately if your payment is still not updated in your CPF account balance after five working days.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-voluntarily-top-up-to-my-ordinary-account-only",
        "question": "Can I voluntarily top-up to my Ordinary Account only?",
        "answer": "Voluntary top-ups cannot be made solely to the Ordinary Account.You can make voluntary top-ups to:Special / Retirement Account only under theRetirement Sum Topping Up Scheme (RSTU)(tax relief available).MediSave Account only (tax relief available)CPF accountsVoluntary top-up is applicable to Singapore Citizens and Permanent Residents only.You canfind outmore on which voluntary top-up is applicable to you.To make a top up to MediSave Account and/or CPF accounts, you are required to be up-to-date with your MediSave payable (paid in full or on an active GIRO plan) under theSelf-Employed Scheme. You may make payment for your MediSave payable via thepayment modes.Tax relief is only applicable to self-employed persons, based on their assessable net trade income for the year of assessment.Find out more about tax relief for self-employed persons.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-the-excess-voluntary-top-ups-only-refunded-in-the-following-year",
        "question": "Why are the excess voluntary top-ups only refunded in the following year?",
        "answer": "The CPF Annual Limit (AL) consists of both the Mandatory Contribution (MC) from your employer and Voluntary Contributions (VC) paid by you, if any. You are allowed to top up VC up to the CPF Annual Limit (AL) of the year.As the MC for December can be paid by January of the following year, any excess VC top-ups made for the preceding year can only be finalized and refunded in the following year.If your mandatory and voluntary CPF contributions have exceeded the CPF Annual Limit during the year, you canwrite to usto request for refund of the excess voluntary top-ups.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-the-excess-voluntary-top-ups-refunded-with-no-interest",
        "question": "Why are the excess voluntary top-ups refunded with no interest?",
        "answer": "The excess voluntary top-ups can only be determined after all your mandatory contributions have been received for the year. This is usually after the month of January in the following year. The interest on the excess voluntary top-ups which should not be earned by the member will be returned to the Board.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-check-the-status-of-my-top-up-application",
        "question": "How can I check the status of my top-up application?",
        "answer": "You may login to your CPF account and check the status of your online application under “Activities”. If your top-up application is successful, it will be reflected in your CPF accounts.If you have made multiple top-up applications, do check the status of all your applications to see which transactions have been successfully processed and make a new application if necessary.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/my-top-up-via-paynow-qr-is-not-reflected-in-my-cpf-account-why-is-my-cpf-account-balance-s-not-updated-immediately",
        "question": "My top-up  via PayNow QR is not reflected in my CPF account. Why is my CPF account balance(s) not updated immediately?",
        "answer": "Your top-up via PayNow QR will generally be processed immediately upon successful deduction from your bank account.If your top-up is not reflected in your CPF accounts, please check your CPF account balance after five working days as more time may be needed to process the transaction. Such cases may arise due to intermittent network connectivity issues beyond CPF Board's control.Please alert us immediately if your payment is still not updated in your CPF account balance after five working days.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-outstanding-medisave-payable-why-am-i-not-able-to-make-voluntary-top-ups-to-my-cpf-accounts-or-on-another-persons-behalf",
        "question": "I have outstanding MediSave payable. Why am I not able to make voluntary top-ups to my CPF accounts or on another person's behalf?",
        "answer": "As a self-employed person, you are required to be up-to-date with your MediSave payable (paid in full or on an active GIRO plan) when making top ups to your CPF accounts or on another person’s behalf.You can conveniently request for an instalment plan or make full payment for your MediSave payable via theManage your MediSave payableform. You will be able to make voluntary top-ups when you are up-to-date with your MediSave payable.Conversely, you will be able to receive voluntary top-ups from your loved ones if they are up-to-date with their MediSave payable (if applicable).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-voluntary-top-up-limit-to-my-medisave-account",
        "question": "What is the voluntary top-up limit to my MediSave Account?",
        "answer": "The maximum amount you can voluntarily top up to your MediSave Account is the difference between yourBasic Healthcare Sum (BHS)and your current MediSave balance. Once your BHS has been reached, no further voluntary top-ups can be made to your MediSave Account. If you exceed your BHS from the top-up, the full amount of your top-up will be refunded to you.You can check your top-up limitwith these steps.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/is-my-voluntary-top-up-to-the-medisave-account-reversible",
        "question": "Is my voluntary top-up to the MediSave Account reversible?",
        "answer": "Voluntary top-ups made are irreversible.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-top-up-to-myself-my-children-or-my-loved-ones-medisave-account",
        "question": "How can I top up to myself, my children or my loved ones' MediSave Account?",
        "answer": "You can make a top-up viaTop up MediSave Accountusing PayNow QR1.You will be prompted to key in your Recipient’s NRIC/CPF Account Number if you are making a top-up to your loved ones.You are encouraged to make top-ups early. All applications and payments should reach CPF Board by the last day of the calendar year to enjoy tax relief for the following year’s Tax Assessment.Backdating of top-ups to previous years is not allowed.Please note that there is no tax relief for top-ups made to your children. Find out more abouttax relieffor your MediSave top-ups.You can find out more on whichvoluntary top-upis applicable to you.To make MediSave top-ups to yourself or a loved one, you are required to be up-to-date with your MediSave payable (paid in full or on an active GIRO plan) under theSelf-Employed Scheme. You may make payment for your MediSave payable via thepayment modes.1Subsequent or duplicate payments made using the same PayNow QRcode will be refunded. To ensure that your cash top-ups are processed successfully, please only scan the PayNow QR code and make payment once.  You will need to submit a new application each time you wish to make another top-up.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-get-tax-relief-for-my-voluntary-top-up-to-my-or-my-loved-ones-medisave-account",
        "question": "Do I get tax relief for my voluntary top-up to my or my loved ones' MediSave Account?",
        "answer": "When you make voluntary cash top-ups to (i) your MediSave Account or (ii) your loved ones, you can enjoy tax relief for cash top-ups made in each calendar year of up to:$ 8,000 if you make a top-up to yourself ; andan additional $ 8,000 if you make a cash top-up to your loved ones *.*Loved ones refer to parents, parents-in-law, grandparents, grandparents-in-law, spouse and siblings.To qualify for tax relief for cash top-ups made to spouse/siblings, the recipient must (i) not have an annual income exceeding $8,0001in the year preceding the year of cash top-up (e.g. salary, tax exempt income such as bank interest, dividends and pension), or (ii) be handicapped.Please note the above tax relief cap applies to both voluntary cash top-ups to MediSave Account and Special/Retirement Account. You can find out more on theconditions to qualify for tax relief.1The income threshold for tax relief for cash top-ups to spouse or sibling has increased from $4,000 to $8,000 and will apply to cash top-ups made on 1 January 2024 or after.If you made a cash top-up to your spouse and/or sibling between 1 January 2024 and 16 February 2024 and wish to claim tax relief for the top-up made due to the increase in income threshold, you maysubmit an application to update your tax relief records for top-ups made in 2024.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-there-no-tax-relief-for-top-ups-to-the-medisave-account-made-to-my-children-or-non-immediate-family",
        "question": "Why is there no tax relief for top-ups to the MediSave Account made to my children or non-immediate family?",
        "answer": "Tax relief is an incentive given to encourage members to build up their healthcare savings for themselves or their immediate family members, particularly older Singaporeans who may have less healthcare savings.However, your children have longer remaining working lifespans and would have more time to build up their healthcare savings for their own healthcare needs. Hence, there is no tax relief for top-ups made to your children or non-immediate family members.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-voluntarily-top-up-to-my-ordinary-account-only",
        "question": "Can I voluntarily top-up to my Ordinary Account only?",
        "answer": "Voluntary top-ups cannot be made solely to the Ordinary Account.You can make voluntary top-ups to:Special / Retirement Account only under theRetirement Sum Topping Up Scheme (RSTU)(tax relief available).MediSave Account only (tax relief available)CPF accountsVoluntary top-up is applicable to Singapore Citizens and Permanent Residents only.You canfind outmore on which voluntary top-up is applicable to you.To make a top up to MediSave Account and/or CPF accounts, you are required to be up-to-date with your MediSave payable (paid in full or on an active GIRO plan) under theSelf-Employed Scheme. You may make payment for your MediSave payable via thepayment modes.Tax relief is only applicable to self-employed persons, based on their assessable net trade income for the year of assessment.Find out more about tax relief for self-employed persons.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-long-does-it-take-to-process-voluntary-top-ups-application-to-my-medisave-account",
        "question": "How long does it take to process voluntary top-ups application to my MediSave Account?",
        "answer": "The application relating to voluntary top-ups to MediSave Account will be processed as stated in the table below.ServiceProcessing TimeTop up MediSave AccountAlmost immediatelyIf the top-up amount is not reflected in your CPF accounts, please check your CPF account balance after five working days as more time may be needed to process the transaction. Such cases may arise due to intermittent network connectivity issues beyond CPF Board's control.Please alert us immediately if your payment is still not updated in your CPF account balance after five working days.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-check-the-status-of-my-top-up-application",
        "question": "How can I check the status of my top-up application?",
        "answer": "You may login to your CPF account and check the status of your online application under “Activities”. If your top-up application is successful, it will be reflected in your CPF accounts.If you have made multiple top-up applications, do check the status of all your applications to see which transactions have been successfully processed and make a new application if necessary.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/my-top-up-via-paynow-qr-is-not-reflected-in-my-cpf-account-why-is-my-cpf-account-balance-s-not-updated-immediately",
        "question": "My top-up  via PayNow QR is not reflected in my CPF account. Why is my CPF account balance(s) not updated immediately?",
        "answer": "Your top-up via PayNow QR will generally be processed immediately upon successful deduction from your bank account.If your top-up is not reflected in your CPF accounts, please check your CPF account balance after five working days as more time may be needed to process the transaction. Such cases may arise due to intermittent network connectivity issues beyond CPF Board's control.Please alert us immediately if your payment is still not updated in your CPF account balance after five working days.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-differences-between-topping-up-my-retirement-savings-making-a-voluntary-housing-refund-and-topping-up-my-medisave-account",
        "question": "What are the differences between topping up my retirement savings, making a Voluntary Housing Refund and topping up my MediSave Account?",
        "answer": "Find out what the differences between the various types of top-ups are below:Topping up your retirement savingsVoluntary Housing RefundTopping up your MediSave AccountTop up/refund toSpecial Account (SA) for members below 55; orRetirement Account (RA) for members 55 or above.Ordinary Account (OA); and/orRA for members 55 or above and have not met their Full Retirement Sum (FRS) in their RA.MediSave Account (MA)Eligibility for tax reliefYou can enjoy tax relief if you madecash top-ups to yourself or your loved ones up to the current FRS.However, please note that tax relief would not apply if you made a CPF transfer.You will not be eligible for tax relief.For non self-employed persons:You get to enjoytax relieffor voluntary top-ups to MA.If you are self-employed, you will enjoytax reliefon yourMediSave contributionsbased on your annual net trade income (NTI). There will be no tax relief for your MediSave contributions if your assessed NTI for the year of assessment is zero or negative.Top-up limitWhat is the maximum amount of top-ups I can receive?If you are below 55, you may top up your SA up to the current FRS.If you are 55 or above, you may top up your RA up to the current Enhanced Retirement Sum.You can check your top-up limit in yourRetirement Dashboard.Can I voluntarily refund a portion of the CPF savings I used for my property?You can make a refund of any amount, capped at the full principal amount you have withdrawn for the property, along with the accrued interest.You may check the amount that you can refund through theHome Ownership Dashboard.Do note that after making a full voluntary housing refund of the CPF savings withdrawn and accrued interest, all CPF withdrawals including monthly housing loan instalments (if any) for the property will stop.What is the voluntary top-up limit to my MediSave Account?The maximum amount you can voluntarily top up to your MA is the difference between yourBasic Healthcare Sum (BHS)and your current MA balance. Once your BHS has been reached, no further voluntary top-ups can be made to your MA. If you exceed your BHS from the top-up, the full amount of your top-up will be refunded to you.You can check your top-up limitwith these steps.WithdrawalTop-ups are meant to boost your retirement income. They will be streamed out to you as monthly payouts and cannot be used for other purposes.You can continue to use your OA savings for the current or next property after making a voluntary housing refund.However, if you would like to use your OA for the same property, after making a voluntary refund of the full principal amount used and the accrued interest, you will need to re-apply to use your CPF savings.After turning 55 and setting aside the FRS, you can withdraw the remaining balance in your OA and SA in full or in part at any time.From 55, you can make retirement withdrawals from your OA and SA in full or in part, at any time for your immediate needs, provided you have set aside your FRS.MA savings are meant for your healthcare needs and cannot be withdrawn as cash.ApplicationTop-ups can be made using cash and/or CPF transfers.How do I apply to make a top-up?Refund can only be made via cash.How can I make a voluntary refund of the housing amount withdrawn if I am not selling my property?Top-ups can only be made via cash.How can I top up to myself, my children or my loved ones’ MediSave Account?Click thislinkto find out what the CPF interest rates are.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-outstanding-medisave-payable-why-am-i-not-able-to-make-voluntary-top-ups-to-my-or-my-loved-ones-medisave-account",
        "question": "I have outstanding MediSave payable. Why am I not able to make voluntary top-ups to my or my loved ones' MediSave Account?",
        "answer": "As a self-employed person, you are required to be up-to-date with your MediSave payable (paid in full or on an active GIRO plan) when making top ups to your MediSave Account or your loved ones'.You can conveniently request for an instalment plan or make full payment for your MediSave payable via theManage your MediSave payableform. You will be able to make voluntary top-ups when you are up-to-date with your MediSave payable.Conversely, you will be able to receive voluntary top-ups from your loved ones if they are up-to-date with their MediSave payable (if applicable).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-check-my-voluntary-top-up-limit-to-my-medisave-account",
        "question": "How do I check my voluntary top-up limit to my MediSave Account?",
        "answer": "When you make a MediSave top-up online, you will be shown the amount of MediSave top-up you can receive before you reach the top-up limit.You can follow these steps to check how much you can top up to your MediSave Account:Go to theTop up MediSave Account formLog in with your SingpassSelect “I wish to make a top-up to Myself” under “Recipient details”Your top-up limit will then be displayed.If you are making a top-up to your loved ones, please check with your recipient directly on the amount he can receive.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-voluntarily-refund-a-portion-of-the-cpf-savings-i-used-for-my-property",
        "question": "Can I voluntarily refund a portion of the CPF savings I used for my property?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can apply tomake a voluntary housing refundof any amount up to the total CPF principal amount you have withdrawn for the purchase of your property, including the accrued interest. Please refer to the guide below to check for the maximum amount of refund that can be made.Your refund will be used to reduce the principal amount withdrawn for your home, followed by the interest accrued on your withdrawals.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-use-my-cpf-savings-for-the-same-property-after-effecting-a-voluntary-housing-refund-to-my-account",
        "question": "Can I use my CPF savings for the same property after effecting a voluntary housing refund to my account?",
        "answer": "You can use your Ordinary Account savings for the same property after effecting a voluntary housing refund to your account so long as you still have an outstanding loan.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/is-my-voluntary-housing-refund-used-to-set-aside-my-retirement-sum-if-i-am-55-and-above",
        "question": "Is my voluntary housing refund used to set aside my Retirement Sum if I am 55 and above?",
        "answer": "If you are 55 and above and have made a voluntary housing refund, the refunded amount will be used to meet your cohort's Full Retirement Sum (FRS).The FRS helps to meet your retirement needs and ensure that you receive monthly payouts during your retirement. Any refunds that exceed your cohort’s FRS in your Retirement Account will remain in your CPF Ordinary and/or Special accounts.This means that your voluntary housing refund can help meet your retirement needs and provide a steady stream of income during your retirement years.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-have-to-refund-the-housing-grant-to-my-cpf-account-when-i-make-a-voluntary-housing-refund-of-the-monies-withdrawn-for-my-property",
        "question": "Do I have to refund the housing grant to my CPF account when I make a voluntary housing refund of the monies withdrawn for my property?",
        "answer": "When you make a voluntary housing refund, you can refund up to the principal CPF withdrawn towards the property (including the CPF Housing Grant) plus its accrued interest to your CPF account.Generally, the housing grant will be refunded to your Ordinary Account. If you have received more than $30,000 in housing grants, part of the housing grants may be credited to your Special Account/Retirement Account and MediSave Account. Check yourHome ownership dashboardto see the amount that will be credited to your Special/Retirement Account and MediSave Account.These savings that are credited to yourSpecial Account/Retirement Account and MediSave Accountcan then be used for approved purposes under the various CPF approved schemes to help you with your healthcare and retirement needs.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-made-a-voluntary-refund-do-i-still-need-to-refund-to-my-cpf-account-when-i-sell-my-property",
        "question": "I have made a voluntary refund. Do I still need to refund to my CPF account when I sell my property?",
        "answer": "The amount that you have to refund upon selling your property depends on how much you have voluntarily refunded:If you have fully refunded all the CPF savings you have withdrawn for your property with accrued interest, you do not need to make any refundsIf you have partially refunded the CPF savings you have withdrawn for your property with accrued interest, you will need to refund the balance CPF savings you have used with interestWhen a property is sold, the selling price will generally will be used to pay the following in this order:1. Outstanding housing loan2. Required CPF refund3. Other sale expenses, e.g., legal fees;If the selling price (including the option monies) after paying the outstanding housing loan is not enough to make the required CPF refund, you do not need to top up the shortfall in cash as long as the property is sold at market value.However, the option monies (e.g. option fee and option exercise fee) received from your buyer in cash upon the sale of your property are considered part of the selling price and need to be refunded to your co-owner’s and your CPF accounts before the transaction can be completed.The refunded amount will be returned to your co-owner's and your CPF accounts in the following proportions:Amount returned to owner A’s CPF Account:Amount returned to owner B’s CPF Account:",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-view-the-status-of-my-voluntary-housing-refund-application",
        "question": "How can I view the status of my voluntary housing refund application?",
        "answer": "You can check the status of your voluntary housing refund application online viaActivities. Once your application has been successfully processed, the refunded amount will be credited to your CPF account. You can then view the details in your 15-months Transaction History by logging in tomy cpfdigital servicesorCPF Mobile appvia your Singpass. Additionally, you will receive an email notification once your application has been processed.Please note that the amount refunded will be used to reduce the principal amount withdrawn for your property and its accrued interest.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-if-i-make-a-voluntary-housing-refund-when-i-am-55-years-old-and-above",
        "question": "What happens if I make a voluntary housing refund when I am 55 years old and above?",
        "answer": "The refund amount will be transferred to your Retirement Account (RA) to meet your cohort’s Full Retirement Sum (FRS). This transfer will help boost your retirement savings and provide you with a higher monthly payout upon reaching your payout eligibility age.When you turn 55 years old, you can withdraw at least $5,000 or any amount in excess after setting aside your FRS. Check the amount you can withdraw by logging in to yourRetirement dashboard.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-is-my-voluntary-housing-refund-used-to-set-aside-my-retirement-sum-if-i-am-55-years-old-and-above",
        "question": "How is my voluntary housing refund used to set aside my Retirement Sum if I am 55 years old and above?",
        "answer": "The refunded amount will be used to meet your cohort's Full Retirement Sum (FRS) if you’re 55 years old and have not met the FRS. Please refer to the example below on how the voluntary housing refund is used to meet your FRS.ExampleAssumptions:1. You turned 55 years old in 20232. Your cohort’s Full Retirement Sum is $198,8003. You have received less than $30,000 in housing grantsCurrent RA balance$98,800Current OA balance$100,000Principal amount withdrawn for the property and the accrued interest (P+I)$500,000If you make a voluntary housing refund of $200,000New RA balanceThe vHR of $100,000 is used to top up to RA to meet the cohort’s FRS$198,800New OA balanceThe remaining vHR of $100,000 remains in OA after topping up RA to meet FRSThe balance in OA can continued to be used for housing payments$200,000Revised P+IThe vHR of $200,000 is used to reduce the P+I$300,000",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-previously-withdrew-from-my-retirement-account-by-pledging-my-property-what-happens-to-my-pledged-property-after-i-make-a-voluntary-housing-refund",
        "question": "If I previously withdrew from my Retirement Account by pledging my property, what happens to my pledged property after I make a voluntary housing refund?",
        "answer": "You will need to refund the amount you previously pledged if the voluntary housing refund is not enough to meet the Full Retirement Sum in your Retirement Account. Check the amount you need to refund under “What happens if” of yourHome ownership dashboard.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-do-i-need-to-refund-when-i-sell-my-property-after-i-made-a-voluntary-housing-refund",
        "question": "How much do I need to refund when I sell my property after I made a voluntary housing refund?",
        "answer": "On sale of your property, the selling price will be distributed, in the following order:1. Outstanding housing loan2. CPF principal amount withdrawn for the property, and its accrued interest3. Other sale expenses, e.g. legal feesThe amount to refund depends on how much you have voluntarily refunded:Full voluntary housing refund of all your CPF principal withdrawn with accrued interestIf you had made a full voluntary housing refund of all your CPF principal withdrawn with accrued interest and did not use further CPF savings for your loan repayments, you do not need to make any refund to your CPF account on sale of your property.Check yourHome ownership dashboardfor the amount of CPF to be refunded (if any).Partial voluntary housing refund of all your CPF principal withdrawn with accrued interestIf you made a partial voluntary housing refund of your CPF principal withdrawn with accrued interest and/or continued to use further CPF savings for your loan repayments, you need to refund the remaining CPF principal amount withdrawn for your property, including the accrued interest (P+I) onsale of your property.Check yourHome ownership dashboardfor the amount of CPF to be refunded (if any).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-make-a-voluntary-housing-refund-of-the-housing-amount-withdrawn-if-i-am-not-selling-my-property",
        "question": "How can i make a voluntary housing refund of the housing amount withdrawn if i am not selling my property?",
        "answer": "You can refund any amount, capped at the full principal amount you have withdrawn for the property with the accrued interest. You can submit your application:1.Onlineby following the steps below:Read the disclaimer. If you accept, click the checkboxClick \"Start\"Log in with your SingpassSelect a payment methodSelect a property, enter a refund amountClick \"Next\"Read the declaration. If you agree, click the checkbox and click \"Confirm\"Make the payment2. Through CPF Mobile app by following the steps below:Log in to CPF Mobile app with your SingpassSelect \"Services\"Select \"Voluntary Housing Refund\" and click \"Continue\"Select the property, key in a refund amount, and click \"Next\"Read the agreement. If you agree, click the checkboxClick \"Next\"Select the payment methodMake the paymentIf you make the refunds by PayNow using the QR code or OCBC Digital, the transaction will be shown in your transaction history immediately after the payment.Members who are unable to submit online or through the CPF Mobile app may write to us atcpf.gov.sg/writetousfor assistance.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-aged-55-and-above-what-happens-to-my-cpf-investment-scheme-special-account-after-my-special-account-is-closed",
        "question": "I am aged 55 and above. What happens to my CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account after my Special Account is closed?",
        "answer": "If you are aged 55 and above, you can continue to hold your existing CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA) investments until you decide to sell them or until they mature. Upon sale or maturity, your proceeds would be paid to your Retirement Account (RA) up to your Full Retirement Sum (FRS), with any remaining balance paid to your Ordinary Account (OA).Before theclosure of SA, CPF savings in SA can be used to invest after setting aside the FRS in your Retirement Account. With the closure of SA, your SA savings would be transferred to the OA once you have set aside the FRS in your RA and you can use them to invest under CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-currently-holding-investments-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-special-account-cpfis-sa-do-i-need-to-do-anything",
        "question": "I am currently holding investments under the CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA). Do I need to do anything?",
        "answer": "You do not need to take any immediate action. You can continue to hold your existing CPFIS-SA investments until you decide to sell them or until they mature.You can view your SA Portfolio by logging in tomy cpf digital serviceswith your Singpass > Select my cpf > My dashboards > Investment.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/where-will-proceeds-from-my-cpf-investment-scheme-special-account-cpfis-sa-investments-go-to-after-my-special-account-has-been-closed",
        "question": "Where will proceeds from my CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA) investments go to after my Special Account has been closed?",
        "answer": "After yourSpecial Account has been closed, the proceeds from your CPFIS-SA investments will be paid to your Retirement Account up to your Full Retirement Sum, with any remaining balance paid to your Ordinary Account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/my-special-account-sa-will-be-closed-in-the-second-half-of-january-2025-can-i-still-apply-to-use-my-sa-savings-under-cpf-investment-scheme-special-account-from-now-till-before-my-sa-is-closed",
        "question": "My Special Account (SA) will be closed in the second half of January 2025. Can I still apply to use my SA savings under CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account from now till before my SA is closed?",
        "answer": "You can apply to use your Special Account (SA) savings under the CPF Investment Scheme until your SA closes in second half of January 2025. To ensure successful processing, please submit your application at least 14 days before the closure. This allows time for processing, which typically takes five to seven business days, and allows for any necessary follow-ups by the product providers to reduce the risk of failed trades.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "What is the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "The CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) comprises the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) and CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA). The scheme gives CPF members an option to invest their CPF savings, while meeting the long term objective of financial security in their old age.Important Notes:Members are advised to exercise prudence when they invest their CPF savings under the CPFIS. No one can guarantee that investments will always be profitable or that investment products included under CPFIS will always earn a profit. The CPF Board does not specifically endorse any product providers or investment products included under the CPFIS. All investments come with risk and you may lose all or a portion of the amount invested.CPF members have to decide for themselves how to invest their savings and what risks to accept. If members are not confident of investing on their own or do not wish to risk their savings, they can always keep their money with the CPF Board and earn the risk-free interest.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-objective-of-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "What is the objective of CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "The Central Provident Fund (CPF) offers a comprehensive range of schemes and services. The CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) gives you the opportunity to invest your CPF savings in a wide range of investments to enhance your retirement nest egg.Investment objectives and goals differ from person to person. The CPFIS reflects this by making different types of investments available to CPF members. Under the CPFIS, you can invest your CPF savings in shares and loan stocks, unit trusts, government bonds, statutory board bonds, bank deposits, fund management accounts, endowment insurance policies, investment-linked insurance policies, exchange traded funds and gold.However, the CPF Board does not specifically endorse any product providers or investment products included under the CPFIS. All investments come with risk and you may lose all or a portion of the amount invested. If you are not confident of investing on your own, you may consider leaving your money in your CPF accounts, which earns risk-free interest.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-enhancements-relating-to-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-were-announced-during-the-fy2018-committee-of-supply-debate",
        "question": "What enhancements relating to CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) were announced during the FY2018 Committee of Supply Debate?",
        "answer": "Second Minister for Manpower Josephine Teo announced the following enhancements to the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS):Introduction of Self-Awareness Questionnaire (SAQ)(PDF, 0.6MB)Removal of sales charge for products offered under CPFIS(PDF, 0.6MB)Reduction of maximum wrap fee chargeable on CPFIS investments(PDF, 0.5MB)Please refer to ourwebpagefor more details of the enhancements.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-service-standards-for-processing-applications-relating-to-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "What are the service standards for processing applications relating to CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "Please refer to the table for our service standards for processing applications relating to CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS).ServiceNormal Processing TimeWithdraw CPF investmentsWithin 3 working daysUpdate Stock / Gold LimitsWithin 2 working daysTransfer CPFIS Sale Proceeds(Division of CPF-related Matrimonial Assets)Within 15 working days",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/which-digital-advisors-can-give-advice-to-cpfis-members",
        "question": "Which digital advisors can give advice to CPFIS members?",
        "answer": "EndowUs and MoneyOwl are the two digital advisors allowed to give advisory services. However, MoneyOwl ceased its operations in December 2023.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-has-happened-to-moneyowl",
        "question": "What has happened to MoneyOwl?",
        "answer": "MoneyOwl ceased its operations in December 2023 and transferred its business to iFast, which already holds the records of all its clients.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-to-my-investments-made-through-moneyowl",
        "question": "What happens to my investments made through MoneyOwl?",
        "answer": "Your investments made through MoneyOwl will stay with iFast. Even with the transfer of business from MoneyOwl to iFast from 25 Oct 2023, you can access and trade using the iFast platform instead of MoneyOwl. They will be reaching out to you with more information about the transfer.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-risk-return-tradeoff",
        "question": "What is risk-return tradeoff?",
        "answer": "All investments are subject to risk. Risk refers to the possibility that an investment could lose value or not gain any additional value because of swings in the financial markets.All investments have a risk-return tradeoff. Historically, lower-risk investments-like cash equivalent (e.g. fixed deposit) investments-have typically offered lower potential for long-term growth and investment return. Higher-risk investments -like stock investments -have typically offered greater potential for long-term growth and investment return.By understanding the risk associated with various investment options, you can choose investments that best match your risk tolerance and personal circumstances.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-decide-how-to-invest",
        "question": "How do I decide how to invest?",
        "answer": "You need to establish a balance between risk and return that you are comfortable with. When establishing this balance, you should consider all the followings:Your risk tolerance- the amount of risk you are comfortable with and can afford to take. Can you still sleep at night if your investments have temporary short-term losses? Do you have enough savings that you can financially afford to take some investment risk?Your investment time horizon- How long will your assets be invested? Your CPF savings are for the long term. Unless you are close to retirement or have a short-term investment time horizon for other reasons, you should generally invest for the long term, but you need to decide what \"long\" means to you.Your overall financial situation- How much money will you need to sustain your lifestyle during retirement? Do you have other assets set aside for retirement besides your CPF savings? How are all of those assets invested? What are your financial commitments?",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-risk-am-i-willing-to-take-for-my-investments",
        "question": "How much risk am I willing to take for my investments?",
        "answer": "As investment objectives and goals differ from person to person, the question of how much \"risk\" to take is a personal one - no one answer is correct for everyone. Only you can decide what risk/return tradeoff you are comfortable with - but theRisk Tolerance Questionnaire(PDF, 0.2MB) may help you assess your tolerance for risk.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-know-if-i-am-investing-for-the-short-term-or-long-term",
        "question": "How do I know if I am investing for the short term or long term?",
        "answer": "The number of years you have to save and invest is called your\"INVESTMENT TIME HORIZON\"- it is the amount of time between when you invest and when you need to spend the proceeds of your investments. This spending can be for your retirement or for other financial commitments which you need to meet, such as to purchase a house or to pay for your children's education expenses.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-does-diversification-helps-to-limit-my-risk-in-investing",
        "question": "How does diversification helps to limit my risk in investing?",
        "answer": "Diversification, or spreading your assets among several investments, helps you smooth out potential ups and downs of your investment returns. Even if one investment does poorly, the others may do better, thereby potentially improving your overall return.You can diversify your investments at two distinct levels by spreading your investments among:different asset classes -cash equivalents (e.g., fixed deposits),bonds and stocks and/ordifferent markets - geographic regions, foreign countries, foreign currencies, industries and companies.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/should-i-maintain-a-consistent-strategy-in-investing",
        "question": "Should I maintain a consistent strategy in investing?",
        "answer": "Once you have decided on the right investment mix to meet your investment objectives and goals, you should try to maintain a consistent strategy. In general, you should only change your strategy if your personal circumstances have changed.As tempting as it may be to \"bail out\" if your investments take a dive, financial experts generally suggest that you stay fully invested. If you try to \"time the market\", you run the risk of getting caught in the trap of \"buying high\" and \"selling low\".If you hold on to your investment, chances are good that its value may eventually go back up, and that it may end up being worth more than when its value dropped.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-is-eligible-to-participate-in-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "Who is eligible to participate in the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "All CPF members whoare at least 18 years old;are not undischarged bankrupts; andhave more than $20,000 in their Ordinary Account (for investment under CPFIS-Ordinary Account) and/or have more than $40,000 in their Special Account (for investment under CPFIS-Special Account).From 1 October 2018, as a new CPFIS investor, you will need to take theSelf-Awareness Questionnaire (SAQ)before you can start investing under CPFIS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-self-awareness-questionnaire-saq",
        "question": "What is the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) Self-Awareness Questionnaire (SAQ)?",
        "answer": "The CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)Self-Awareness Questionnaire(SAQ) helps you assess if you have basic financial knowledge and whether CPFIS is suitable for you. The SAQ starts with learning modules on investment concepts, products and charges under CPFIS. You will then log in with your Singpass to attempt a quiz.From 1 October 2018, if you are a new CPFIS investor, you will need to take the SAQ before you can start investing under CPFIS. Agent banks and product providers will require you to declare your SAQ status and/or ask to view a copy of your SAQ status for verification. You can participate in the CPFIS once you have taken the SAQ, regardless of your SAQ results. You cancheck your SAQ statusvia my cpf digital services.If you already have a CPFIS account, while you are not required to take the SAQ, you are still strongly encouraged to do so.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-cpf-savings-can-i-invest",
        "question": "How much CPF savings can I invest?",
        "answer": "You can find out how much CPF savings you can invest by logging in tomy cpf digital serviceswith your Singpass > Selectmy cpf> My dashboards > Investment. You can also refer to thelist of instruments available for investment under the CPF Investment Scheme(PDF, 0.1MB) to learn about the instruments that you can invest in.The first $60,000 of your combined CPF accounts earns extra interest. To enable members to earn extra interest, monies in excess of $20,000 in your Ordinary Account and $40,000 in your Special Account can be invested. This requirement applies to all members, even if you are aged 55 and above and have set aside the Full Retirement Sum, due to the inherent risk associated with investments which applies across all age groups.Details on the instruments included under the CPF Investment SchemeYou can refer toAnnex A(PDF, 48KB) for more details on the instruments included under the CPF Investment Scheme. You may wish to refer to the risk classification tables forunit trusts(PDF, 0.1MB),investment-linked insurance products(PDF, 0.2MB) andexchange traded funds(PDF, 40KB) which CPF monies can be invested in.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/which-of-my-cpf-accounts-can-i-use-to-participate-under-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account-cpfis-oa-or-cpf-investment-scheme-special-account-cpfis-sa",
        "question": "Which of my CPF accounts can I use to participate under CPF Investment Scheme - Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) or CPF Investment Scheme - Special Account (CPFIS-SA)?",
        "answer": "You can only use your Ordinary Account (OA) savings for investments under CPF Investment Scheme - Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA), and your Special Account (SA) savings for investments under CPF Investment Scheme - Special Account (CPFIS-SA).The instruments available for investments under CPFIS-OA and CPFIS-SA are different. You may not combine savings from your OA and SA to buy a product. However, you can transfer funds from your OA to your SA* to invest under CPFIS-SA. Such transfers are irreversible. The total savings in the SA including the amount withdrawn under CPFIS-SA cannot exceed the current full retirement sum after the transfer.* Applicable only to members below age 55.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-difference-between-the-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account-cpfis-oa-and-cpf-investment-scheme-special-account-cpfis-sa",
        "question": "What is the difference between the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) and CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA)?",
        "answer": "Under CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA), investments may only be made using Ordinary Account savings while under CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA), investments may only be made using Special Account savings. The instruments available for investments under CPFIS-OA and CPFIS-SA are different.To find out how much CPF savings you can invest and whatinstruments youcan invest in, you can refer to thelist of instruments available for investment under the CPFIS(PDF, 0.1MB).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-check-how-much-cpf-i-can-invest",
        "question": "How do I check how much CPF I can invest?",
        "answer": "To check how much you can invest, you can view your CPF Statement by:logging in tomy cpfdigital serviceswith your Singpass > Selectmy cpf> My dashboards > Investmentaccessing the 'CPF Mobile'app with your Singpass, orvisiting anyCPF Service Centrespersonally with your identity card.Your stock and gold limits will be updated on the 11th of every month, based on your previous month-end balances. The limits will be updated on the 12th, if the 10th is a Sunday/Public Holiday.If you would like to know your limits based on your current balances, please contact the Board for an ad-hoc update of your limits. Please only proceed to invest after receiving our confirmation on the updated limits, which will be sent within two working days from the date of your request.For further details, please refer to thisexample(PDF, 66KB).Note: Before you commit to an investment, you should consider the other transactions that may affect your Ordinary Account and Special Account balances (e.g. outstanding investment transactions, monthly housing instalments, lump-sum housing payments, etc) as they could change your amount available for investment. Should you invest beyond your current limits, you will not be able to use your CPF monies to settle your trade. You may then have to settle the trade using cash and incur additional transaction fees.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-apply-to-use-my-cpf-savings-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "How do I apply to use my CPF savings under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "If you are a new CPFIS investor, you will need to take the Self-Awareness Questionnaire (SAQ) before you can start investing under CPFIS. The SAQ helps you to assess if you have basic financial knowledge and whether CPFIS is suitable for you.The process for applying to use your CPF savings under CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) and CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA) are different.CPFIS-OAFor CPFIS-OA, you will need to open a CPF Investment Account with one of the following CPFIS agent banks:DBS Bank Ltd (DBS)Oversea-Chinese Banking Corporation Ltd (OCBC)United Overseas Bank Ltd (UOB)Only UOB offers gold products (excluding gold ETFs). If you wish to invest in gold, you will need an investment account with UOB.You will need to bring along your identity card and a copy of your CPF statement for the agent bank to verify your CPF account number. The agent bank will also require you to declare your SAQ status and/or ask to view a copy of your SAQ status.Once you have successfully opened a CPF Investment Account, you may approach the product providers directly to buy or sell your investments.Your agent banks will liaise with the Board and the various product providers to settle your purchase and sale of investment, and keep track of your investment holdings and transactions in your CPF Investment Account. Do cater processing time required for the settlement of each application* (applicable to both the purchase and sale of investments). You can check with the respective service / product providers directly for the processing time required.Note that you can only maintain one CPF Investment Account at any one time.For more information, you can contact theService/Product Providers(PDF, 0.1MB) included under the CPFIS.CPFIS-SAFor CPFIS-SA, no CPF Investment Account is required.You may approach the product providers directly to buy or sell your investments.You will need to bring along your identity card and a copy of your CPF statement for the product provider to verify your CPF account number. The product provider will also require you to declare your SAQ status and/or ask to view a copy of your SAQ status. Do cater processing time required for the settlement of each application* (applicable to both the purchase and sale of investments). You can check with the respective service / product providers directly for the processing time required.CPF Board will liaise with the various product providers to settle your purchase and sale of investment, and keep track of your investment holdings and transactions.For more information, you can contact theService/Product Providers(PDF, 0.1MB) included under the CPFIS.*When you reach age 55, your SA and/or OA savings will be transferred to Retirement Account to set aside the Full Retirement Sum. To ensure successful processing, please submit your application at least 14 days before you turn age 55. This allows time for processing, which typically takes five to seven business days, and allows for any necessary follow-ups by the product providers to reduce the risk of failed trades.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/whom-should-i-approach-to-buy-or-sell-my-investments-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "Whom should I approach to buy or sell my investments under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "You may approach the following Service/Product Providers to buy or sell your investments:InstrumentsService/Product ProvidersFixed DepositsDeposits BanksSingapore Government BondsBond Dealers or BrokersSingapore Government Treasury BillsBond DealersStatutory Board BondsBond Dealers or BrokersBonds Guaranteed by Singapore GovernmentBrokersAnnuitiesEndowment Insurance PoliciesInvestment - Linked Insurance ProductsInsurance CompaniesUnit TrustsFund Management CompaniesInvestment AdministratorsFund Management AccountsFund Management CompaniesSharesProperty FundsCorporate BondsExchange Traded FundsBrokersGoldGold ETFsOther Gold productsFor Gold ETFs: BrokersFor other Gold products:- Sell through your Agent Bank- Buy through UOB Agent Bank and you need a UOB investment account.For more information on the various investment products, you may approach theproduct providers(PDF, 0.1MB) included under CPFIS or thebroking firms(PDF, 51KB).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-role-of-agent-banks-under-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account-cpfis-oa",
        "question": "What is the role of agent banks under CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA)?",
        "answer": "The agent banks are appointed to maintain members' CPF Investment Accounts under the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) as they have an extensive network of branches and facilities to support the investment and settlement of shares and bonds listed on the Singapore Exchange. The agent banks' electronic banking services such as ATMs are easily accessible and allow members to conveniently apply for shares or bonds during an IPO. The banks are also able to handle the complex processing of corporate actions such as bonus and rights issues, dividend payments and schemes of arrangement under the CPFIS-OA.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-participate-in-the-cpf-investment-scheme-while-i-am-overseas",
        "question": "Can I participate in the CPF Investment Scheme while I am overseas?",
        "answer": "You can participate in the CPF Investment Scheme while you are overseas. However, there are some investments which would require you to be personally present. You may have to authorise someone to act on your behalf by way of a Power of Attorney if you are not able to handle the transactions yourself.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-have-to-incur-any-charges-for-cpf-investment-scheme-investments",
        "question": "Do I have to incur any charges for CPF Investment Scheme investments?",
        "answer": "You will incur charges which are payable from your CPF savings. Please refer to thelist of typical charges(PDF, 0.2MB) that may be incurred when you invest your CPF in various instruments.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-continue-to-use-my-cpf-monies-to-pay-for-the-quarterly-bank-charges-even-if-i-do-not-have-20-000-in-my-ordinary-account",
        "question": "Can I continue to use my CPF monies to pay for the quarterly bank charges even if I do not have $20,000 in my Ordinary Account?",
        "answer": "You can use your Ordinary Account balance to pay for the quarterly agent banks charges, even if your Ordinary Account balance is below $20,000. The restriction on the use of the first $20,000 in Ordinary Account for CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account only applies to new investments, including payments for recurring single premiums (for insurance) and regular savings plans (for unit trusts).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-top-up-monies-form-part-of-the-required-40-000-that-needs-to-be-set-aside-before-i-can-invest-my-special-account-monies",
        "question": "Do top-up monies form part of the required $40,000 that needs to be set aside before I can invest my Special Account monies?",
        "answer": "Top-up monies form part of the $40,000 that needs to be set aside in the Special Account (SA) before you can use the excess for your investment. However, top-up monies cannot be used for investment. For example, if you have $100,000 in your SA, of which $90,000 are top up monies you received in your SA, only monies in excess of the $90,000 (i.e. $10,000) can be invested. Please refer to thisFAQfor further information on usage of top-up monies.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-top-up-my-cpf-investment-account-under-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account-with-cash-if-i-do-not-have-sufficient-cpf-savings-for-investment",
        "question": "Can I top-up my CPF Investment Account under CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account with cash if I do not have sufficient CPF savings for investment?",
        "answer": "Cash top-ups are not allowed, except in the case of taking up entitlements (e.g. rights shares) or conversion of entitlements. You may top-up your CPF Investment Account through your agent bank if you have insufficient CPF savings or stock limit to subscribe for the entitlements or conversion. However, such cash top-ups are not withdrawable or refundable, even if your applications are unsuccessful.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-use-my-cpf-to-apply-for-shares-property-funds-or-corporate-bonds-offered-during-an-initial-public-offering-ipo-under-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account-cpfis-oa",
        "question": "How do I use my CPF to apply for shares, property funds or corporate bonds offered during an Initial Public Offering (IPO) under CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA)?",
        "answer": "You may apply for the IPO in any of the available ways.Use your agent bank's ATMs for your application;Use your agent bank's internet banking for your application; orObtain a CPF cashier's order from your agent bank's counter and attach it to your IPO application form.The amount of CPF needed will be transferred automatically from your Ordinary Account to your CPF Investment Account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-engage-in-contra-trading-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "Can I engage in contra trading under the CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "CPF savings cannot be used for contra trading as it may encourage speculative trading, and investors bear a higher risk of losing their monies. Hence, it is not suitable for long term investment and for retirement planning.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-invest-in-shares-listed-on-the-singapore-exchange-sgx-as-long-as-they-meet-the-inclusion-criteria-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "Can I invest in shares listed on the Singapore Exchange (SGX) as long as they meet the inclusion criteria under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "The Board welcomes the inclusion of shares listed on the SGX Mainboard as long as they meet the inclusion criteria. However, some companies who meet the inclusion criteria have not applied to be included under CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS), and CPF savings cannot be used for these shares. You can refer toSGX websitefor the list of shares included under the CPFIS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-cpf-monies-be-used-for-rights-and-or-warrants",
        "question": "Can CPF monies be used for rights and/or warrants?",
        "answer": "You cannot use your CPF monies to purchase rights/warrants directly from the marketplace. However, if you are issued rights/warrants that arise from shares/investments that you currently hold, you may use your CPF monies to pay for the exercise price of these rights/warrants provided the underlying investments being taken up are included under the CPF Investment Scheme, subject to your available stock limit. For such cases, your agent bank will reach out to you on the details of the application.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-soon-can-i-sell-my-investments-which-are-traded-on-the-singapore-exchange-after-i-buy-them-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account",
        "question": "How soon can I sell my investments which are traded on the Singapore Exchange after I buy them under the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account?",
        "answer": "You can sell your investments (e.g. shares or property funds) which are listed on the Singapore Exchange one trading day after the purchase date provided:Your stock broker has keyed the purchase trade on the day the purchase contract is made; andYou have sufficient investible funds in your CPF Investment and/or Ordinary Account to settle the purchase.Your available stock limit or gold limit will be updated on the 2nd trading day (i.e. T+2) based on the cost of the shares, property funds, corporate bonds or gold exchange traded funds (ETFs) sold when the sale transaction is settled. Please refer to thisexample(PDF, 0.1MB) to see how the stock limit and gold limit are computed.Can I reinvest the full sale proceeds immediately?If you intend to buy another share, property fund, corporate bond or gold ETF during this T+2 period, please check with your agent bank on your available stock limit or gold limit first. You will need to have sufficient investible funds in your CPF Investment and/or Ordinary Account to settle the new purchase before the settlement deadline.Why can’t I reinvest the full sale proceeds immediately?You have to ensure that you have the sufficient limits, and monies to reinvest when your sale proceeds have been refunded. Unlike cash trades, stock investment using CPF is subject to the CPF stock limit which may change with CPF contributions, withdrawals, crediting of CPFIS sale proceeds, new CPFIS investments etc. Hence, to err on the safe side, it may be better for you to reinvest after your fund position is firmed up on T+2, in line with SGX settlement framework.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-use-my-cpf-to-apply-for-singapore-government-bonds-and-treasury-bills-t-bills-at-primary-auctions-can-the-application-be-submitted-using-online-or-atm-services",
        "question": "How do I use my CPF to apply for Singapore Government Bonds and Treasury Bills (T-bills) at primary auctions? Can the application be submitted using online or ATM services?",
        "answer": "For CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA)Please apply for the bonds and T-bills through your CPFIS-OA agent bank. Application is restricted to your CPFIS-OA agent bank to facilitate the settlement process for bonds and T-bills purchased under CPFIS-OA.DBS/POSB: Apply through DBS/POSB's internet banking portal or digibank mobile.OCBC: Apply through OCBC’s internet banking portal or OCBC Digital application.UOB: Apply for SGS bonds in person at any UOB branch. Apply for T-bills through UOB’s internet banking portalFor step-by-step guide on how to submit your application through your CPFIS-OA agent bank’s electronic portal, you may visit their website,DBS(scroll to dropdown menu “How to apply?”),OCBC(scroll to section “Invest digitally into T-bills & SGS bonds with your CPF”) andUOB(scroll to section \"Things you should know\").After the T-bills auction closes, you can check the aggregate results of the auction at the Monetary Authority of Singapore’swebsite. If your application is successful, the T-bills allotted to you will be reflected in the CPF investment account statement sent by your agent bank.For CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA)You may apply for the bonds and T-bills via any of the CPFIS bond dealers (i.e. DBS, OCBC or UOB).DBS/POSB: Apply in person at any DBS/POSB branch.OCBC: Apply through OCBC’s internet banking portal or OCBC Digital application.UOB: Apply in person at any UOB branch.For step-by-step guide on how to submit your application through the CPFIS bond dealer’s electronic portal, you may visit their website,OCBC(scroll to section “Invest digitally into T-bills & SGS bonds with your CPF”).After the T-bills auction closes, you can check the aggregate results of the auction at the Monetary Authority of Singapore’swebsite. If your application is successful, the T-bills allotted to you will be reflected in yourSpecial Account investment portfolio statement.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-applied-to-purchase-treasury-bills-t-bills-at-primary-auction-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-when-would-my-cpf-savings-be-deducted-for-the-purchase",
        "question": "I have applied to purchase Treasury Bills (T-bills) at primary auction under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS). When would my CPF savings be deducted for the purchase?",
        "answer": "Your CPF savings for T-bills purchase under CPFIS would be deducted only upon the successful allotment of the T-bills. In so doing, CPF members will continue earning CPF interest on their CPF savings, in case full or part of their T-bills application is unsuccessful. The deductions are done after the auction date (i.e. the date where the allotment of your T-bills purchase has been finalised) but before the issue date of the T-bills.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-start-investing-my-cpf-ordinary-account-oa-savings-in-treasury-bills-t-bills-under-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account-cpfis-oa",
        "question": "How do I start investing my CPF Ordinary Account (OA) savings in Treasury bills (T-bills) under CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA)?",
        "answer": "You need to be at least 18 years old; not an undischarged bankrupt; and have more than $20,000 in your CPF Ordinary Account (OA). If you meet all of the conditions and would like to start investing your CPF OA savings in T-bills, please take the following steps:Step 1:Complete CPFISSelf-Awareness Questionnaire (SAQ)to assess if CPFIS is suitable for you. You cancheck your SAQ completion status.Step 2:Open CPF Investment Account (CPFIA) online with any of the three CPFIS agent banks:DBS's digibot(scroll to “Get started with CPFIA” and click “digibot”)OCBC's websiteor OCBC's mobile appUOB's websiteAlternatively, you may also visit any of the banks (DBS, OCBC or UOB) branches to open your CPF Investment Account.Step 3:Invest in the T-bills of your choice. The Government issues 6-months and 1-year T-bills. You can check theMAS websiteon upcoming T-bills auctions. After deciding, you can use the bank’s online services to apply for T-bills. Refer toHow to use your CPF for T-bills.Step 4:Wait for the results of your T-bills purchase, which will be available on auction date. The bank will notify you on the outcome of your T-bills purchase. You can also check the T-bills allotted to you via your CPF Investment Account (CPFIA) online. Your CPF OA would be deducted and transferred to your CPFIA only upon successful allotment of the T-bills. The deducted amount (i.e., initial investment amount) would be lower than the amount which you have been allotted as T-bills are issued at a discount to the face value. Refer to theT-bills FAQs on the MAS websiteon how to compute your initial investment amount based on cut-off yield (T-bills FAQs > Application of T-bills > “How do I compute my initial investment for my T-bills based on the cut-off yield?”).Step 5:Upon maturity of your T-bills in 6 or 12 months (depending on the type of T-bills that you have purchased), your CPFIS agent bank will credit the proceeds to your IA. You can then take any of the following actions:Re-invest in another T-bill purchase or any other investment.If you do not plan to re-invest your CPF OA savings, you can apply to return the balances in the CPFIA to CPF OA to earn the CPF interest. You can do so via your CPFIS agent bank’s ATMs, internet/phone banking or over the bank counter. ClickDBSandOCBC’s links to find out more.If you do nothing, the monies in your CPFIA will be automatically returned to your CPF OA, if your CPFIA is inactive for 2 consecutive months.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-purchase-a-regular-premium-insurance-policy-under-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "Can I purchase a regular premium insurance policy under CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "With effect from 1 January 2001, CPF savings cannot be used for new regular premium insurance policies. Only Single Premium or Recurring Single Premium insurance policy is allowed under CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account and CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-continue-to-use-my-ordinary-account-savings-to-service-my-regular-premium-insurance-bought-before-1-january-2001-even-if-my-balance-falls-below-20-000",
        "question": "Can I continue to use my Ordinary Account savings to service my regular premium insurance bought before 1 January 2001, even if my balance falls below $20,000?",
        "answer": "You can continue to service the future premiums using your Ordinary Account savings, even if your balance falls below $20,000. This applies to you even after age 55 as long as you have set aside the Full Retirement Sum or the Basic Retirement Sum with sufficient property charge/pledge in the Retirement Account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-the-restriction-on-investments-for-the-first-20-000-in-ordinary-account-and-the-first-40-000-in-special-account-affect-me",
        "question": "How will the restriction on investments for the first $20,000 in Ordinary Account and the first $40,000 in Special Account affect me?",
        "answer": "The first $60,000 of your combined CPF accounts earns an extra 1% interest. To enable members to earn extra interest, only monies in excess of $20,000 in your Ordinary Account (OA) and $40,000 in your Special Account (SA) can be invested.However, you can continue to service your agent bank fees and regular premium insurance policies (excludes recurring single premium insurance policies or regular savings plans for unit trusts) even if your OA balance falls below $20,000.If you have already made investments using your OA or SA balances, you are not required to sell these investments.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-options-available-to-me-if-i-foresee-that-i-do-not-have-sufficient-cpf-to-continue-paying-the-instalments-on-my-regular-premium-insurance-policy",
        "question": "What are the options available to me if I foresee that I do not have sufficient CPF to continue paying the instalments on my regular premium insurance policy?",
        "answer": "If you foresee difficulties in paying your future premiums using CPF, you may wish to consider the following options after consulting your insurance advisor:Pay the instalment using cash. Any proceeds from your insurance policy will then be apportioned according to the amount of premiums paid using cash and CPF;Change the payment frequency from yearly to half-yearly or even to quarterly or monthly, subject to the insurance company’s agreement, so that a lower premium will be deducted per payment;Reduce the sum assured, thus reducing the amount of premium payable; orConvert the policy to a paid-up policy.After you have decided on the option, you need to liaise with your insurance company on the payment of the premium.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-have-an-existing-regular-premium-insurance-policy-bought-using-cash-can-i-continue-to-service-the-future-premiums-using-cpf-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account-cpfis-oa",
        "question": "If I have an existing regular premium insurance policy bought using cash, can I continue to service the future premiums using CPF under the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA)?",
        "answer": "With effect from 1 January 2001, CPF savings cannot be used for new regular premium insurance policies, regardless of whether the policies are converted from cash or newly bought from insurance companies.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-have-terminated-my-insurance-policy-bought-using-cpf-can-i-reinstate-the-policy-and-pay-the-outstanding-premiums-and-future-premiums-using-cpf",
        "question": "If I have terminated my insurance policy bought using CPF, can I reinstate the policy and pay the outstanding premiums and future premiums using CPF?",
        "answer": "You need to liaise with your insurance company on the reinstatement of the policy. Upon reinstatement, you may pay the outstanding and future premiums using CPF. However, no CPF can be used to pay any outstanding interest owing to the insurance company.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-invest-in-fixed-deposit-in-foreign-currency-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "Can I invest in Fixed Deposit in foreign currency under the CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "Foreign currency Fixed Deposits are not included under the CPF Investment Scheme.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/is-there-a-minimum-interest-rate-for-cpf-investment-scheme-fixed-deposit-fd-that-fd-banks-must-offer",
        "question": "Is there a minimum interest rate for CPF Investment Scheme Fixed Deposit (FD) that FD Banks must offer?",
        "answer": "With effect from 1 May 2007, Fixed Deposit (FD) Banks must offer a minimum effective interest rate that is at least the prevailing CPF interest rate for new placements or roll over of any CPF Investment Scheme FDs. In this way, members will not be worse off than leaving their monies in the CPF Accounts.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-use-cpf-savings-to-place-fixed-deposits-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "Can I use CPF savings to place Fixed Deposits under the CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "You can use your CPF savings to place Fixed Deposits (FD) with any of the four Fixed Deposit Banks (DBS, Maybank, OCBC and UOB) under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS). Currently, none of the FD banks are offering FD products under CPFIS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-forgotten-my-cpf-investment-account-number-how-can-i-go-about-checking-this",
        "question": "I have forgotten my CPF Investment Account Number. How can I go about checking this?",
        "answer": "To check your CPF Investment Account Number, you can:login tomy cpfOnline Serviceswith your Singpass > Selectmy cpf> My dashboards > Investment;access the 'CPF Mobile' app using your Singpass;check your CPF Investment Scheme Statement sent by your agent bank; orcontact your agent bank directly.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-transfer-my-cpf-investment-account-under-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account-from-one-agent-bank-to-another-if-so-must-i-sell-my-investments-first",
        "question": "Can I transfer my CPF Investment Account under CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account from one agent bank to another? If so, must I sell my investments first?",
        "answer": "You may transfer your CPF Investment Account from one agent bank to another. You need not sell your investments, except for your investment in gold bought from your agent bank (excluding gold Exchange Traded Funds). All your investments and cash balances will be transferred along with your CPF Investment Account. To transfer your CPF Investment Account, you need to apply at the bank which you intend to transfer your account to.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-close-my-cpf-investment-account-under-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account",
        "question": "How do I close my CPF Investment Account under CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account?",
        "answer": "You will have to sell all your investments first before instructing your agent bank to close your CPF Investment Account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-there-are-adjustments-under-cpf-investment-scheme-in-my-ordinary-or-special-account-what-interest-rate-will-be-used",
        "question": "If there are adjustments under CPF Investment Scheme in my Ordinary or Special Account, what interest rate will be used?",
        "answer": "Any adjustments under the CPF Investment Scheme in your Ordinary or Special Account will be based on the CPF interest rates for the respective account. The interest rate will not include the extra 1% interest that is paid on the first $60,000 of your combined balances.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-accept-gifts-and-or-rebates-from-my-service-providers-when-investing-under-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "Can I accept gifts and/or rebates from my service providers when investing under CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "All gifts and/or rebates arising from investing under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) must be converted to cash and refunded back to your CPF Ordinary and Special Accounts respectively. You are not allowed to receive gifts and/or rebates direct from your service provider as this will result in a leakage of CPF funds. Alternatively, you may also receive rebates in the form of additional units of investments under the CPFIS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-wrap-fee",
        "question": "What is Wrap fee?",
        "answer": "Wrap fee is an ongoing fee charged by a financial adviser to an investor, for providing bundled investment services, including advisory, brokerage and administrative. The fee is usually charged as a percentage on the market value of assets under management of the financial adviser.Wrap fee is consumptive and erodes returns on investment funds. As CPF monies are meant for retirement and to prevent our members from paying excessive wrap fees, CPF Board has capped wrap fees at 0.4% per annum with effect from 1 October 2020. This is in line with the Board's continuing efforts to lower the cost of investment for our members.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-do-if-my-wrap-account-currently-charges-me-a-wrap-fee-of-more-than-0-4-per-annum",
        "question": "What should I do if my wrap account currently charges me a wrap fee of more than 0.4% per annum?",
        "answer": "With effect from 1 October 2020, your wrap fee payable will be capped at 0.4% per annum. You should contact your financial adviser or Investment Administrators if you continue to pay more than the capped rate after 1 October 2020.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-type-of-investor-will-be-affected-by-the-wrap-fee-cap",
        "question": "What type of investor will be affected by the wrap fee cap?",
        "answer": "The wrap fee cap will affect CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) investors who have wrap accounts with any of the 4 CPFIS-included Investment Administrators.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-this-wrap-fee-cap-affect-my-investments",
        "question": "How will this wrap fee cap affect my investments?",
        "answer": "Wrap fee is typically paid by redemption of units in your CPF-funded unit trust investment. With effect from 1 October 2020, you should not be paying more than 0.4% per annum in wrap fee from your CPF-funded investment.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-attend-and-vote-at-a-company-s-annual-extraordinary-general-meetings-agms-egms-as-a-cpf-investor",
        "question": "How do I attend (and vote at) a Company's Annual/Extraordinary General Meetings (AGMs/EGMs) as a CPF investor?",
        "answer": "CPF investors should refer to the company announcements on SGXNet (or Company website) for instructions on attending AGMs/EGMs.Special Arrangements due to Covid-19 MeasuresCompanies would not be able to proceed with physical general meetings during the Circuit Breaker period due to the Safe Distancing measures in place. Companies that hold AGMs/EGMs during this period may have special arrangements (e.g. \"live\" webcast). CPF investors who wish to participate in these meetings and/or vote on meeting resolutions should take note of the following:AttendanceCPF investors should refer to the company announcements on SGXNet (or Company website) for instructions on how to attend the virtual meeting. CPF investors should take note of the pre-registration deadlines (including the submission of questions to the Company which will be addressed publicly before or during the virtual meeting).VotingSince CPF investors cannot physically attend general meetings to vote, they can instead vote through their respective CPF Agent Banks. CPF investors must submit their voting instructions to their agent banksat least seven working days before the general meeting. CPF investors should contact their respective Agent Banks (DBS, OCBC, UOB) to find out more about how to submit their voting instruction(s).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-check-my-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-details",
        "question": "How can I check my CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) details?",
        "answer": "There are various ways in obtaining the details of your investments under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS):CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA)You can either refer to your CPF Investment Scheme statement sent by your agent bank or contact them directly.CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA)You can view the details of your investments by:logging intomy cpfdigital serviceswith your Singpass > Selectmy cpf> My dashboards > Investment;accessing the 'CPF Mobile' app with your Singpass; orvisiting anyCPF Service Centrespersonally with your identity card.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-invested-in-a-company-using-cpf-how-can-i-get-the-latest-financial-statement-or-annual-report-of-this-company-if-the-company-has-been-delisted-and-what-should-i-do-if-the-company-does-not-respond-to-my-request",
        "question": "I have invested in a company using CPF. How can I get the latest financial statement or annual report of this company, if the company has been delisted? And what should I do if the company does not respond to my request?",
        "answer": "You may approach the company for the financial statement or annual report directly. You can mail your request to their office address through registered post. The office addresses of companies can be found onACRA's BizFile portal. If you do not hear back from the company, please approach your agent bank who will follow up with ACRA.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-do-if-the-company-s-shares-that-i-have-invested-in-using-cpf-monies-are-suspended-or-delisted",
        "question": "What should I do if the company's shares that I have invested in using CPF monies are suspended or delisted?",
        "answer": "If the shares of a company you have invested in using CPF monies are suspended or delisted, you have the option to continue holding them in your CPFIS portfolio. However, it is important to note that you will have to continue paying quarterly agent bank fees on these shares.You should stay informed about the latest developments by checking the company’s website or SGX’sCompany Announcements. Understanding the reasons behind the suspension or delisting can help you assess the future viability of the company.If you have decided that you no longer wish to hold the shares of the company, consider reaching out to the company to check if they have a buyback program in place. If that is not an option, pleaseWrite to Usand we will see how we can assist you.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-when-i-sell-my-investments-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "What happens when I sell my investments under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "The sale proceeds from your investments under the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) and CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA) are handled differently.CPFIS-OAWhen you sell your investments, the sales proceeds will automatically be credited into your CPF Investment Account. The monies will remain there, unless you instruct your agent bank to transfer the amount into your OA. Do cater processing time required for the settlement of each application (applicable to both the purchase and sale of investments). You can check with the respective service/product providers directly for the processing time required.Your agent bank will also automatically transfer the cash balance held in your CPF Investment Account to your OA (at the end of the month*) if your Investment Account has been inactive (i.e. if there had been no investment transactions) for two consecutive months.* The monies will be transferred on the third last working day of the month. In the event that the third last working day falls on a Saturday, the transfer will take place on the second last working day of the month.CPFIS-SAWhen you sell your investments, the sales proceeds will automatically be credited into your SA. Do cater processing time required for the settlement of each application (applicable to both the purchase and sale of investments). You can check with the respective service/product providers directly for the processing time required.We know that some members use ‘SA Shielding’ (i.e. investing their SA savings shortly before age 55 and liquidating it after age 55), to retain more CPF savings in the SA and enjoy its attractive interest rates.The use of ‘SA Shielding’ comes with costs and investment risks – there may be transaction fees involved in using CPF for investment and you may lose a portion of the amount invested.A better option for members who want to enjoy the attractive CPF interest rates is to top-up their Retirement Account up to the Enhanced Retirement Sum through the Retirement Sum Topping-Up Scheme instead.We will continue to monitor the ‘SA Shielding’ trend closely and take appropriate action if necessary. Financial advisers and insurance brokers who promote ‘SA Shielding’ without highlighting the costs and investment risks may be guilty of mis-selling, and should be reported to theMonetary Authority of Singapore.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-transfer-the-monies-from-my-cpf-investment-account-to-my-ordinary-account",
        "question": "How do I transfer the monies from my CPF Investment Account to my Ordinary Account?",
        "answer": "You can perform this request by:Following the steps onDBS websiteUsingOCBC’s internet banking(After login, Mouse over “Investments & Insurance” menu bar, click “Retirement Portfolio” from dropdown list, then click on “Refund to CPF Board” on left menu bar)UsingUOB’s internet banking(After login, click “Investment” on left menu bar, and click “Transfer to CPF” under CPFIS-Ord A/c)If you do nothing, your monies in your CPF Investment Account (IA) will only be refunded at the end of the second month of inactivity. You will lose up to two months of CPF interest.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-transferred-money-from-investment-account-back-into-my-cpf-ordinary-account-when-does-the-cpf-interest-computation-start",
        "question": "I have transferred money from Investment Account back into my CPF Ordinary Account. When does the CPF interest computation start?",
        "answer": "When you transfer money from your Investment Account to your Ordinary Account, you will start to earn CPF interest on the transferred amount from the following month onwards.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-need-to-pay-accrued-interest-if-i-used-my-cpf-savings-for-cpf-investments",
        "question": "Do I need to pay accrued interest if I used my CPF savings for CPF investments?",
        "answer": "You do not need to pay back the accrued interest on the CPF savings used for your CPF investments.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-will-the-maturity-proceeds-of-my-investments-be-credited-to-my-cpf-accounts",
        "question": "When will the maturity proceeds of my investments be credited to my CPF accounts?",
        "answer": "The maturity proceeds for investments under CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) and CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA) are handled differently:CPFIS-OAUpon maturity of your CPFIS-OA investments, the proceeds will be credited into your CPF Investment Account generally within one week. You can check with your agent bank to know if the proceeds have been credited.CPFIS-SAUpon maturity of your CPFIS-SA investments, the proceeds will be credited into your SA generally within one week. To check whether the proceeds have been credited, you can view your CPFIS statement by logging into:my cpfOnline Serviceswith your Singpass > Selectmy cpf> My dashboards > Investment; orthe 'CPF Mobile' app with your Singpass.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-my-investment-proceeds-in-my-cpf-investment-account-not-transferred-to-my-ordinary-account-immediately",
        "question": "Why are my investment proceeds in my CPF Investment Account not transferred to my Ordinary Account immediately?",
        "answer": "Your investment returns go to your CPF Investment Account (IA) with the agent banks to facilitate quicker reinvestments in assets like shares and bonds on the Singapore Exchange. If you did not make any transactions for 2 months, your IA balance will be automatically refunded at the end of the month.If you do not plan to reinvest, you should request your agent bank totransfer the sale proceeds from your IA back to your Ordinary Account (OA). This allows your funds to start earning CPF interest earlier of up to 3.5% per annum from the next month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-my-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-investments-be-sold-or-liquidated-when-i-apply-to-withdraw-my-cpfis-investments-upon-meeting-cpf-withdrawal-conditions",
        "question": "Will my CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) investments be sold or liquidated when I apply to withdraw my CPFIS investments upon meeting CPF withdrawal conditions?",
        "answer": "Applying to withdraw your CPFIS investments will not result in liquidation of your investment holdings. If your withdrawal application is approved, your agent bank and/or product providers will contact you on the transfer of your investments to you.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-transfer-my-shares-bought-under-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-to-my-central-depository-cdp-account",
        "question": "How do I transfer my shares, bought under CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS), to my Central Depository (CDP) account?",
        "answer": "You can apply to withdraw your CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) investments and transfer your shares to your own CDP account, after you have reached 55 years old and have set aside your Full Retirement Sum (FRS) in the Retirement Account (RA). The FRS can be set aside fully with cash, or with cash (i.e. at least the Basic Retirement Sum) and property. Your CPF Investment Account will be closed once you apply to withdraw your investments.Please refer to thisFAQfor more information on how the retirement sum is set aside at age 55.You will be able to view the link to submit your application through theInvestment dashboardif you meet the eligibility conditions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-continue-to-invest-under-the-cpf-investment-schemes-beyond-age-55",
        "question": "Can I continue to invest under the CPF Investment Schemes beyond age 55?",
        "answer": "You can continue to invest even after age 55, as long as you have set aside your Full Retirement Sum (FRS) in the Retirement Account. The FRS can be set aside fully with cash, or with cash (i.e. at least the Basic Retirement Sum) and property. In addition, you will not be able to invest the first $20,000 in your Ordinary Account (OA) and the first $40,000 in your Special Account (SA). This requirement applies to all members, even if you are aged 55 and above and have set aside the FRS, due to the inherent risk associated with investments which applies across all age groups. If you are eligible to withdraw your CPF, you have the flexibility to withdraw your OA/SA savings and invest as cash.Please also note that thestock and gold limits(PDF, 0.1MB) applicable to you may change.Please refer to thisFAQfor more information on how the retirement sum is set aside at age 55.To check your available CPF amount for investment, you can:login intomy cpfdigital serviceswith your Singpass > Selectmy cpf> My dashboards > Investment;access the 'CPF Mobile' app with your Singpass; orvisit anyCPF Service Centrespersonally with your identity card.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-withdraw-my-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-investments-when-i-reach-55-years-old",
        "question": "Can I withdraw my CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) investments when I reach 55 years old?",
        "answer": "You can apply to the Board to withdraw your CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) and CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA) investments as well as the cash balance in your Investment Account, as long as you have set aside your Full Retirement Sum (FRS) in the Retirement Account (RA). The FRS can be set aside fully with cash, or with cash (i.e. at least the Basic Retirement Sum) and property. Your CPF Investment Account will be closed once you apply to withdraw your investments.Please refer to thisFAQfor more information on how the retirement sum is set aside at age 55.You will be able to view the link to submit your application through theInvestment dashboardif you meet the eligibility conditions.Please refer to the following information to find out what would happen after you have applied for withdrawal of investments under the CPFIS:CPFIS-OAWe will inform the agent bank to close your CPF Investment Account. The agent bank will contact you for the withdrawal of your investments and cash balance (if any) in your CPF Investment Account. Your investments will be transferred* to your own name and you may thereafter liquidate them as you wish and have the sale proceeds paid to you directly.Once withdrawn, your CPFIS investments and cash balance in your CPF Investment Account will no longer be protected from any claims by your creditors and/or the Official Assignee.* Central Depository (Pte) Ltd (“CDP”) imposes a transfer fee of $10.00 (excluding GST) for every share counter transferred from your CPF Investment Account to your CDP Account.CPFIS-SAWe will inform your product provider(s) to transfer your investments to your own name and you may thereafter liquidate them as you wish and have the sale proceeds paid to you directly.Once withdrawn, your CPFIS investments will no longer be protected from any claims by your creditors and/or the Official Assignee.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-does-the-board-treat-the-maturity-proceeds-by-the-insurer-after-i-reached-55-years-old",
        "question": "How does the Board treat the maturity proceeds by the insurer after I reached 55 years old?",
        "answer": "The maturity proceeds from your insurance policies under the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) and the CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA) are handled differently.For insurance policies under:CPFIS-OAFor CPFIS-OA policies, the proceeds would be refunded to your CPF Investment Account with your agent bank. You can instruct your bank to transfer the monies back to your CPF Ordinary Account. You can apply for withdrawal of the monies (once the proceeds are credited) subject to the prevailing CPF withdrawal rules. Find out more onwithdrawal of CPF savings.For policies that have already been transferred to your name earlier when you applied for withdrawal of your CPFIS investments, it would be considered as cash policies and the insurance companies would pay the proceeds directly to you.If you need to withdraw more than the default online Daily Withdrawal Limit of $2,000, find outmore.If you need to withdraw more than the maximum online Daily Withdrawal Limit, find outmore.CPFIS-SAFor CPFIS-SA policies, the proceeds would be refunded to your CPF Special Account. You can apply for withdrawal of the monies (once the proceeds are credited) subject to the prevailing CPF withdrawal rules. Find out more onwithdrawal of CPF savings.If you need to withdraw more than the default online Daily Withdrawal Limit of $2,000, find outmore.If you need to withdraw more than the maximum online Daily Withdrawal Limit, find outmore.For policies that have already been transferred to your name when you applied for withdrawal of your CPFIS investments, it would be considered as cash policies and the insurance companies would pay the proceeds directly to you.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-will-happen-to-my-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-investments-if-i-leave-singapore-permanently-and-withdraw-all-my-cpf-monies",
        "question": "What will happen to my CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) investments if I leave Singapore permanently and withdraw all my CPF monies?",
        "answer": "For CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA), we will inform the agent bank to close your CPF Investment Account. The agent bank will contact you for the withdrawal of your investments and cash balance (if any) in your CPF Investment Account. Your investments will be transferred* to your own name and you may thereafter continue servicing your investments using cash or liquidate them as you wish and have the sale proceeds paid to you directly.* Central Depository (Pte) Ltd (“CDP”) imposes a transfer fee of $10.00 (excluding GST) for every share counter transferred from your CPF Investment Account to your CDP Account.For CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account (CPFIS-SA), we will inform your product provider(s) to transfer your investments to your own name and you may thereafter liquidate them as you wish and have the sale proceeds paid to you directly.Once withdrawn, your CPFIS investments and cash balance in your CPF Investment Account will no longer be protected from any claims by your creditors and/or the Official Assignee.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-to-my-investments-when-my-cpf-account-is-closed",
        "question": "What happens to my investments when my CPF account is closed?",
        "answer": "The treatment of your investments when your CPF account is closed will depend on the investment scheme you have participated in.CPF Investment Scheme – Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA)We will inform the agent bank to close your CPF Investment Account. The agent bank will then contact you for the withdrawal#of your investments and cash balance (if any). Your investments will be transferred to your own name and you may thereafter continue servicing your investments using cash or liquidate them as you wish and have the sale proceeds paid to you directly.Once transferred, your CPFIS investments and cash balance in your CPF Investment Account will no longer be protected from any claims by your creditors and/or the Official Assignee.#Central Depository (Pte) Ltd (“CDP”) imposes a transfer fee of $10.00 (excluding GST) for every share counter transferred from your CPF Investment Account to your CDP Account.CPF Investment Scheme – Special Account (CPFIS-SA)We will inform your product provider(s) to transfer your investment to your own name. Thereafter, you may liquidate them as you wish and have the sale proceeds paid to you directly.Once transferred, your CPFIS investments and cash balance in your CPF Investment Account will no longer be protected from any claims by your creditors and/or the Official Assignee.Special Discounted Shares (SDS) SchemeYour discounted Singtel shares will be automatically liquidated in the month following theautomatic closure of your CPF account. The sales proceeds will be held together with your CPF savings, which you can transfer to your bank account at any point in time.If you do not wish for your discounted Singtel shares to be automatically liquidated, please liquidate them before you renounce your Singapore Citizenship or Permanent Residency.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-find-out-my-own-profit-loss-on-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "How can I find out my own profit/loss on CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "You may refer to the portfolio statement sent to you by your agent bank or your product provider. If you have sold your investments, the difference between the cost and sale proceeds is your profit/loss. If you have not sold your investments, the difference between the cost and market value is your profit/loss.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-if-i-make-a-loss-on-my-investments-do-i-have-to-make-good-the-loss",
        "question": "What happens if I make a loss on my investments? Do I have to make good the loss?",
        "answer": "You need not make good your investment loss. However losses will reduce your retirement nest egg.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-withdraw-my-investment-profits",
        "question": "Can I withdraw my investment profits?",
        "answer": "Profits made from investments under the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account and/or CPF Investment Scheme-Special Account are not withdrawable as the purpose of investing is to grow your savings for retirement. However, the profits can be used for other CPF schemes, subject to the terms and conditions of these schemes.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/are-my-investment-profits-interest-earned-from-investments-and-dividends-received-taxable",
        "question": "Are my investment profits, interest earned from investments and dividends received taxable?",
        "answer": "Your investment profits, interest earned from investments and dividends are not taxable under the CPF Investment Scheme.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-does-the-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account-cpfis-oa-total-profits-losses-statistic-measure",
        "question": "What does the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) Total Profits/Losses statistic measure?",
        "answer": "The CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) Total Profits/Losses statistic provides a complete representation of the investors total portfolio performance. It takes into account not only the realised profits or losses of investments that were sold, but also the unrealised profits or losses of investments that members held during the reporting period.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-is-members-investment-performance-in-the-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account-cpfis-oa",
        "question": "How is members' investment performance in the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA)?",
        "answer": "Please refer to theCPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) Profits/Losses Reportif you wish to view members' investment performance in the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/where-can-i-find-a-copy-of-the-cpf-investment-scheme-ordinary-account-cpfis-oa-profits-losses-report",
        "question": "Where can I find a copy of the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) Profits/Losses Report?",
        "answer": "Please refer to theCPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) Profits/Losses Report.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-constitutes-offences-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "What constitutes \"offences\" under the CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "Manipulating investment transactions so that a member may siphon his CPF savings in cash thereby withdrawing the savings prematurely, is an offence under CPF Investment Scheme.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-are-manipulative-investment-transactions-detected",
        "question": "How are manipulative investment transactions detected?",
        "answer": "CPF Board continually monitors the trend of various CPF Investment Scheme transactions. The Singapore Exchange also monitors irregularities in share transactions. Transactions that look suspicious are referred to the Commercial Affairs Department for investigation.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-will-cpf-board-do-with-members-or-third-parties-who-are-found-to-have-conducted-manipulative-transactions",
        "question": "What will CPF Board do with members or third parties who are found to have conducted manipulative transactions?",
        "answer": "Under the law, CPF Board is empowered to recover CPF savings that is siphoned or withdrawn prematurely under such circumstances, with interest. The member could also be prohibited from making further withdrawals for a period of one year or more as the Board may determine, from the date of the contravention or from the date of the making of any false representations or furnishing of false information.The Board takes a serious view on any attempts to siphon CPF savings prematurely and will not hesitate to take legal action against CPF members and intermediaries or other parties who collaborate to do this. Third parties will be charged under the Penal Code. The Board may issue a Notice to Attend Court (NTA) to such persons. Please refer to theNTA form(PDF, 0.2MB) for a sample.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-i-be-charged-if-my-friend-conducts-manipulative-share-trading-using-my-cpf-and-trading-accounts-given-by-me-previously-without-my-knowing",
        "question": "Will I be charged if my friend conducts manipulative share trading using my CPF and trading accounts (given by me previously) without my knowing?",
        "answer": "This will depend on the outcome of investigations.  However, you should always protect your password and not allow other people to transact in your name without your knowledge or your approval.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-i-run-the-risk-of-unknowingly-breaching-cpf-laws-while-trading-or-investing-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "Will I run the risk of unknowingly breaching CPF laws while trading or investing under the CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "As long as your intention is to invest for the medium to long term, and you did not siphon out any CPF savings by receiving cash for your investment transactions whether through manipulated transaction prices or cash rebates, it is unlikely that you will breach the CPF laws for manipulative transactions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-will-happen-to-my-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-investments-if-i-did-not-open-a-cpf-investment-scheme-investment-account-in-time-for-the-transfer",
        "question": "What will happen to my Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme investments if I did not open a CPF Investment Scheme Investment Account in time for the transfer?",
        "answer": "As indicated in the National University of Singapore (NUS) letter to you, if you did not open a CPF Investment Scheme Investment Account by 27 December 2007, NUS is unable to transfer your Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme - Ordinary Account (ASPFAIS-OA) investment holdings and Part V insurance policies. As the Academic Staff Provident Fund (ASPF) scheme has closed down, your ASPFAIS Investment Account has been frozen and you will no longer be able to use your ASPF monies to transact under the ASPFAIS and service the premiums of your insurance policies bought under the ASPF Part V Scheme.You can still open a CPFIS Investment Account at any agent bank i.e. DBS, OCBC and UOB, and instruct NUS to transfer your ASPFAIS investments and Part V insurance policies to your newly-opened CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) Investment Accountafter 1 January 2008. However, this transfer will be effected only on a monthly basis and any payments to be made in the meantime, including insurance premiums, would have to be paid in cash.For your investments bought under Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme - Special Account (ASPFAIS-SA), NUS would have transferred them over to CPF Investment - Special Account (CPFIS-SA) as long as you have a CPF Account. No CPFIS Investment Account is needed for the transfer of investment holdings under the SA.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-i-receive-any-notifications-after-the-transfer-of-my-investments-from-my-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-to-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "Will I receive any notifications after the transfer of my investments from my Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme to CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "You will receive a letter from your agent bank, informing you of the details of the investments being transferred from your Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS) Investment Account to your CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) Investment Account. You will also receive a letter from National University of Singapore after the transfer.You can also view your Special Account (SA) investment holdings (combination of ASPFAIS-SA and CPFIS-SA) in your SA portfolio statement anytime using your Singpass viamy cpfdigital services.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/after-the-merger-of-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-aspfais-and-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-will-the-transfer-be-reflected-in-any-of-my-cpfis-statements",
        "question": "After the merger of Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS) and CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS), will the transfer be reflected in any of my CPFIS statements?",
        "answer": "The transfer will be reflected through the change tothe net amount withdrawn.  Your net amount withdrawn under the Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme - Ordinary Account (ASPFAIS-OA) will be merged with your net amount withdrawn under the CPF Investment Scheme - Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA).  A footnote will be permanently shown in your \"CPFIS Stock & Gold Limits Computation\" statement, informing you of the amount transferred from your ASPFAIS-OA. For your investments made under Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme -Special Account (ASPFAIS-SA), they will be transferred to your CPF Investment Scheme - Special Account (CPFIS-SA). You are able to view your combined investment holdings in your SA portfolio statement.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-will-happen-to-my-stock-gold-investment-limits-arising-from-the-merger-of-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-and-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "What will happen to my stock & gold investment limits arising from the merger of Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme and CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "Your Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme stock & gold investment limits will be merged with your CPF Investment Scheme stock & gold investment limits.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/arising-from-the-merger-of-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-and-cpf-investment-scheme-do-i-need-to-inform-my-broker-or-any-of-the-product-providers-of-my-new-cpf-investment-account-number",
        "question": "Arising from the merger of Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme and CPF Investment Scheme, do I need to inform my broker or any of the product providers of my new CPF Investment Account number?",
        "answer": "Your agent bank will inform the respective product providers, except stockbrokers, of your new Investment Account number. Agent banks would not be able to inform the stockbrokers on your behalf because agent banks do not know which stockbrokers you have trading accounts with.You will need to inform all your stockbrokers about your new CPF Investment Scheme Investment Account number. If your stockbrokers use the outdated investment account number, your CPF trades will fail and you will need to settle your trades using cash.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/after-the-transfer-of-my-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-investments-to-cpf-investment-scheme-what-will-happen-to-the-sale-proceeds-if-i-subsequently-sell-those-investments",
        "question": "After the transfer of my Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme investments to CPF Investment Scheme, what will happen to the sale proceeds if I subsequently sell those investments?",
        "answer": "All the sale proceeds will be refunded to your CPF Accounts. You can subsequently withdraw the monies subject to CPF withdrawal rules.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-all-my-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-aspfais-part-v-insurance-policies-be-transferred-to-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "Will all my Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS) Part V Insurance Policies be transferred to CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "All your Part V insurance policies will be transferred to your CPF Investment Scheme Investment Account with the agent bank.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-do-i-need-to-open-a-cpf-investment-scheme-investment-account-now-to-hold-my-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-aspfais-investment",
        "question": "Why do I need to open a CPF Investment Scheme Investment Account now to 'hold' my Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS) Investment?",
        "answer": "The Academic Staff Provident Fund (ASPF) Part V Scheme does not fall under the purview of the ASPF Investment Scheme. Under the ASPF Part V Scheme, the policies were bought under the name of National University Singapore (NUS). NUS had been paying the premiums directly to the insurance companies, after deducting the monies from members' ASPF Ordinary Accounts, without going through the agent banks. As the CPF Board does not have such a scheme, Part V insurance policies have to be transferred to the CPF Investment Scheme-Ordinary Account (CPFIS-OA) instead. Under the CPFIS-OA, you need to have a CPFIS Investment Account to hold your investments, including the transferred Part V insurance policies.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-use-my-cpf-monies-to-service-the-premiums-of-my-part-v-insurance-policy-under-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-aspfais",
        "question": "Can I use my CPF monies to service the premiums of my Part V Insurance Policy under Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS)?",
        "answer": "You can use your CPF monies in your Ordinary Account to service the future premiums of your policies (including endowment, whole life or rider policies, and regular premium policies).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-increase-or-decrease-the-premiums-to-be-paid-for-my-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-aspfais-part-v-insurance-policies",
        "question": "Can I increase or decrease the premiums to be paid for my Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS) Part V insurance policies?",
        "answer": "Academic Staff Provident Fund (ASPF) members are not allowed to make any changes to their Part V insurance policies that will cause anincreasein premiums with effect from 28 December 2006 (i.e. the date that National University Singapore issued the official \"Dissolution Notice\" to all its members). However, if the increase in premiums is due to attained age at renewal of the policies1, or conversion of the policies2, you can use your CPF monies to pay the higher premium.ASPF members can make any changes to their Part V insurance policies that will result in adecreasein premiums, as long as the insurance companies allow it.1When a member exceeds a certain age, he may have to pay a higher premium to renew his insurance policy. In such an instance, he can continue to use his CPF monies to pay the higher premiums.2A member's insurance policy contract may allow him to convert: (1) a rider to a new whole life policy, endowment policy or investment-linked insurance product (ILP); or (2) a whole life policy to an endowment policy or vice versa.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-take-a-policy-loan-on-my-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-aspfais-part-v-insurance-policy",
        "question": "Can I take a policy loan on my Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS) Part V insurance policy?",
        "answer": "Policy loans are not allowed for Part V insurance policies under the CPF Investment Scheme.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-pledge-my-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-aspfais-part-v-insurance-policy",
        "question": "Can I pledge my Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS) Part V insurance policy?",
        "answer": "Pledging of Part V insurance policies is not allowed under the CPF Investment Scheme.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-my-insurance-policy-continue-to-run-on-automatic-premium-loan-apl-and-or-extended-term-insurance-eti-after-the-transfer-to-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "Can my insurance policy continue to run on Automatic Premium Loan (APL) and/or Extended Term Insurance (ETI) after the transfer to CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "Automatic Premium Loan and Extended Term Insurance are allowed to continue after the transfer of your Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS) Part V insurance policy to CPF Investment Scheme.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-may-i-repay-the-automatic-premium-loan-apl-of-my-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-aspfais-part-v-insurance-policy",
        "question": "How may I repay the Automatic Premium Loan (APL) of my Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS) Part V insurance policy?",
        "answer": "You may repay the Automatic Premium Loan (APL) by paying cash to the insurance company directly. The cash balance in your CPF Investment Scheme Investment Account cannot be used to repay the APL.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-change-the-life-insured-under-my-part-v-insurance-policy-under-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-aspfais",
        "question": "Can I change the life insured under my Part V insurance policy under Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS)?",
        "answer": "The life insured must be the CPF member whose CPF savings are used to pay premiums.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-nominate-beneficiaries-to-the-proceeds-of-my-part-v-insurance-policy-under-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-aspfais",
        "question": "Can I nominate beneficiaries to the proceeds of my Part V insurance policy under Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS)?",
        "answer": "You may nominate beneficiaries as long as:No legal or equitable trust, including but not limited to statutory trusts under any written law, is created over the Part V insurance policy; andYour insurer allows you to do so.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-run-out-of-cpf-monies-to-pay-the-premiums-of-my-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-aspfais-part-v-insurance-policies-what-should-i-do",
        "question": "If I run out of CPF monies to pay the premiums of my Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS) Part V insurance policies, what should I do?",
        "answer": "You have the following options:Use cash to pay the premiums;Convert your Part V insurance policies to a paid-up mode1; orActivate the Automatic Premium Loan (APL)2or Extended Term Insurance (ETI)3feature(s) of your Part V insurance policies, if they have such features and if your insurance company allows you to do so.1Converting a policy to paid-up mode means that the policyholder will not need to pay premiums anymore. The sum assured of a paid-up policy is usually lower than that of the original policy. All supplementary riders attached will be terminated.2APL means that once the policy has accumulated sufficient cash value, if the policyholder is unable to pay the premium, he can borrow from the cash value. However, he is required to pay back the loan and compound interest. Once the loan plus compound interest exceeds the cash value of the policy, the policy will lapse.3ETI means that if the policyholder still wants the insurance protection but doesn't want to pay any more premiums, the existing cash value of his policy is treated as a single premium which is used to buy protection for future years. The number of years of protection he will get varies directly with the quantum of the cash value.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-the-proceeds-of-my-academic-staff-provident-fund-approved-investment-scheme-aspfais-part-v-insurance-policy-and-or-rider-be-distributed",
        "question": "How will the proceeds of my Academic Staff Provident Fund Approved Investment Scheme (ASPFAIS) Part V insurance policy and/or rider be distributed?",
        "answer": "In general, premiums of Part V insurance policies and riders (if any) paid using Academic Staff Provident Fund (ASPF) monies or cash prior to the transfer of the policy to CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) would be treated as though the premiums were paid using CPF monies. This is because Section 22 of the First Schedule of the National University Singapore (Corporatisation) Act provides that all premiums paid or deemed to have been paid with ASPF moneys in respect of ASPF Approved Investment Scheme Investments and Part V Assurances shall, on and after the dissolution date, be deemed to have been paid with CPF monies. Hence, the proportion of the proceeds (except death benefits) corresponding to such premiums would be refunded to your CPFIS Investment Account.However, the distribution of the full proceeds would depend on the premium payment mode after the transfer of the Part V policy to CPFIS. If, after the transfer of your policy to CPFIS:All the premiums of your Part V insurance policy and rider are paid using your CPF Ordinary Account savingsIf all the premiums of your Part V insurance policy and rider are paid using your CPF Ordinary Account savings, all proceeds would have to be refunded to your CPFIS Investment Account.Your CPF monies are exhausted and you then use cash to pay the premiums of the Part V insurance policy and riderIf your CPF monies are exhausted and you used cash to pay the premiums of the Part V insurance policy and rider, the proceeds would be pro-rated based on CPF savings vis-à-vis cash used to pay for the premiums after the transfer. The CPF portion and cash portion of the proceeds will be respectively refunded to your CPFIS Investment Account and to you.All the premiums of the Part V insurance policy and rider are paid using cashIf all the premiums of the Part V insurance policy and rider are paid using cash, the proportion of the proceeds corresponding to the premiums paid in cash after the transfer of the policy to CPFIS would be refunded to you in cash. The remaining proceeds would be refunded to your CPFIS Investment Account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-a-unit-trust-ut",
        "question": "What is a Unit Trust (UT)?",
        "answer": "Under the CPF Investment Scheme, you can invest in various Unit Trusts (UTs).A UT is an investment fund managed by a professional investment manager. It consists of investments in one or more of the three basic asset classes — cash, bonds and stocks. The combination of assets for each UT is determined by the investment objective of the particular UT.For information on the investment objectives of the various UTs, please contact the relevant investment managers. They will be able to provide you with the prospectus and fact sheet for the UT. Alternatively, you may visit theFund Singaporewebsite, which provides comprehensive information about UTs (and investment-linked life insurance products) available in Singapore.UTs offer investors a cost-efficient way to diversify or spread their investments. As the savings of individual investors are pooled into a UT, the UT can buy a greater variety of investments than is possible for an individual investor, thus making greater diversification possible. UTs may also allow you to access markets and investments which you may not be able to access through direct personal investment.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-an-investment-linked-insurance-policy-ilp",
        "question": "What is an Investment-Linked Insurance Policy (ILP)?",
        "answer": "Under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS), you can invest in various Investment-Linked Insurance Policies (ILPs).An ILP is made up of an insurance component coupled with an investment fund managed by a professional fund manager. Insurers usually set up two or more sub-funds for each ILP with differing investment objectives to suit the risk appetite of different types of policyholders. These underlying ILP sub-funds are similar to unit trusts. The allocation of premiums across these sub-funds may be fixed by the insurer or decided by the policyholder, depending on the structure of the ILP.The advantage of an ILP is that it effectively combines investments in a unit trust with purchase of insurance coverage. This is also its disadvantage. An investor might prefer a more flexible combination of insurance coverage and unit trust investment that is not offered by any of the ILPs included under the CPFIS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-i-know-whether-i-am-ready-to-invest",
        "question": "How will I know whether I am ready to invest?",
        "answer": "Once you have an understanding of the amount of risk you are comfortable with and of your investment time horizon, you are ready to make some investment decisions. The CPF Board has classified unit trusts, Investment-Linked Insurance Policies (ILPs) and Exchange Traded Funds (ETFs) permitted under CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) into the Risk Classification System.There is a wide range of investments available under the CPFIS to help you achieve your investment objectives and goals. The Risk Classification System is intended to help you determine which of these may be most appropriate for your investment circumstances.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-cpf-investment-scheme-risk-classification-system",
        "question": "What is the CPF Investment Scheme Risk Classification System?",
        "answer": "The Risk Classification System is developed to help you determine which of the various investment options may be most appropriate for your investment circumstances, through better understanding of the level and type of risk associated and your risk tolerance. It splits the investment risk associated withUnit Trust,Investment-Linked ProductsandExchange Traded Fundsincluded under CPF Investment Scheme Funds into two broad categories, \"Equity Risk\" and \"Focus Risk\".Equity RiskEquity Risk is related to exposure to the \"riskier\" types of investments in the Funds. The greater the proportion of assets invested in stocks, the higher the Equity Risk (i.e. higher risk category). Conversely, the greater the proportion of investments in bonds and cash, the lower the Equity Risk (i.e. lower risk category).Focus RiskFocus Risk reflects how focused the investments of the Funds are in particular geographical regions, foreign countries, foreign currencies, industries or individual companies. A Fund that invests in shares of companies from around the world would have lower Focus Risk (i.e. broadly diversified) than a fund that invests in shares of companies from one country only (i.e. narrowly diversified).The CPF Board does not give any consideration to nor has made any investigation on the investment objectives, financial situation or particular needs of the reader, any specific person or any group of persons. Accordingly, no warranty whatsoever is given and no liability whatsoever is accepted for any loss arising whether directly or indirectly as a result of the reader, any person or any group of persons acting on any information, opinion or statement expressed in these FAQs.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-an-exchange-traded-fund-etf",
        "question": "What is an Exchange Traded Fund (ETF)?",
        "answer": "Under the CPF Investment Scheme, you can invest in Exchange Traded Funds (ETFs).An ETF is an investment fund that is listed and traded on an Exchange. It is designed to track an index of markets and sectors or a fixed basket of stocks. It is bought and sold in the same way stocks are bought and sold on the Exchange.Investors can track the ETF's performance by monitoring the particular underlying index's performance.What are the benefits of an ETF?Exchange Traded Funds (ETFs) offer investors the benefit of diversification as investors need only to buy an ETF share to gain exposure to a diversified portfolio of domestic or international stocks. ETFs have low annual management fees and investors may buy or sell ETFs at prevailing market prices during trading hours in the Exchange. Investors are also able to see what stocks they are buying as ETFs offer transparency in its composition.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-should-i-invest-in-broadly-diversified-investments-and-when-should-i-invest-in-narrowly-focused-investments",
        "question": "When should I invest in broadly diversified investments and when should I invest in narrowly focused investments?",
        "answer": "After you have made your decision on how much to invest in the three basic types of investments: cash, bonds and stocks (i.e. based on the amount of equity risk you are comfortable with), for most CPF members, investing in broadly diversified investments within that equity risk category should generally help minimise investment risk. In other words, investing in broadly diversified investments should help reduce risk compared with investing in narrowly focused investments in the same equity risk category.However, there could also be reasons for investing in narrowly focused investments. You enjoy riskier investments, even when the odds are not necessarily in your favour. You are happy to take on the extra downside risk of not diversifying because of the potential for higher returns, although you are aware that a positive result is not guaranteed.For investments in the same equity risk category, it is reasonable to expect potential rewards over the long term to be very roughly the same for both a broadly diversified investment and a narrowly focused investment. However, you may want to accept the higher downside risk of a narrowly focused investment if you think that a narrowly focused investment may give better results in the short term.For example, if you are confident about the recovery of the Japanese economy in the short term, you may wish to invest in a Japan focused unit trust even though this unit trust has higher risk than a better diversified global equity unit trust.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-cpf-schemes-that-contribute-towards-asset-enhancement",
        "question": "What are the CPF schemes that contribute towards asset enhancement?",
        "answer": "The CPF Investment Scheme and the Special Discounted Shares Scheme contribute towards asset enhancement.You can refer to theFrequently Asked Questionsfor more details on the schemes.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-criteria-for-inclusion-of-shares-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "What are the criteria for inclusion of Shares under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "In considering the inclusion of shares under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS), the Board uses the following criteria:The shares are offered by a company that is incorporated in Singapore;The shares are listed on the Singapore Exchange (SGX) Mainboard as primary listing; (The shares are not new Catalist shares or shares transferred from SGX Main Board to Catalist except for former SESDAQ shares. Please refer to theFAQs on Transformation of SESDAQ to Catalistfor details.)The shares are traded in Singapore Dollars;The company allows Agent Banks to appoint all CPF shareholders of the company as proxies to attend and vote at meetings; andThe shares are not placed in the SGX watch-list.You can refer to theSGX websitefor the list of shares included under the CPFIS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-criteria-for-inclusion-of-property-fund-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "What are the criteria for inclusion of Property Fund under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "In considering the inclusion of Property Funds under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS), the Board uses the following criteria:The property fund is offered by a company that is incorporated in Singapore;The property fund is listed on the Singapore Exchange (SGX) Mainboard;The property fund is traded in Singapore Dollars;The company allows Agent Banks to appoint all CPF unitholders of the property fund as proxies to attend and vote at meetings.You can refer to theSGX websitefor the list of Property Funds included under the CPFIS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-criteria-for-inclusion-of-corporate-bonds-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "What are the criteria for inclusion of Corporate Bonds under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "In considering the inclusion of Corporate Bonds under the CPF Investment Scheme, the Board uses the following criteria:The bonds are issued by a company incorporated in Singapore;The bonds are listed on Singapore Exchange (SGX);The bonds are traded in Singapore dollars;The bonds are not offered to institutional investors or accredited investors and certain other persons only under Section 274 or 275 of the Securities and Futures Act;The bonds are not subject to trading restrictions in the secondary market;The bonds are rated at least A2 by Moody's, A by Standard and Poor's or A by Fitch; andProspectus, which comply with the Securities and Futures Act requirements for the bonds, are issued. For bonds which are exempted from the prospectus requirement, an information memorandum setting out the terms of the issue, the risks of investing in the bonds and other relevant information must be issued and made available to CPF members.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-criteria-for-inclusion-of-fixed-deposit-banks-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "What are the criteria for inclusion of Fixed Deposit Banks under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "In considering the inclusion of Fixed Deposit Banks under CPF Investment Scheme, the Board uses the following criteria:The bank must be locally incorporated with minimum capital funds of S$1.5 billion and good credit rating; orThe bank must be a subsidiary of a locally-incorporated bank which meets the criteria at (i). The bank must continue to be a subsidiary of the locally-incorporated bank; orIf the bank is a foreign bank, it must be accorded the Qualifying Full Bank privileges.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-criteria-for-inclusion-as-an-investment-administrator-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "What are the criteria for inclusion as an Investment Administrator under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "The Company must satisfy the following requirements in order to be eligible for inclusion under the CPFIS:The Company is licensed by MAS to provide financial advisory and/or investment managemaent services and has not been subjected to any disciplinary action by any regulatory authority in the last 5 years;The assets of investors are held under trust in a Nominee Account by a custodian and must be properly accounted for each investor;The Company has an existing distribution network, and able to offer different investment instruments allowed under CPFIS and investment products from different product providers to enable the Company to give independent advice to investors on products that best suit the investor, rather than push in-house products;The Company is able to provide value added services like independent financial advice, aggregation of investors' investment transactions, consolidated statements on value of investment holdings.The Company and its related group of companies must have a sound financial position.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-basic-investment-classes",
        "question": "What are the basic investment classes?",
        "answer": "Most investments fall into one of three basic asset classes — cash equivalents, bonds and stocks (also called shares or equities).Cash equivalentsCash equivalent (e.g. fixed deposit) investments are usually investments which have low risk of losing value but offer relatively low potential returns. Cash equivalents are typically used to hold money that will be needed in the near future or to hold assets temporarily while considering how to invest the assets for the long term.BondsBonds, often referred to as fixed income securities or debt securities, are loans to a corporation or government to finance its operations. A bond represents the corporation's or government's promise to repay at a specified date (at maturity) the amount borrowed from investors. The bond generally earns interest. Bonds also increase or decrease in value based on market conditions.Examples of bonds include government bonds and corporate bonds.StocksStocks represent ownership in a corporation. If you own stock in the XYZ Corporation, you are part owner of that company. Stocks may provide income in the form of dividends. Stock investments increase in value when the price of the share goes up and vice versa. Historically, over periods of several years or more, many types of stocks have increased in value. However, past performance is no guarantee of future results.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-criteria-for-inclusion-of-gold-exchange-traded-funds-etfs-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "What are the criteria for inclusion of Gold Exchange Traded Funds (ETFs) under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "In considering the inclusion of Gold Exchange Traded Funds (ETFs) under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS), the Board uses the following criteria:The gold ETF is backed by physical gold that meets the London Good Delivery Rules issued by London Bullion Market Association (or other equivalent globally accepted standards);The gold ETF is offered by a Singapore-incorporated company (for locally constituted gold ETF authorized by MAS) or through a local representative (for foreign gold ETF recognized by MAS);The gold ETF is listed on the SGX; andThe company allows Agent Banks to appoint all CPF unitholders of the gold ETF as proxies to attend and vote at meetings.What are the criteria for a local representative to offer foreign Gold ETF?The criteria for a local representative to offer foreign Gold ETF are:Must be a company incorporated in Singapore;Must provide CPF Board a copy of the representative agreement evidencing the appointment of the representative by the foreign gold ETF issuer or marketing agent;Provide evidence of indemnity mechanism (such as back-to-back agreement) put in place between the representative and the foreign issuer/marketing agent, allowing the representative to have recourse to the foreign issuer/marketing agent if the latter does not discharge its duties, obligations and responsibilities with due care and in good faith;Have good regulatory compliance record in Singapore; andHave sound financial position.Which Gold ETFs are included under the CPFIS?List of Gold ETFs included under the CPFIS:SPDR Gold Shares (under SGX trading name \"GLD US$\" and \"GLD SG$\")",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-there-revised-criteria-for-new-funds-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "Why is there revised criteria for new funds under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "Currently, new funds applying for admission under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) are evaluated based on a number of factors such as the capability of the fund managers, the investment philosophy of the fund, its key decision makers, the appropriateness and quality of its research and analysis, its portfolio construction and implementation, and its past performance.While this screening mechanism has helped to ensure a minimum standard for the funds under the CPFIS, more stringent criteria have been introduced so that funds under the CPFIS would better meet the objectives of CPFIS, which is to help members invest for the long-term for financial security in old age. In addition to setting a higher evaluation benchmark based on the current screening mechanism, the Board will also consider the funds' expense ratio. The latter will help lower the investment cost for members over the longer term. Funds submitted for admission under the CPFIS should also preferably have a performance track record of at least 3 years as this will allow the Board to better assess whether the funds are able to give consistently good performance against the benchmark.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-reasons-for-the-board-selecting-these-new-criteria-for-new-funds-which-wants-to-be-included-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "What are the reasons for the Board selecting these new criteria for new funds which wants to be included under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "The new criteria cover issues that the Board is most concerned with, such as quality, consistency of performance relative to peer group and investment costs.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-proportion-of-funds-applying-for-admission-into-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-has-been-successful-what-is-the-target-under-the-revised-criteria",
        "question": "What proportion of funds applying for admission into CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) has been successful? What is the target under the revised criteria?",
        "answer": "Fund managers would generally assess the quality of their funds using the published CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) evaluation criteria before applying for inclusion under CPFIS. Thus far, funds within the top 50 percentile in their global peer group1have been successful in their application for admission into CPFIS, and the majority of funds that have applied for admission into CPFIS have been admitted.New funds will need to meet a higher criterion - i.e. they must be among the top 25 percentile of funds. Going forward, we do not expect a significant change in the success rate of application as managers would continue to assess the quality of their funds against the CPFIS evaluation criteria before application.1This refers to comparison of funds of similar asset class/strategy on a world-wide basis.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-the-funds-that-have-already-submitted-their-applications-for-inclusion-under-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-be-affected-by-the-revised-criteria",
        "question": "Will the funds that have already submitted their applications for inclusion under CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) be affected by the revised criteria?",
        "answer": "The revised criteria will only apply to fund applications received by the Board from 1 February 2006 onwards.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-different-evaluation-factors-for-admission-into-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-under-the-old-and-new-entry-criteria",
        "question": "What are the different evaluation factors for admission into CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) under the old and new entry criteria?",
        "answer": "New funds will continue to be evaluated according to existing evaluation factors. However, new funds will have to meet a higher benchmark, and henceforth funds admitted to CPF Investment Scheme will be among the top 25 percentile of funds. In addition, new funds will have to meet an expense ratio criterion pegged at the median of all funds in the same risk class. New funds should preferably also have a track record of at least 3-years.Supplementary InformationThe specific aspects of the investment process that are looked at during the evaluation process for Unit Trusts and Investment-Linked Insurance Policies include the following:Investment Philosophy;Key Decision Makers;Research and Analysis;Portfolio Construction;Implementation/Trading; andPast Performance.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-an-expense-ratio",
        "question": "What is an expense ratio?",
        "answer": "The expense ratio refers to the ongoing costs of operating a fund by fund managers/insurers expressed as a percentage of the fund's average net assets. Operating costs include investment management fees, trustee fees, and audit fees, etc.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-new-total-expense-ratio-ter-caps",
        "question": "What are the new Total Expense Ratio (TER) caps?",
        "answer": "The new Total Expense Ratio1(TER) caps are as follows:Risk CategoriesNew TER Caps (%)Higher Risk1.75Medium to High Risk1.55Low to Medium Risk0.95Lower Risk0.35For CPF Investment Scheme List A funds, fund managers/insurers are not allowed to charge expenses more than the TER caps.1Guidelines on the computation of expense ratio can be found in theInvestment Management Association of Singapore (IMAS) website.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-cpf-board-reducing-the-total-expense-ratio-ter-caps",
        "question": "Why is CPF Board reducing the Total Expense Ratio (TER) caps?",
        "answer": "Reducing the Total Expense Ratio caps is part of CPF Board's continuous efforts to lower the cost of investing under the CPF Investment Scheme. This would help enhance returns, hence enable CPF members who have invested in the fund to accumulate their retirement savings faster.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-cpf-investors-benefit-from-the-reduced-total-expense-ratio-ter-caps",
        "question": "How will CPF investors benefit from the reduced Total Expense Ratio (TER) caps?",
        "answer": "Expenses on investment have a significant impact on returns. Hence, reducing Total Expense Ratio caps will lower the expenses that CPF investors have to bear and increase a fund's per-unit net asset value. This will enable CPF members who have invested in the fund to accumulate their retirement savings faster.The following example illustrates the impact of expense ratio:Amount invested: $10,000 over 30 years, with annual return of 5%1Total expense ratio of the Fund decreases from 1.95% to 1.75%Savings =$1,475(or 6% more in his retirement savings)Expense Ratio of 1.95%Expense Ratio of 1.75%Net investment value after 30 years$24,629$26,104Savings$1,4751Assumes no front end load",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-actions-do-i-as-a-cpfis-investor-need-to-take-due-to-reduction-in-total-expense-ratio-caps",
        "question": "What actions do I (as a CPFIS investor) need to take due to reduction in Total Expense Ratio caps?",
        "answer": "You do not have to take any action unless the fund(s) you have invested in cannot comply with the reduced Total Expense Ratio (TER) caps.In which case, the relevant parties (i.e. Fund Management Companies/insurers/investment administrators) will notify you by letters. As existing funds which are unable to comply with the new TER caps from 2016 will be downgraded to List B and will not be allowed to take innewCPF monies from then, you will be given the following options by the relevant parties:Free switches to other funds included under CPF Investment Scheme within a specified period from the date of the letter (around one month)Redeem the unitsContinue to remain invested in these funds (if you choose this option, no further action is required from you)Note: Cash investors would not be affected.For info - List of funds will be updated when necessary.List A and B unit trusts(PDF, 0.2MB)List A and B Investment Link Products (ILPs) Sub-funds(PDF, 0.1MB)",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-there-still-be-a-range-of-funds-for-cpf-investors-to-choose-from",
        "question": "Will there still be a range of funds for CPF investors to choose from?",
        "answer": "The lowering of the Total Expense Ratio (TER) caps would not have significant impact on the choices of investment under the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS). The Board will work with industry players towards complying with the new TER caps, to give CPF members continued choice in terms of the range of funds available under the CPFIS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-are-the-new-total-expense-ratio-ter-caps-determined",
        "question": "How are the new Total Expense Ratio (TER) caps determined?",
        "answer": "The new Total Expense Ratio (TER) caps are determined based on the FY2012medianTERs (for the relevant risk categories) of CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) List A funds, and taking into account industry feedback. Median TERs were also used in 2008 when CPF Board first implemented TER caps for funds under the CPFIS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/is-the-3-years-track-record-for-new-funds-applied-at-the-fund-level-or-based-on-the-experience-of-fund-management-companies",
        "question": "Is the 3 years track record for new funds applied at the fund level or based on the experience of Fund Management Companies?",
        "answer": "The preference for a 3 year performance track record is generally applied at the fund level. Fund managers should preferably show a minimum track record so that they can be better assessed on their ability whether they are able to give consistently good performance against the benchmark for the specific fund they manage.In the case of indexed funds or Exchange Traded Funds, the 3 year track record is applied differently. The focus will be on the fund management company's technology or systems and processes that they have established to perform the rebalancing functions to track indexes closely1and their ability to consistently maintain a low cost structure for the index funds they have under management.1Low tracking error",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-admission-criteria-for-funds",
        "question": "What is the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) admission criteria for funds?",
        "answer": "The admission criteria for the CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) funds are:Top quartile of global peer groupTotal Expense Ratio lower than the median of CPFIS funds in respective risk class0% sales chargePreferably track record of 3 yearsThese criteria aims to raise the quality and lower cost of investments for funds included under the CPFIS.You can refer to thereportson the performance of the CPFIS funds.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-does-cpf-board-currently-assess-whether-funds-admitted-are-still-suitable-to-remain-in-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis",
        "question": "How does CPF Board currently assess whether funds admitted are still suitable to remain in CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)?",
        "answer": "When determining if a product is suitable to be under CPF Investment Scheme, the emphasis so far has been on past performance and the competency of its investment professionals. Re-evaluation will be required for Fund Management Companies/Funds that have undergone material changes in the organisational structure, fund structure or management team.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-the-new-admission-criteria-be-applied-to-existing-funds-under-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "Will the new admission criteria be applied to existing funds under CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "The new criteria will apply to existing funds from 1 January 2011. To help members make better informed investment decisions, the Board will, in due course, step up its member education efforts and also avail relevant information on the performance and expense ratios of existing funds.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-can-members-do-if-the-funds-in-which-they-have-already-invested-do-not-meet-the-new-standards-set-by-the-board-following-re-evaluation",
        "question": "What can members do if the funds in which they have already invested do not meet the new standards set by the Board following re-evaluation?",
        "answer": "Members who have already invested in such funds can continue to remain invested in the funds, or consider switching to other funds or selling out of the funds if the funds no longer meet their investment objective.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-trailer-fees",
        "question": "What are trailer fees?",
        "answer": "Trailer fees are fees payable to distributors (including financial advisors) who sell the fund to the investors. The trailer fees are generally paid out from a fund’s annual management fees (which is part of the total expense ratio1) by the fund manager or product provider to distributors. As such, trailer fees arenot additional costto end investors.1The expense ratio refers to the ongoing costs of operating a fund by fund managers/insurers expressed as a percentage of the fund's average net assets. Operating costs include investment management fees, trustee fees, and audit fees, etc.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-is-cpf-board-enhancing-the-disclosure-of-trailer-fees",
        "question": "How is CPF Board enhancing the disclosure of trailer fees?",
        "answer": "Currently, fund managers pay trailer fees to their distributors who sell their funds to investors. Fund Managers disclose the trailer fees range in their products’ sales documents which distributors (including financial advisors) generally relied upon when selling their products to investors. Such trailer fees range could be too wide to be meaningful to investors. As such, more trailer fees information i.e. the median would be more useful to investors.From 1 October 2022, Fund Management Companies (FMCs), Insurers, Investment Administrators (IAs), financial advisors and insurance agents are required to disclose trailer fees information (i.e. range and median) in their CPFIS products’ sales documents in order to help CPF investors make informed decision on their investment purchase.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-would-i-benefit-from-the-enhanced-disclosure-of-trailer-fees",
        "question": "How would I benefit from the enhanced disclosure of trailer fees?",
        "answer": "You would be able to understand how much trailer fees that your insurance agents and financial advisors receive.The trailer fees information would be presented to you in the sales documents e.g. the funds’ Product Highlight Sheet, prospectus, Policy Illustration for Investment-linked Products (ILPs), subscription forms by your financial advisors.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-all-cpf-investment-scheme-cpfis-included-unit-trusts-ilp-sub-funds-charge-trailer-fees",
        "question": "Do all CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS)-included Unit Trusts/ILP sub-funds charge trailer fees?",
        "answer": "Trailer fees is subjected to the business agreements between product providers and their distributors (including financial advisors). Some funds may not have trailer fees payable to distributors.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-need-to-pay-additional-fees-due-to-trailer-fees-disclosure-by-my-product-service-providers-is-there-any-action-required-of-me-as-a-cpfis-investor",
        "question": "Do I need to pay additional fees due to trailer fees disclosure by my product/service providers? Is there any action required of me (as a CPFIS investor)?",
        "answer": "You do not need to pay any additional fees. No action is required from you (as a CPFIS investor) given that trailer fees are paid by the fund manager or product provider to distributors.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-can-i-approach-if-i-want-to-know-more-on-the-trailer-fees-of-the-cpf-investment-scheme-products",
        "question": "Who can I approach if I want to know more on the trailer fees of the CPF Investment Scheme products?",
        "answer": "You can approach your product/service provider or financial advisors for more information on trailer fees.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-rationale-of-harmonising-the-criteria-for-new-and-existing-funds-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "What is the rationale of harmonising the criteria for new and existing funds under the CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "CPF Board (\"CPFB\") has, since 2006, taken measures to improve the quality of funds in CPF Investment Scheme (CPFIS) and lower the costs of investing. From 1 February 2006, new Unit Trusts and Investment-Linked Products (collectively known as \"funds\") must meet the stricter criteria1before being admitted into CPFIS2. From 1 January 2011, all funds in the CPFIS must meet the stricter criteria to continue to take in new CPF monies. This is part of CPFB's ongoing efforts to lower cost and improve the quality of CPFIS funds to benefit CPF members who seek to invest their CPF savings for higher returns.1(i) Top quartile of global peer group (ii) Total Expense Ratio lower than the median of CPFIS funds in respective risk class (iii) Sales charge not exceeding 3% and (iv) Preferably track record of 3 years.2Prior to 1 February 2006, the admission criterion was top 50 percentile of global peer group.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-this-harmonisation-affect-the-funds-included-under-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "How will this harmonisation affect the funds included under CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "All CPF Investment Scheme funds that have not met the stricter admission criteria and that wish to be able to take in new CPF monies from 1 January 2011 need to be re-evaluated.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-the-re-evaluation-affect-the-funds-that-i-am-holding-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme",
        "question": "How will the re-evaluation affect the funds that I am holding under the CPF Investment Scheme?",
        "answer": "Re-evaluation will not affect the funds that you are holding. However if by  December 2010, the funds which you are holding do not meet the stricter criteria, or if your Fund Management Company (FMC) / insurer chooses not to have the funds re-evaluated, you will not be able to purchase more units of such funds with your CPF monies.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/is-it-compulsory-to-keep-switching-funds-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-if-the-funds-which-i-am-holding-do-not-meet-the-stricter-criteria",
        "question": "Is it compulsory to keep switching funds under the CPF Investment Scheme if the funds which I am holding do not meet the stricter criteria?",
        "answer": "You can opt to hold on to your existing funds without switching.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/if-i-hold-a-fund-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-that-does-not-meet-the-stricter-criteria-when-must-i-exercise-the-switching-option",
        "question": "If I hold a fund under the CPF Investment Scheme that does not meet the stricter criteria, when must I exercise the switching option?",
        "answer": "Funds that are unable to meet the stricter criteria can only take in new CPF monies till December 2010, and you will be given up till 30 June 2011 to exercise the switching option.In addition, a fund may decide to cease taking in new CPF monies earlier. If this happens, you have to exercise the switching option within the timeframe stipulated by the Fund Management Company/insurer in its communication letter to you.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-i-know-whether-the-funds-that-i-am-holding-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-do-not-meet-the-stricter-criteria-by-december-2010",
        "question": "How will I know whether the funds that I am holding under the CPF Investment Scheme do not meet the stricter criteria by December 2010?",
        "answer": "If the funds do not meet the stricter criteria by December 2010, the respective Fund Management Company(FMC)/insurer will be required to inform their CPF clients in writing, and to offer their clients three options, by December 2010.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-do-if-the-funds-that-i-am-holding-under-the-cpf-investment-scheme-do-not-meet-the-stricter-criteria-by-december-2010",
        "question": "What should I do if the funds that I am holding under the CPF Investment Scheme do not meet the stricter criteria by December 2010?",
        "answer": "You will be given options by the Fund Management Companies (FMCs) or insurers to hold, redeem or switch your units, for free, into other CPF Investment Scheme funds that are eligible to take in new CPF monies from 1 January 2011. If you decide to switch funds, please consider whether the new funds match your investment objective andrisk profile(PDF, 0.2MB).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-special-discounted-shares-scheme",
        "question": "What is Special Discounted Shares Scheme?",
        "answer": "The Special Discounted Share Scheme is part of the Government's asset enhancement programme to make Singapore a share-owning society, thus giving Singaporeans a greater stake in the country.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/where-can-i-find-more-information-about-discounted-singtel-shares",
        "question": "Where can I find more information about discounted Singtel shares?",
        "answer": "You can refer to theSingtel websitefor more information.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/where-can-i-check-the-number-of-discounted-singtel-shares-in-my-cpf-account",
        "question": "Where can I check the number of discounted Singtel shares in my CPF account?",
        "answer": "You can login tomy cpfOnline Serviceswith your Singpass and check the \"Discounted Singtel shares\" section in the Investment dashboard.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-my-current-discounted-singtel-shareholdings-different-from-the-quantity-i-purchased-in-1993-and-or-1996-even-though-i-did-not-sell-the-shares",
        "question": "Why are my current discounted Singtel shareholdings different from the quantity I purchased in 1993 and/or 1996 even though I did not sell the shares?",
        "answer": "Singtel performed capital reductions on 1 September 2004 and 1 September 2006. In the 2004 capital reduction, Singtel cancelled 1 in every 14 of its shares, with the resultant shareholding rounded-up to the nearest 10 shares, where applicable. Singtel then reimbursed you S$2.36 for each cancelled share. In the 2006 capital reduction, Singtel cancelled 1 in every 20 of its shares, with the resultant shareholding rounded-up to the nearest 10 shares, where applicable. Singtel reimbursed you $2.74 for each cancelled share. Both reimbursements were credited into your CPF Ordinary Account. You were then informed, in writing, of the capital reductions in September 2004 and September 2006.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-my-discounted-singtel-shares-not-reflected-in-my-central-depository-cdp-statement",
        "question": "Why are my discounted Singtel shares not reflected in my Central Depository (CDP) statement?",
        "answer": "Your discounted Singtel shares are held by the Board on your behalf. Your discounted Singtel shares would therefore be reflected in your CPF Statement of Account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-would-i-know-if-i-would-make-a-gain-or-loss-if-i-were-to-sell-my-discounted-singtel-shares-now",
        "question": "How would I know if I would make a gain or loss if I were to sell my discounted Singtel shares now?",
        "answer": "For sale of discounted Singtel shares, you can use theweighted average cost (WAC) methodto determine whether you would make a gain or loss.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-dividends-rates-declared-by-singtel-for-the-discounted-singtel-shares-to-date",
        "question": "What are the dividends rates declared by Singtel for the discounted Singtel shares to-date?",
        "answer": "You may refer toSingtel websiteor ourdividend tablefor rates declared by Singtel.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/where-can-i-find-more-information-on-singtel-s-scrip-dividend-scheme-as-announced-by-singtel-on-12-november-2020",
        "question": "Where can I find more information on Singtel's Scrip Dividend Scheme, as announced by Singtel on 12 November 2020?",
        "answer": "For financial year ending 31 March 2021, Singtel has paid interim dividend at dividend rate of $0.051 per share. The scrip shares were offered at $2.422 per share. For more information, please visit theSingtel website.If you had opted for scrip shares, the number of scrip shares issued to you, in respect of your shareholdings as at 27 November 2020 (‘Record Date’), was calculated as follows:Number of scrip shares issued =Number of discounted Singtel shares (at Record Date) x Dividend rateIssue price of scrip share",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/are-the-dividends-received-from-the-discounted-singtel-shares-subject-to-tax",
        "question": "Are the dividends received from the discounted Singtel shares subject to tax?",
        "answer": "Dividends received from your discounted Singtel shares are not taxable.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-transfer-my-discounted-singtel-shares-to-another-person",
        "question": "Can I transfer my discounted Singtel shares to another person?",
        "answer": "Your discounted Singtel shares can only be transferred into a CDP securities account under your name after you have set aside the Full Retirement Sum (FRS) in your Retirement Account at age 55.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-happens-when-i-sell-my-discounted-singtel-shares",
        "question": "What happens when I sell my discounted Singtel shares?",
        "answer": "When you sell your discounted Singtel shares, the sale proceeds will be refunded to your CPF Ordinary Account and form part of your CPF savings.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-to-sell-my-discounted-singtel-shares",
        "question": "How to sell my discounted Singtel shares?",
        "answer": "There are three ways to sell your discounted Singtel shares:via Online Sale FacilityLog in to my cpf Online Services with your Singpass. Select my cpf > My dashboards > Investment, look under “Discounted Singtel Shares” section and click on “Sell your shares”.You will be directed to POEMS - an online trading platform managed by Phillip Securities Pte Ltd (‘Phillip Securities’). Once you have submitted your online instruction, Phillip Securities will sell your discounted Singtel shares. The proceeds of sale will be refunded to your CPF Ordinary Account within 6 working days.You can find out more information on selling your discounted Singtel shares through the Online Sale Facility in thisdocument.via Singapore Post OfficeVisit anySingapore Post Offices(‘SingPost’). For SingPost to process your instruction, you need to sell a minimum quantity of 10 shares. You would also need to produce the following documents at SingPost:Your identity card; andThe latest copy of your CPF Statement of Account, which indicates the number of discounted Singtel shares held in your CPF account.If you are unable to sell your discounted Singtel shares in person, you may authorise a third party to sell the shares on your behalf. Your authorised person must bring the following documents to SingPost:A completed and signed ‘Account Opening and Authorisation for The Sale of STA & ST2 Shares Form’. All sections including ‘Third Party Authorisation’ are to be completed. This application form is available at all SingPost branches;Identity cards belonging to both authorised person and you; andThe latest copy of your CPF Statement of Account, which indicates the number of discounted Singtel shares held in your CPF account.You can find out more information on selling your discounted Singtel shares through SingPost in thisdocument.via Singapore Exchange (SGX) Retail BrokerPlease approach your broker if you have a trading account with them. If you do not have a trading account, you can open one with anySGX broking firm.Internet trading platforms for most brokers do not cater for sale of discounted Singtel shares. Please check with your broker before selling your discounted Singtel shares.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-withdraw-my-sale-proceeds-or-investment-profits-from-my-discounted-singtel-shares",
        "question": "Can I withdraw my sale proceeds or investment profits from my discounted Singtel shares?",
        "answer": "The sale proceeds and investment profits form part of your CPF savings. You can apply to withdraw them from age 55 if you meet thewithdrawal conditions.For more information on how you can withdraw your CPF retirement savings, please refer to thisFAQ.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-withdraw-my-discounted-singtel-shares-when-i-reach-55-years-old",
        "question": "Can I withdraw my discounted Singtel shares when I reach 55 years old?",
        "answer": "You are required to set aside the Full Retirement Sum (FRS) in your Retirement Account (RA), before you can withdraw your discounted Singtel shares. The FRS can be set aside fully with cash, or with cash (i.e. at least the Basic Retirement Sum) and property.Have you met your CPF withdrawal conditions?YesLog in tomy cpf Online Serviceswith your Singpass > Select my cpf > My dashboards > Investment, look under “Discounted Singtel Shares” section and click on “Withdraw your shares”.We will process your application within 15 working days once we receive your application.After your discounted Singtel shares have been transferred to your CDP securities account, they will no longer be protected from any claims by your creditors and/or the Official Assignee.NoYou can only withdraw your discounted Singtel shares if you have set aside the Full Retirement Sum (FRS) in your Retirement Account at age 55. However, you can sell your discounted Singtel shares, in which the sale proceeds will be credited into your CPF Ordinary Account.To sell, please log in tomy cpf Online Serviceswith your Singpass > Select my cpf > My dashboards > Investment, look under “Discounted Singtel Shares” section and click on “Sell your shares”.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-my-discounted-singtel-shares-be-sold-or-liquidated-when-i-apply-to-withdraw-my-discounted-singtel-shares-upon-meeting-cpf-withdrawal-conditions",
        "question": "Will my discounted Singtel shares be sold or liquidated when I apply to withdraw my discounted Singtel shares upon meeting CPF withdrawal conditions?",
        "answer": "Withdrawing your discounted Singtel shares will not result in liquidation of your shares. It is a request to the Board to transfer the discounted Singtel shares to your CDP securities account. Once the shares have been transferred, you will receive a statement from CDP and the Board.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-service-standards-for-processing-applications-relating-to-discounted-singtel-shares",
        "question": "What are the service standards for processing applications relating to discounted Singtel shares?",
        "answer": "Please refer to the table for our service standards for processing applications relating to discounted Singtel shares.ServiceNormal Processing TimeWithdraw My Discounted Singtel Shares Upon Meeting CPF Withdrawal ConditionsWithin 15 working days(this includes the Central Depository's (CDP) processing time)Transfer Discounted Singtel Shares(Division of CPF-related Matrimonial Assets)Within 15 working days** Transferee must have a CPF investment account with agent bank",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-transfer-my-discounted-singtel-shares-for-division-of-matrimonial-assets",
        "question": "How can I transfer my discounted Singtel shares for division of matrimonial assets?",
        "answer": "To obtain an application form to transfer your discounted Singtel shares for division of matrimonial assets, pleasewrite to us.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/where-can-i-see-my-special-dividend-as-declared-by-singtel-on-10-november-2022",
        "question": "Where can I see my special dividend as declared by Singtel on 10 November 2022?",
        "answer": "Singtel declared a special dividend of $0.05 per share for financial year ending 31 March 2023. According to Singtel, the special dividend will be paid in tranches. The first S$0.025 will be paid along with the interim dividend in December 2022, while the remaining S$0.025 will be paid out together with Singtel’s final dividend in August 2023. The special dividend in both tranches is payable based on their respective book closure dates. For more information on Singtel’s special dividend, you can refer toSingtel website.If you have discounted Singtel shares in your CPF account during these periods, you will receive Singtel’s special dividend along with your interim/final dividend in your Ordinary Account. Please check your CPF statement.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-singtel-dividends-did-i-receive-in-2022",
        "question": "How much Singtel dividends did I receive in 2022?",
        "answer": "Singtel declared and paid dividends in January, August and December. If you had discounted Singtel shares in your CPF account during these periods, you would have received Singtel’s dividends in your Ordinary Account. Please check your CPF statement.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-did-singtel-pay-interim-dividend-in-december-2022",
        "question": "Why did Singtel pay interim dividend in December 2022?",
        "answer": "For financial year ending 31 March 2023, Singtel has decided to pay interim dividend earlier in December, instead of the following January. From 2023 onwards, Singtel will declare and pay dividends in August and December. For more information on Singtel’s dividend payments, you can refer toSingtel website.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-singtel-s-dividend-rate-s-not-reflected-in-my-yearly-statement-of-account",
        "question": "Why is Singtel's dividend rate(s) not reflected in my Yearly Statement of Account?",
        "answer": "You can find Singtel’s dividend rates inSingtel websiteor thedividend tableon CPF website. If you have discounted Singtel shares in your CPF account, you would have received Singtel’s dividends in your Ordinary Account. Please check your CPF statement.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/where-can-i-find-details-of-all-singtel-s-dividends-paid-in-2022",
        "question": "Where can I find details of all Singtel's dividends paid in 2022?",
        "answer": "You can find Singtel’s dividend rates inSingtel websiteor thedividend tableon CPF website. If you have discounted Singtel shares in your CPF account, you would have received Singtel’s dividends in your Ordinary Account. Please check your Ordinary Account transaction history for dividend(s) received.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-workfare-income-supplement-scheme",
        "question": "What is the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme?",
        "answer": "The Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme was introduced in 2007 as a permanent feature of Singapore's social security system. The support is targeted at lower-wage Singaporean workers whose earnings are in the bottom 20% of the working population, with some support to those slightly above, and is reviewed regularly to ensure that it meets the needs of Singaporeans.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/am-i-eligible-for-the-workfare-income-supplement-wis-scheme",
        "question": "Am I eligible for the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme?",
        "answer": "You will be eligible for the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme if you:i. are a Singapore Citizen;ii. are at least 30 years old or older on 31 December of the Work Year or are a person with disability of any age;iii. earn a gross monthly income1of at least $5002, but not more than $2,500 for the month worked and in the past 12 months3(average gross monthly income) as an employee; or have an average monthly income of at least $500, but not more than $2,500 as a Self-Employed Person (SEP).If you are an SEP, you are also required to declare your Net Trade Income (NTI) and make your MediSave contributions to be eligible for WIS.iv. live in a property with an annual value4of $21,000 and below from Work Year 2024 ($13,000 and below for WY2023), assessed as at 31 December of the preceding year;v. own not more than one property; andvi. if you are married,you and your spouse together own not more than one property; andthe assessable income of your spouse does not exceed $70,000 for the preceding Year of Assessment.For work done in Work Year 2022 and earlier:You will be eligible for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme if you:i. are a Singapore Citizen;ii. are at least 35 years old as of 31 December of the Work Year;iii. and earned a gross monthly income1of not more than $2,300 for the month worked and in the past 12 months3(average gross monthly income) as an employee; or had an average monthly income of not more than $2,300 as a Self-Employed Person (SEP).If you are an SEP, you are also required to declare your Net Trade Income (NTI) and make your MediSave contributions to be eligible for WIS.iv. live in a property with an annual value4of $13,000 and below, assessed as at 31 December of the previous year;v. own not more than one property; andvi. if you are married;you and your spouse together own not more than one property; andthe assessable income of your spouse does not exceeds $70,000 for the previous Year of Assessment.Please refer to thislinkto find out your WIS eligibility status. WIS will be enhanced in 2025. For the updated eligibility criteria from 2025, please refer to our FAQshere.1Includes basic salary and extra wages such as overtime pay, commissions and bonuses2Persons with disabilities, workers who qualify for ComCare Short-to-Medium-Term Assistance and caregivers of care recipients (generally include caregivers residing with care recipients who are medically certified to have permanent moderate to severe disabilities) will qualify for concessionary WIS, even if they earn less than $500. Eligible caregivers have started receiving concessionary WIS for Work Year 2023 onwards.3Defined as income earned in the past 12-month period ÷ Total number of months worked in the past 12-month period4Annual value is the estimated gross annual rent of the property if it were to be rented out, excluding furniture, furnishings and maintenance fees. It is determined based on estimated market rentals of similar or comparable properties.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-are-the-enhancements-to-the-workfare-income-supplement-wis-from-2025-onwards",
        "question": "What are the enhancements to the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) from 2025 onwards?",
        "answer": "The enhancements to WIS, which will take effect from 2025 onwards, are as follows:i.Qualifying monthly wage cap raised from $2,500 to $3,0001. This takes into account wage growth of Singaporeans.ii.Higher annual WIS payments of up to $4,900. Payments depend on age and wages, and have been enhanced across all age bands. Eligible employees can receive up to $4,900 per year in payments, compared to $4,200 per year today (refer to table below). Older workers and all persons with disabilities will continue to receive the highest payments. The payments for self-employed persons are set at two-thirds of employee payments and will be correspondingly increased.1In addition, the worker must earn an average gross monthly wage of not more than $3,000 in the past 12 months.Maximum Annual Workfare Payment for Employees*Age Band(For Work Done from 1 Jan 2023)(For Work Done from 1 Jan 2025)30-34$2,100$2,45035-44$3,000$3,50045-59$3,600$4,20060 & above$4,200$4,900All persons with disabilities$4,200$4,900* The payment amounts depend on actual wages. The payments for self-employed persons are set at two-thirds of employee payments.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-do-i-need-to-do-to-receive-workfare-income-supplement-wis",
        "question": "What do I need to do to receive Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)?",
        "answer": "If you are an employee, you do not need to do anything. Your eligibility for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) will be automatically assessed based on the CPF contributions* made by your employer.If you are a Self-Employed Person (SEP), you will need to:• declare your Net Trade Income (NTI) from Work Year 2023 to the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS). If you receive a notification (via letter/form/SMS) to file tax from IRAS, or you meet the requirement to file tax (i.e. NTI above $6,000 and/or Total Income above $22,000), please complete and submit the tax return to IRAS directly. The income tax filing period is from 1 March to 18 April annually.If you do not receive a notification from IRAS or do not meet the requirement to file tax, you will need to declare your self-employed NTI to IRAS viamyTax Portalwhich will be available from 1 March to 31 October annually for taxpayers to e-File tax returns; and• make the full required MediSave contributions:If your NTI is more than $6,000You are required to make MediSave contribution to fulfil the liability under theSelf-Employed Scheme (SES). Your MediSave contribution is due 30 days from the date of issuance of the Notice of Computation (NOC) from IRAS or Notice of Contribution from CPF Board.  Estimate how much MediSave to contribute to receive WIS by using theWIS calculatorfor SEPs.If your NTI is $6,000 or lessYou are not required to pay MediSave contribution under SES. However, in order to qualify for WIS, you will be required to make MediSave contributions within 2 years after the year you worked. E.g. if you worked in 2024, you will need to make the Medisave contributions by 31 December 2026. Please see the following for the required amount of MediSave contribution to qualify for WIS if your NTI is $6,000 or less, according to your age in the year you worked:30 to 34 years35 to 44 years45 to 49 years50 years and above$240$270$300$315If you have declared your income to IRAS and have yet to receive your NOC from IRAS by 31 January two years after the WY (e.g. by 31 January 2025 for WY2023), you maywrite to ususing your Singpass for the Board to assess your eligibility for WIS. Do note that you must also contribute to your MediSave by the specified timelines to receive WIS.*Under the CPF Act, employers must contribute CPF if their employees earn more than $50 a month, regardless of whether the employee is employed on a permanent, part-time, contract or casual basis. If your employer is not contributing CPF on your behalf, please approach your employer to clarify on the discrepancies. If your employer does not provide you with a satisfactory response, you can lodge a report with CPF Board.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-workfare-income-supplement-wis-will-i-get",
        "question": "How much Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) will I get?",
        "answer": "The Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) depends on your age and wages. You may use the onlineWIS calculatorto estimate the amount of WIS you will receive.If you are employedAgeMaximum Annual WIS2022From 202330-34Not applicable$2,10035-44$1,700$3,00045-54$2,500$3,60055-59$3,30060 and above$4,000$4,200Persons with disabilities will receive the same amount as those who are aged 60 and above.If you are self-employedAgeMaximum Annual WIS2022From 202330-34Not applicable$1,40035-44$1,133$2,00045-54$1,667$2,40055-59$2,20060 and above$2,667$2,800Persons with disabilities will receive the same amount as those who are aged 60 and above.WIS will be enhanced in 2025. For the enhanced WIS payment quanta, please refer to our FAQshere.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-cash-and-cpf-contributions-will-i-receive-from-the-workfare-income-supplement-wis-scheme",
        "question": "How much cash and CPF contributions will I receive from the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme?",
        "answer": "If you are an employee, you will receive 60% of your Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) in CPF contributions and the remaining 40% in cash.A higher proportion is credited into your Special/Retirement and MediSave Accounts to boost your retirement and healthcare savings, as savings in these accounts earn up to 5% per annum if you are below 55, and up to 6% per annum if you are 55 or above.You can refer to the table below on the allocation of the WIS CPF into the three accounts, according to the age bands*.Age(Years)Ordinary AccountMediSave AccountSpecial/Retirement Account35 & below30%35%35%Above 35 - 4529%37%34%Above 45 – 5028%38%34%Above 50 – 5525%38%38%Above 55 – 6043%45%11%Above 60 – 6521%64%15%Above 658%84%8%If you are a self-employed person, you will receive 90% of your WIS in your MediSave Account and the remaining 10% in cash.* Figures may not add up due to rounding.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-will-i-receive-my-workfare-income-supplement-wis",
        "question": "When will I receive my Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)?",
        "answer": "If you are an eligible employee, you will receive Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) for every month that you work. The payment will be made two months after the month of work. You are encouraged to link your NRIC to PayNow with the participating banks to receive your benefits earlier.If you do not have a PayNow-NRIC bank account but have provided your bank account number to the Government previously, you will receive your benefits via bank transfer. If you do not have a bank account, the benefits will be credited to you via GovCash. Please see the examples below:Month you have workedMonth you will receive payment to your bank account or GovCashPayNow-NRIC / Bank CreditingGovCashJanEnd Mar1st week of AprilFebEnd Apr1st week of MayMarEnd May1st week of JuneMonth xEnd of month (x+2)1st week of the following month (x+3)You may login to oure-serviceswith your Singpass to check your payment details after the payment has been made to your bank accounts or via GovCash.If you are an eligible Self-Employed Person (SEP), you will receive WIS once a year for work done in the preceding work year (WY).The earliest that you can receive WIS is inend April of the following WY(e.g. receive WIS by end April 2025 for work done in 2024), provided that (i) we have received your assessed Net Trade Income (NTI) after you have declared your income to IRAS*; and (ii) you have contributed to your MediSave by 31 March of the following WY.  You will receive your WIS later (after April of the following WY) if your income declaration and MediSave contribution are made later.* If you receive a notification to file tax from IRAS, or you meet the requirement to file tax (i.e. NTI above $6,000 and/or Total Income above $22,000), please submit your tax return to IRAS directly from 1 March to 18 April of the following WY. If you do not receive a notification from IRAS or do not meet the requirement to file tax, please e-File your tax return to IRAS via myTax Portal, from 1 March to 31 October of the following WY.If you have declared your income to IRAS but have yet to receive your Notice of Computation from IRAS by 31 January two years after the WY (e.g. by 31 January 2025 for WY2023), you maywrite to ususing your Singpass for the Board to assess your eligibility for WIS. Do note that you must also contribute to your MediSave by the specified timelines to receive WIS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/will-i-receive-workfare-income-supplement-wis-if-i-am-unemployed",
        "question": "Will I receive Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) if I am unemployed?",
        "answer": "The Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme supplements the income and CPF savings of lower-income Singaporeans, and encourages them to enter and remain in the labour market.You will not receive WIS if you are not working. If you require assistance in looking for a job, or are seeking more information on training and skills upgrading under the Workfare Skills Support (WSS) scheme, please contact the Workforce Singapore (WSG) hotline at 6883 5885 or visit theirwebsite.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-singapore-permanent-residents-prs-not-eligible-for-the-workfare-income-supplement-wis-scheme",
        "question": "Why are Singapore Permanent Residents (PRs) not eligible for the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme?",
        "answer": "The Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme is only for Singaporean lower-wage workers.If you require financial assistance, please contact theComCarehotline at 1800-222-0000, or emailAsk_SSO@msf.gov.sg.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-there-a-need-for-the-government-to-recover-the-excess-workfare-income-supplement-wis-paid-to-workers",
        "question": "Why is there a need for the government to recover the excess Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) paid to workers?",
        "answer": "The Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme supports lower-wage Singaporean workers’ income and retirement savings via cash and CPF contributions. To ensure that the WIS scheme remains fair, the excess WIS (both the cash and CPF portions) will be recovered from future WIS payment(s) that the worker may receive.For fraudulent cases, the recovery will be carried out immediately after the worker’s conviction or before conviction if the worker offered restitution in writing. Cash refund in lieu of CPF will be required if there are insufficient balances in the worker’s CPF accounts. Interest accrued on the outstanding cash amount may also be recovered. The worker will be issued aNotice to Attend Courtif the WIS payments are not refunded.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-is-my-income-calculated-for-the-workfare-income-supplement-wis",
        "question": "How is my income calculated for the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)?",
        "answer": "To be assessed for Workfare Income Supplement, we will calculate your income based on the income declared by your employer(s) for work done in that month.For work done in Sep 2024 and earlier:To be assessed for Workfare Income Supplement, we will calculate your income based on the CPF contributions made by your employer(s) for work done in that month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-earning-close-to-the-qualifying-wage-cap-why-is-my-workfare-income-supplement-wis-so-low",
        "question": "I am earning close to the qualifying wage cap, why is my Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) so low?",
        "answer": "To best support lower-wage workers, the WIS benefits are gradually reduced as the wage levels of the workers increase nearer to the qualifying wage cap. The gradual reduction ensures that the lower-wage workers do not see a sharp reduction in their WIS benefits when they upgrade their skills and begin to earn more. Taken together, the total amount of the income and the WIS benefits would still increase overall as one's income increases.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-a-contract-part-time-employee-will-i-be-eligible-for-workfare-income-supplement",
        "question": "I am a contract / part-time employee. Will I be eligible for Workfare Income Supplement?",
        "answer": "Contract / part-time employees are eligible for the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) if they meet theWIS eligibility criteria.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-on-no-pay-study-medical-maternity-leave-will-i-be-considered-as-employed-to-qualify-for-workfare-income-supplement",
        "question": "I am on no-pay/study/medical/maternity leave. Will I be considered as employed to qualify for Workfare Income Supplement?",
        "answer": "For the purpose of Workfare Income Supplement (WIS), staff on study/medical/maternity leave will be considered as employees if you are still receiving a salary and CPF contributions from your employers.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/my-employer-does-not-pay-my-cpf-what-can-i-do-to-qualify-for-workfare-income-supplement-wis",
        "question": "My employer does not pay my CPF. What can I do to qualify for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)?",
        "answer": "Under the CPF Act, employers must contribute CPF if their employees earn more than $50 a month, regardless of whether the employee is employed on a permanent, part-time, contract or casual basis.If your employer is not contributing CPF on your behalf, please approach your employer to clarify on the discrepancies. If your employer does not provide you with a satisfactory response, you can lodge a report with CPF Board.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-is-a-self-employed-person",
        "question": "Who is a self-employed person?",
        "answer": "A self-employed person (SEP) is someone who performs work for others under a contract for service.If you earn an income by buying and selling goods or from providing professional or personal services, you’re an SEP. Examples of SEPs include hawkers, taxi drivers, freelancers, sole proprietors or a partner in a partnership.Visit theInland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) websiteto read more on the definition of an SEP.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-is-my-net-trade-income-determined-for-workfare-income-supplement-wis-if-i-am-a-self-employed-person",
        "question": "How is my net trade income determined for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) if I am a self-employed person?",
        "answer": "From Work Year 2023 onwards, all Net Trade Income (NTI) declarations must be made with Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS). The Workfare Income Supplement you are eligible to receive will be computed based on your NTI earned in the Work Year (not including previous years’ losses) that CPF Board receives from IRAS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-must-self-employed-persons-seps-contribute-to-medisave-to-receive-workfare-income-supplement-wis",
        "question": "Why must self-employed persons (SEPs) contribute to MediSave to receive Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)?",
        "answer": "A key principle of the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme is that each recipient has a personal responsibility to save for his future needs, with the government providing additional support.Self-employed persons (SEPs) are required to contribute to their MediSave Accounts as they do not receive regular MediSave contributions from employers. It is important to contribute regularly to ensure enough savings for healthcare needs. This is especially important during old age, when SEPs may have stopped working.WIS is intended to supplement, not replace the MediSave contributions made by the SEPs.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-medisave-contribution-do-i-have-to-make-to-qualify-for-workfare-income-supplement-wis",
        "question": "How much MediSave contribution do I have to make to qualify for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)?",
        "answer": "If your net trade income (NTI) is more than $6,000The amount of MediSave contribution you need to make to qualify for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) is based on your NTI earned in the Work Yearwithoutaccounting for previous years’ losses. CPF Board receives this NTI from IRAS. This amount may differ from the MediSave contributions you are required to fulfil as a self-employed person under theSelf-Employed Scheme (SES), which may be adjusted based on previous years’ losses or excess MediSave contributions.You may refer to any of the following sources for the amount of MediSave contribution that you need to make to qualify for WIS:WIS e-services: Login to the WISe-serviceswith your Singpass to check your MediSave liability payable.WIS calculator: Estimate the amount of MediSave payable using theWIS calculatorfor SEPs.If your NTI is $6,000 or less*Please see the following for the required amount of MediSave contribution to qualify for WIS, according to your age in the year you worked:30 to 34 years$24035 to 44 years$27045 to 49 years$30050 years and above$315* Note: SEPs earning less than $6,000 will also have to meet the eligibility criteria for concessionary WIS. Please refer to the concessionaryWIS eligibility criteriafor more details.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-make-my-medisave-contributions",
        "question": "How can I make my MediSave contributions?",
        "answer": "There are several ways you can contribute to your MediSave. The most convenient way is via GIRO, which allows automatic monthly deductions from your bank account.Payment modeDetailsGIROUsingmy cpfdigital services (list of participating banks)Log in with your Singpass.Submit theSet up GIRO for MediSave contributionsapplication.Check the status of your GIRO application via Activities.Mail (for other banks)Download and complete theApply for GIRO for MediSave Contributionsform (FORM SE GIRO (PDF, 0.2MB)).Mail it to the address printed overleaf of the GIRO application form.We will notify you of your GIRO application status once the bank has processed it.PayNow QRRequest an instalment plan or contribute to your MediSave payable in full via theManage your MediSave payableform.Cash/ NETS/ CashCardMake MediSave contributions (any amount) via cash, NETS or CashCard at any SingPost branch.You may view your MediSave contributions on the Self-employment dashboard. To accessmy cpfDigital Services – Self-employment dashboard, please log in to theCPF websiteusing your Singpass.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-declare-my-annual-net-trade-income-online-as-a-self-employed-person",
        "question": "How do I declare my annual net trade income online as a self-employed person?",
        "answer": "For Work Year 2023 (WY2023) onwardsAll Net Trade Income (NTI) declarations for Work Year 2023 (Year of Assessment 2024) can be made with the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) by filing a tax return. There is no need to file separate declarations with CPF Board.If you receive a notification (via letter/form/SMS) to file tax from IRAS or you meet the requirement to file tax (i.e. NTI above $6,000 and/or Total Income above $22,000), please complete and submit the tax return to IRAS directly. The income tax filing period is from 1 March to 18 April annually.If you do not receive a notification from IRAS or do not meet the requirement to file tax, you can declare your self-employed net trade income (NTI) to IRAS viamyTax Portalwhich will be available from 1 March to 31 October annually for taxpayers to e-File tax returns.Once IRAS has assessed your income for the year, your assessed NTI will be transmitted to the Board. You can check your updated NTI records by logging in to the Self-employment dashboard with your Singpass.For Work Year 2022 (WY2022) or earlierIf you were not issued a Notice of Assessment (NOA) by IRAS and wish to declare NTI for work years prior to 2023, you canwrite to ususing your Singpass.If you have declared your NTI with IRAS, you need not declare your income again to CPF Board.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-made-the-required-medisave-contribution-to-qualify-for-workfare-income-supplement-why-is-my-payment-still-not-reflected-in-the-medisave-payable-page-after-logging-into-e-services",
        "question": "I have made the required MediSave contribution to qualify for Workfare Income Supplement, why is my payment still not reflected in the MediSave Payable page after logging into e-Services?",
        "answer": "Contributions made each month will be updated in e-Services on the 9th working day of the following month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-do-employees-receive-monthly-workfare-income-supplement-wis-payments-while-self-employed-persons-receive-their-wis-once-a-year",
        "question": "Why do employees receive monthly Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) payments while Self-Employed Persons receive their WIS once a year?",
        "answer": "The incomes of employees are automatically computed based on their monthly CPF contributions from their employers. This enables CPF Board to assess their Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) eligibility automatically and disburse their WIS on a monthly basis.On the other hand, the net trade income (NTI) of a Self-Employed Person (SEP) is assessed over an entire year and can only be determined the following year after the current year has ended.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-do-self-employed-persons-receive-only-two-thirds-of-the-workfare-income-supplement-wis-received-by-employees",
        "question": "Why do Self-Employed Persons receive only two-thirds of the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) received by employees?",
        "answer": "The CPF contribution made by Self-Employed Persons (SEPs) is comparatively less than employees who earn the same amount. SEPs are only required to contribute to their MediSave Account whereas employees need to contribute to all their CPF Accounts (Ordinary, Special and MediSave Accounts).",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-a-homemaker-babysitter-can-i-qualify-for-the-workfare-income-supplement-wis-scheme",
        "question": "I am a homemaker/babysitter. Can I qualify for the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme?",
        "answer": "Allowances received for carrying out family support roles such as babysitting and general caregiving for dependants are considered transfers within the family. They are not external sources of income derived from employment, hence it would not be appropriate to consider these transfers for Workfare Income Supplement scheme.The Government recognises that such family roles are important. There are other forms of government support for these roles, such as theMarriage and Parenthood packagewhich provides broad-based support for couples to raise and care for their children.Employee/Self-Employed Persons who are also caregivers (generally include caregivers residing with care recipients who are medically certified to have permanent moderate to severe disabilities) could qualify for concessionary WIS, even if they earn less than $500. For more information, please refer to our FAQshere.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-a-freelancer-conducting-a-home-business-eg-baking-sewing-can-i-qualify-for-the-workfare-income-supplement-wis-scheme",
        "question": "I am a freelancer/conducting a home business (e.g. baking, sewing). Can I qualify for the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme?",
        "answer": "To qualify for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme, please declare your net trade income as a self-employed person and contribute to your MediSave Account. You will also need to meet theWIS eligibility criteriain order to qualify for WIS.To conduct a home business, you need to follow the guidelines under HDB's Home-Based Small-Scale Business Scheme. Please refer to theHousing Development Board's websitefor more information.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-used-to-declare-my-income-to-cpfb-to-determine-my-wis-excess-caye-contributions-for-the-year-why-is-cpfb-no-longer-accepting-income-declarations",
        "question": "I used to declare my income to CPFB to determine my Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)/excess Contribute As You Earn (CAYE) contributions for the year. Why is CPFB no longer accepting income declarations?",
        "answer": "The Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) has been appointed as the single collecting agency for all SEPs’ income information from Work Year 2023 (or Year of Assessment 2024). This means that all SEPs will now declare their net trade income (NTI), including all other sources of income derived from Work Year 2023, to IRAS. SEPs who receive a notification (via letter/form/SMS) to file tax from IRAS or meet the requirement to file tax (i.e. NTI above $6,000 and/or Total Income above $22,000), will need to complete and submit the tax return to IRAS directly. The income tax filing period is from 1 March to 18 April annually.SEPs who do not receive a notification from IRAS or do not meet the requirement to file tax may declare their self-employed net trade income (NTI), including all other sources of income derived from Work Year 2023, to IRAS viamyTax Portalwhich will be available from 1 March to 31 October annually for taxpayers to e-File tax returns.SEPs will receive a Notice of Computation (NOC) from IRAS if they are required to make MediSave contributions, after IRAS has issued a Notice of Assessment for the relevant Year of Assessment.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/my-net-trade-income-in-a-work-year-was-negative-can-i-trade-the-losses-to-offset-my-income-in-the-following-year-to-qualify-for-the-workfare-income-supplement-wis-scheme",
        "question": "My net trade income in a work year was negative. Can I trade the losses to offset my income in the following year to qualify for the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme?",
        "answer": "Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) is based on your net trade income earned in the work year and does not include previous year's losses.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-the-workfare-income-supplement-for-platform-workers-aligned-to-that-of-employees-only-in-2029",
        "question": "Why is the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) for platform workers aligned to that of employees only in 2029 when the increased CPF contributions for platform workers is implemented in 2025?",
        "answer": "CPF contributions rates will gradually increase for platform workers from 2025 to 2028. To support lower-income platform workers during this period, we will provide the Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) to help mitigate the drop in take-home earnings. PCTS will fully offset the increase in platform workers’ CPF contributions in 2025 and gradually taper down before ceasing in 2029.When the platform workers’ CPF contribution rates are fully aligned with employees in 2029, Workfare Income Supplement will be aligned with that of employees for platform workers who are mandated or opt in to the increased CPF contributions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-platform-workers-who-have-not-opted-in-to-the-increased-cpf-contributions",
        "question": "Why are platform workers who have not opted in to the increased CPF contributions not eligible to receive Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) aligned to that of employees from 2029?",
        "answer": "Platform workers who have not opted in to increased CPF contributions continue to contribute less to their CPF, like self-employed persons (SEPs). Thus, the Workfare Income Supplement for these eligible platform workers are aligned with SEPs.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-workfare-income-supplement-scheme-enhancement-that-applies-to-platform-workers",
        "question": "What is the Workfare Income Supplement Scheme (WIS) enhancement that applies to platform workers?",
        "answer": "Eligible platform workers who are mandated or opt in to the increased CPF contributions will receive higher Workfare Income Supplement Scheme (WIS) payments at the same level as employees from 2029, once their CPF contribution rates fully align with that of employees. They will also receive a higher proportion of WIS payments in cash – 40% compared to 10% today.All eligible platform workers will also receive WIS monthly (instead of annually) from March 2025. This is because platform operators will deduct CPF contributions from platform workers as and when they earn and submit them to CPF Board every month from 2025 onwards, including MediSave contributions for those who do not opt in.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-worked-as-both-an-employee-as-well-as-a-self-employed-person-sep-in-the-work-year-when-will-i-receive-my-workfare-income-supplement-wis-for-the-work-year",
        "question": "I worked as both an employee as well as a self-employed person (SEP) in the work year. When will I receive my Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) for the work year?",
        "answer": "You will receive monthly Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) payments based on your employee income if you meet the WIS eligibility criteria for the work year (WY).If you are also an eligible dual status worker (DSW) who has worked concurrently as an SEP and employee in the year, you may receive additional WIS if your combined employment and net trade income results in a higher WIS payment. You will receive the additional WIS payment after you have declared your income and made the required MediSave contributions.You will receive WIS once a year for work done as an SEP in the preceding year. The earliest payment for SEPs/DSWs for a particular WY will be on 30 April WY+1*.*Payment via PayNow NRIC-linked bank account or bank crediting will be credited by end of the month while payment via GovCash will be on the 3rd of the following month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-have-income-from-different-types-of-employment-e-g-employee-self-employed-person-platform-worker-during-the-work-year-when-will-i-receive-my-workfare-income-supplement-wis-for-the-work-year",
        "question": "I have income from different types of employment (e.g. employee, self-employed person, platform worker) during the work year. When will I receive my Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) for the work year?",
        "answer": "You will receive monthly Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) payments based on your employee and/or platform worker income if you meet the WIS eligibility criteria for the work year (WY).If you have concurrently worked as a self-employed person (SEP) in the year, you may receive additional WIS if your total income (including net trade income) results in a higher WIS payment. You will receive the additional WIS payment after you have declared your income and made the required MediSave contributions.You will receive WIS once a year for work done as an SEP in the preceding year. The earliest payment for SEPs for a particular WY will be on 30 April WY+1*.*Payment via PayNow NRIC-linked bank account or bank crediting will be credited by end of the month while payment via GovCash will be on the first week of the following month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/to-qualify-for-workfare-income-supplement-wis-what-is-considered-income",
        "question": "To qualify for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS), what is considered income?",
        "answer": "Employee income is based on the definition of Gross Wages under the CPF Act:Total Gross Wages = Total Ordinary Wages + Total Additional WagesWhere:Ordinary Wages (OW) are wages due or granted wholly or exclusively in respect of an employee's employment in that month, and payable before the due date for payment of CPF contributions for that month e.g. monthly salary.Wages which are not classified as OW will be Additional Wages (AW) for the month e.g. annual performance bonus.Total Wages are the total amount of an employee's wages for any calendar month, which is the sum of his OW for the month and the AW paid to him in that month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-overtime-pay-and-bonuses-included-in-workfare-income-supplement-wis-assessment",
        "question": "Why are overtime pay and bonuses included in Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) assessment?",
        "answer": "Basic salary, overtime pay, and bonuses are part of a worker’s total income that will help support the worker and his or her family. Given that the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) is intended to supplement the income of lower-wage workers, it is most useful to assess the total income in determining one’s eligibility for WIS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-is-the-12-month-average-gross-monthly-income-ami-criterion-computed",
        "question": "How is the 12-month average gross monthly income (AMI) criterion computed?",
        "answer": "The 12-month average gross monthly income is defined as:Sum of income earned in the past 12-month period ÷ Total number of months worked in the past 12-month periodTo qualify for WIS:a) Your 12-month average gross monthly income must not exceed $2,500; andb) Your gross monthly income must not exceed $2,500.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-the-minimum-income-criterion-be-waived-for-workers-who-want-to-work-more-but-are-unable-to",
        "question": "Can the minimum income criterion be waived for workers who want to work more but are unable to?",
        "answer": "The minimum income criterion of $500 per month was introduced from 2023 to encourage workers to work more regularly or take up higher-paying jobs.$500 per month is achievable for most regular workers. At an hourly wage of $10.501, workers who work 3-hr daily shifts for 16 days a month would already earn more than $500 per month.We recognise that some want to work more but are unable to do so due to their personal circumstances or are in greater need of support, such as Persons with Disabilities (PWDs), ComCare Short-to-Medium-Term Assistance recipients and caregivers of care recipients2. Such workers will continue to qualify for concessionary WIS, even if they earn less than $500 per month.1based on Local Qualifying Salary requirement for part-time workers from July 2024 onwards2This will generally includecaregiversresiding with care recipients who are medically certified to have permanent moderate to severe disabilities.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-earn-less-than-500-per-month-do-i-qualify-for-workfare-income-supplement-wis",
        "question": "I earn less than $500 per month. Do I qualify for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)?",
        "answer": "If you earn less than $500 per month, you will qualify for concessionary Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) if you belong to one of the groups and meet other WIS eligibility criteria:•            Person with Disability (PWD)•            Comcare Short-to-Medium Term Assistance recipient•            Caregiver of a care recipient. This generally includescaregiversresiding with care recipients who are medically certified to have permanent moderate to severe disabilities.For employees, you will receive a flat concessionary payment, based on age:Age in Work Year30 to 34 years35 to 44 years45 to 59 years60 years and above and all PWDsMonthly concessionary Workfare payment$50$75$120$130Self-employed persons (SEPs) will receive two-thirds of the WIS payments received by employees after they have made the required MediSave contributions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/who-are-considered-eligible-caregivers-for-concessionary-wis",
        "question": "Who are considered eligible caregivers for concessionary WIS?",
        "answer": "To be eligible for concessionary WIS as a working caregiver, individuals must fulfill all 4 criteria below:a) Their care recipients qualify for selected Agency for Integrated Care (AIC) schemes1;b) They are related household members of the care recipient (i.e. related by blood or legal relations to the care recipient, and staying together at the same address);c) Their care recipients are not residing in nursing homes; andd) They meet all other eligibility criteria for WIS, except the $500 minimum income threshold.Eligible caregivers have started receiving concessionary WIS payments for work done from 2023 onwards.CPF Board will automatically assess caregivers’ eligibility for WIS. Caregivers do not need to notify CPFB Board that they are a caregiver nor submit any supporting documents.If you are a caregiver and have recently moved in with your care recipient, you are required to update your residential address in your NRIC withICA. If you have already done so but have yet to receive concessionary WIS payments, please contactCPF Board.1The schemes from Agency for Integrated Care (AIC) are: Home Caregiving Grant, Pioneer Generation Disability Assistance Scheme, Interim Disability Assistance Programme for the Elderly, ElderFund, MediSave Care, CareShield Life Claims, and ElderShield Claims. These AIC schemes are for individuals who have permanent moderate to severe disabilities.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-annual-value-av-of-a-property-and-why-is-the-av-of-my-place-of-residence-used-to-assess-my-eligibility-for-workfare-income-supplement-wis",
        "question": "What is the Annual Value (AV) of a property and why is the AV of my place of residence used to assess my eligibility for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)?",
        "answer": "Annual Value (AV) is the estimated gross annual rent of the property if it were to be rented out, excluding furniture, furnishings and maintenance fees. It is determined based on estimated market rentals of similar or comparable properties. It can be found on the property tax bill you receive each year.AV serves as a housing criterion that targets lower-wage workers with less household wealth.For more information on the computation of AV, please visit theInland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) website.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-is-the-annual-value-av-requirement-for-workfare-income-supplement-wis-decided-and-what-address-is-used-to-determine-the-av-in-wis",
        "question": "How is the Annual Value (AV) requirement for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) decided and what address is used to determine the AV in WIS?",
        "answer": "The Annual Value (AV) threshold of $21,000 from Work Year 2024 (was $13,000), covers all HDB flats, as well as some smaller private residences. In general, Singaporeans staying in larger properties with AV above the cut-off tend to have greater access to household wealth, and therefore would not be eligible for the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme.The AV will be based on the address reflected in your NRIC. Under the National Registration Act, you must report a change of address within 28 days of moving at the Immigration & Checkpoints Authority (ICA)website.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-constitutes-a-second-property-for-workfare-income-supplement-wis-scheme",
        "question": "What constitutes a second property for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme?",
        "answer": "All types of properties e.g. Housing & Development Board flat, private property and non-residential property, are taken into account in determining the eligibility for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-renting-a-room-whole-unit-in-the-property-that-i-stay-in-am-i-eligible-for-workfare-income-supplement-wis",
        "question": "I am renting a room/whole unit in the property that I stay in. Am I eligible for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)?",
        "answer": "If you are renting the entire property unit, the annual value of that property unit will be used to assess your eligibility.If you are renting only a room or some rooms in the property, pleasewrite to uswith your tenancy agreement and particulars (name, NRIC, telephone number, address and the nature of your appeal).You can also write to us viaMailbox(Singpass required) and skip the hassle of keying in your personal particulars.We will review your WIS eligibility after we have received your request and the supporting documents.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-residents-in-welfare-homes-qualify-for-workfare-income-supplement-wis",
        "question": "Do residents in welfare homes qualify for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)?",
        "answer": "Residents in welfare homes registered with the National Council of Social Service/ Ministry of Health/ Ministry of Social and Family Development will qualify for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) if they meet all of the otherWIS eligibility criteria.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-my-spouse-income-and-property-ownership-used-to-determine-my-eligibility-for-workfare-income-supplement-wis",
        "question": "Why is my spouse's income and property ownership used to determine my eligibility for Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)?",
        "answer": "To ensure that Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) is targeted at recipients with limited access to household wealth, you will not qualify for WIS if:the assessable income of your spouse for the preceding Year of Assessment exceeds $70,000; oryou and your spouse together own two or more properties.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-my-spouse-assessable-income-for-the-preceding-year-of-assessment-used-to-determine-my-workfare-income-supplement-wis-eligibility-for-the-current-work-year",
        "question": "Why is my spouse's Assessable Income for the preceding Year of Assessment used to determine my Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) eligibility for the current work year?",
        "answer": "This is to allow potential Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) recipients to receive WIS earlier despite the time needed by the Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore (IRAS) for the processing and transmission of Assessable Income (AI) to the CPF Board.The AI for the previous Year of Assessment (YOA) is used to assess one's WIS eligibility for the current year. E.g. we will use your spouse's AI for YOA 2022 to assess your eligibility for 2023 WIS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-will-i-receive-the-workfare-income-supplement-wis-payment",
        "question": "How will I receive the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) payment?",
        "answer": "You will receive the cash portion of Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) via your PayNow-NRIC-linked bank account. To check your PayNow-NRIC-linked bank account details, please approach your bank.If you do not have a PayNow-NRIC-linked bank account with a PayNow-GIRO-participating local or foreign bank in Singapore but have provided your DBS/POSB, OCBC or UOB bank account to the Government previously, you will receive your cash portion of WIS via bank transfer. You can check and update your bank account details registered with us by logging in to oure-serviceswith your Singpass.Otherwise, the amount will be credited to you via GovCash. GovCash is a payment mode that allows Singaporeans to receive their benefits from Government agencies more quickly and conveniently. You are encouraged to link your NRIC to PayNow with a PayNow-GIRO-participating local or foreign bank in Singapore to receive your benefits earlier*.*If you have linked your NRIC number to your bank account after the 16th of the month or submitted your bank account details after the 14th of the month, your updates will only be effective in the following month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-change-the-mode-of-payment-for-my-workfare-income-supplement-wis-i-have-already-registered-for-paynow-nric-to-receive-my-government-cash-benefits-do-i-still-need-to-provide-my-bank-account-details",
        "question": "How can I change the mode of payment for my Workfare Income Supplement (WIS)? / I have already registered for PayNow-NRIC to receive my Government cash benefits. Do I still need to provide my bank account details?",
        "answer": "No further action is required from you if you have already registered for PayNow-NRIC with the participating banks. You are encouraged to register for PayNow-NRIC with a PayNow-GIRO-participating local or foreign bank in Singapore to receive your WIS payments earlier. Payment will be made by default to your PayNow-NRIC-linked bank account.If you do not have a PayNow-NRIC-linked bank account, you can update your bank account details by logging in to our WISe-serviceswith your Singpass. Payment instructions received will be used for future government benefits. The Government will be validating the bank account details that you have registered. If you have closed your bank account, ceased being a joint account holder, or have provided the wrong bank account details, we will inform you to update your bank account details. You will receive a notification sent to your Singpass app. If you do not have the app, a letter will be sent to your NRIC address. This notification will not be sent via SMS, WhatsApp or any other platforms.If you have not linked your NRIC to PayNow or have not provided a valid bank account to the Government, you will receive future Government cash benefits via GovCash.GovCashis a payment mode where you can withdraw your Government benefits in cash from OCBC ATMs.Citizens who are on GovCash will receive their cash benefits 2-3 weeks later than those who have linked their NRIC to PayNow or have provided a valid bank account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-paynow-and-how-do-i-link-my-nric-to-paynow",
        "question": "What is PayNow and how do I link my NRIC to PayNow?",
        "answer": "PayNow is a secure funds transfer service that allows customers to receive money into their bank account via NRIC/FIN and/or mobile number.With PayNow, the recipient’s bank information will be kept private. The recipient will need to provide their mobile number or NRIC/FIN to the sender to send money. Other PayNow users will not have access to your personal details unless it is provided by you.To receive government benefits via PayNow, you will need to link your NRIC to PayNow. PayNow-Mobile number is not accepted. You can register for PayNow-NRIC if you have a bank account with the following participating banks in Singapore:BankBank of ChinaCIMBCitibankDBS Bank / POSBGXS BankHSBC BankICBCMariBankMaybankOCBCRHB BankStandard Chartered BankState Bank of IndiaTrust BankUOBThe list of PayNow-GIRO banks is updated as of 6 Dec 2024.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/my-mobile-number-is-already-registered-to-my-bank-account-on-paynow-can-the-government-credit-my-government-cash-benefits-to-me-via-paynow-mobile-instead-of-via-paynow-nric",
        "question": "My mobile number is already registered to my bank account on PayNow. Can the Government credit my Government cash benefits to me via PayNow-Mobile instead of via PayNow-NRIC?",
        "answer": "We can only credit your Government cash benefits to you via your PayNow-NRIC-linked bank account. NRIC is an unchanged proxy issued by the Government, compared to mobile numbers which may be easily changed. To ensure that the money is credited to the correct recipient’s bank account, only NRIC will be accepted as the proxy for Government benefits via PayNow.Eligible seniors who have linked their NRIC to PayNow, with a PayNow-GIRO-participating bank will receive the benefits in this bank account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-I-update-my-mode-of-payment-to-receive-cash-benefits-from-the-government",
        "question": "How can I update my mode of payment to receive cash benefits from the Government?",
        "answer": "There are two options which you can choose to update the mode of payment for your government cash benefits:Option 1: Register for PayNow-NRICYou can register for PayNow-NRIC if you have a bank account with theparticipating banks. Please refer to your respective bank's website for specific details on how to link your NRIC to PayNow. Please note that PayNow-Mobile number is not accepted.You are encouraged to register for PayNow-NRIC as government cash benefits will be credited to your PayNow-NRIC-linked bank account by default.PayNow is a secure funds transfer service that allows customers to receive money into their bank account via NRIC/FIN and/or mobile number. With PayNow, the recipient's bank information will be kept private. The recipient will need to provide their mobile number or NRIC/FIN to the sender to send money. Other PayNow users will not have access to your personal details unless it is provided by you.Option 2: Provide your bank account detailsYou may provide your bank account details by logging in to oure-serviceswith your Singpass. The bank account that you have provided will only be used if you do not have a PayNow-NRIC linked bank account.Bank crediting is only available via the three local banking groups DBS/POSB, OCBC, UOB, and your bank account must be a personal or joint account registered with your NRIC number.The Government will validate the bank account details that you have registered with your bank. If you have closed your bank account, ceased being a joint account holder, or have provided the wrong bank account details, we will inform you to update your bank account details. You will receive a letter sent to your NRIC address.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-govcash-and-is-it-safe",
        "question": "What is GovCash and is it safe?",
        "answer": "GovCash is a payment mode that allows Singapore citizens to withdraw their Government benefits in cash from over 500 OCBC ATMs located across Singapore.Singaporeans who prefer to seek assistance with their GovCash withdrawals can visit the ATMs located within OCBC's branches during operating hours, where OCBC Digital Ambassadors will be present to guide them. In addition, GovCash also allows recipients to use the scan-and-pay function and PayNow transfer option through the LifeSG mobile app.GovCash is as secure as receiving payments via cheque. It adopts the Singpass Face Verification technology to authenticate users, including a liveness-detection capability that blocks the use of photographs, videos, or masks during the verification process. Users are also required to key in their unique 8-digit Payment Reference Number (PRN) during the withdrawal of the Government benefits at the OCBC ATMs.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-receive-my-cash-benefits-via-govcash",
        "question": "How do I receive my cash benefits via GovCash?",
        "answer": "There are three options which you can choose to receive your cash benefit via GovCash:Option 1: Use LifeSG to transfer to PayNow-NRIC linked bank accountIf you have an existing bank account, you can link your account to PayNow-NRIC with your bank. Thereafter, login to LifeSG mobile app (LifeSG) using your Singpass to transfer your GovCash to your PayNow-NRIC linked bank account. The LifeSG app can be downloaded from the Apple App store or Google Play Store.Option 2: Use LifeSG for Scan & PayYou can use LifeSG to scan participating merchant’s QR code for purchases or scan your friend/family’s QR code to transfer your GovCash to them. You can only make purchases at merchants that accept PayNow/NETS QR code using the LifeSG app. You can look out for the PayNow/NETS logo on the SG QR label that is displayed by the merchants.Option 3: Withdraw from OCBC ATMsYou can withdraw your cash benefit at OCBC ATMs islandwide. You just need to enter:a) Your unique 8-digit Payment Reference Number (PRN)b) Your NRIC number; andc) pass the facial verificationYou do not need to have an OCBC bank account to use this service.You will receive the PRN via a letter and your Singpass app (if any) or SMS after your cash benefits has been paid. You can also log into thee-serviceswith your Singpass to view your PRN by selecting “GovCash PRN” that is found at the menu on the left. This will only be available after the payment has been made.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-lost-my-letter-containing-the-payment-reference-number-prn-can-someone-else-take-my-money",
        "question": "I lost my letter containing the Payment Reference Number (PRN), can someone else take my money?",
        "answer": "It is not possible to withdraw the money with just the Payment Reference Number as GovCash uses the Singpass Face Verification technology to authenticate users during the withdrawal of the Government benefits from OCBC ATMs. The Face Verification technology incorporates a liveness-detection capability that blocks the use of photographs, videos or masks during the verification process.This security feature prevents any fraudulent withdrawal of the Government benefits by third party using photographs or videos belonging to the beneficiary and ensuring only the eligible Singaporean can perform the withdrawal of his or her Government benefits.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-you-re-send-my-payment-reference-number-to-me-so-that-i-can-perform-my-govcash-withdrawal",
        "question": "Can you re-send my Payment Reference Number to me so that I can perform my GovCash withdrawal?",
        "answer": "You can log into thee-serviceswith your Singpass to view your Payment Reference Number (PRN) by selecting “GovCash PRN” that is found at the menu on the left. This will only be available after the payment has been made through GovCash.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-do-if-my-facial-recognition-at-the-atm-with-govcash-functions-is-unsuccessful",
        "question": "What should I do if my facial recognition at the ATM with GovCash functions is unsuccessful?",
        "answer": "If you are unable to verify your identity via Singpass Face Verification at the ATM despite repeated tries, you may visit a NEW ATM located at selected OCBC branches (refer toOCBC websitefor latest list of NEW ATMs) during the branch operating hours, and OCBC's Digital Ambassadors will be available to assist you.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/where-can-i-seek-help-regarding-my-govcash-withdrawal",
        "question": "Where can I seek help regarding my GovCash withdrawal?",
        "answer": "Singaporeans who require assistance with their GovCash withdrawals can visit a NEW ATM located at selected OCBC branches (refer toOCBC websitefor latest list of NEW ATMs) during the branch operating hours, and OCBC Digital Ambassadors will be available to assist you.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-help-a-beneficiary-with-medical-condition-eg-physically-immobile-or-mentally-incapacitated-to-withdraw-their-govcash-monies",
        "question": "How can I help a beneficiary with medical condition (e.g. physically immobile or mentally incapacitated) to withdraw their GovCash monies?",
        "answer": "You can help a beneficiary with medical condition (e.g. who is physically immobile or mentally incapacitated) to withdraw their GovCash monies if you are:Aged 21 years and above; andA next-of-kin, or caregiver, or appointed donee under the Lasting Power of Attorney (LPA), or court-appointed Deputy of the beneficiaryTo help with the withdrawal of the GovCash monies, please bring the following documents and visit anyOCBC-New ATMduring branch operating hours, where OCBC Digital Ambassadors will be available to render assistance:a) Original documentary evidence stating the beneficiary's medical condition (e.g. doctor's memorandum, medical report or court order). The date of the document(s) should not be more than 1 year from the withdrawal date, unless it specifically states that the patient's condition is permanent or the condition is known to be permanent (e.g. bedridden, immobile, physically incapacitated, disabled, intellectually disabled, autism, down syndrome, cerebral palsy, etc);b) A photocopy of the beneficiary’s NRIC;c) Your original NRIC; andd) Beneficiary’s GovCash Payment Reference Number (PRN)You may be required to sign a Letter of Indemnity at the bank, witnessed by the bank officer.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/is-there-a-specific-time-frame-for-me-to-withdraw-utilise-my-govcash",
        "question": "Is there a specific time frame for me to withdraw/utilise my GovCash?",
        "answer": "You can choose to withdraw/utilise your GovCash at your convenience. However, you are encouraged to withdraw/utilise your GovCash as the intent of the scheme is to supplement your income and retirement savings.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-check-my-govcash-balance",
        "question": "How do I check my GovCash balance?",
        "answer": "To check your GovCash balance, please visit any OCBC ATMs with your 8-digit Payment Reference Number (PRN). Upon successful authentication, you will be able to view your GovCash balance. Alternatively, you may login to the LifeSG mobile app using your Singpass to view your GovCash balance and transaction history.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-know-if-the-merchants-allow-me-to-make-purchases-using-my-govcash",
        "question": "How do I know if the merchants allow me to make purchases using my GovCash?",
        "answer": "You can only make purchases using GovCash at merchants that accept PayNow/NETS QR code using the LifeSG app. You can look out for the PayNow/NETS logo on the SG QR label that is displayed by the merchants.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/can-i-cancel-the-payment-after-i-have-confirmed-the-payment-utilising-my-govcash-on-the-lifesg-mobile-app",
        "question": "Can I cancel the payment after I have confirmed the payment utilising my GovCash on the LifeSG mobile app?",
        "answer": "No, your GovCash balance will be deducted upon successful payment.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-should-i-do-if-i-do-not-want-to-receive-my-payments-via-govcash",
        "question": "What should I do if I do not want to receive my payments via GovCash?",
        "answer": "There are two options for you if you do not wish to receive your payments via GovCash:Option 1: Register for PayNow-NRIC with one of the participating banksWe encourage you to register for PayNow-NRIC with a PayNow-GIRO-participating bank.The list of PayNow-GIRO-participating banks in alphabetical order are: Bank of China, CIMB, Citibank, DBS Bank / POSB, HSBC Bank, ICBC, Maybank, OCBC Bank, RHB Bank, Standard Chartered Bank, Trust Bank and UOB Bank.If your preferred bank is on this list, you may contact your bank for specific details on how to register your NRIC on PayNow.After you have linked your NRIC to PayNow, future Government benefits that you are eligible for will be automatically credited to your PayNow-NRIC-linked bank account.Option 2: Register your bank account detailsAlternatively, you can choose to receive your payments via crediting to your bank account. To do so, you may login to thee-servicesusing your Singpass, select “Bank Account Submission” and update your POSB/DBS, OCBC or UOB bank account details.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-the-option-to-withdraw-govcash-only-available-in-10-denominations-and-what-can-i-do-with-my-balance-govcash",
        "question": "Why is the option to withdraw GovCash only available in $10 denominations and what can I do with my balance GovCash?",
        "answer": "Currently, the minimum withdrawal amount at the ATMs is $10. Hence, GovCash withdrawals can also be made in $10 denominations. If the balance in your GovCash is less than $10, you can accumulate your balance monies before your next withdrawal.Alternatively, you can also transfer the balance to your PayNow NRIC-linked bank account or utilise them to make payments at any merchants with PayNow/NETS QR code, or transfer to your friends by scanning the PayNow QR code using the LifeSG mobile app.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-and-when-will-i-receive-workfare-notification-on-the-amount-i-am-receiving",
        "question": "How and when will I receive Workfare notification on the amount I am receiving?",
        "answer": "You will be notified via letters and/or SMS nearer to the payment dates. You can also login to thee-Serviceswith your Singpass to check your payment.To receive the notification earlier via SMS, please log in to thee-Serviceswith your Singpass and select \"Notification\" to opt-in to receive SMS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-receive-sms-notifications-and-stop-receiving-hardcopy-notifications-for-the-workfare-income-supplement-wis-scheme",
        "question": "How can I receive SMS notifications and stop receiving hardcopy notifications for the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) scheme?",
        "answer": "To receive SMS notifications, register your mobile number with CPF Board viamy cpfdigital services -Account Settingswith your Singpass.If you wish to receive notifications of your Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) by SMS instead of hardcopy letters, please log in to thee-Serviceswith your Singpass and opt-in to SMS at “Notification”.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-provide-or-update-my-mobile-number-to-receive-sms-notification-on-my-workfare-payment",
        "question": "How can I provide or update my mobile number to receive SMS notification on my Workfare payment?",
        "answer": "We will only send SMS notifications on Workfare payments to the mobile number that you have registered with CPF Board.To receive SMS notifications, you may update your mobile number viamy cpfdigital services -Account Settingswith your Singpass.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-tell-if-the-workfare-sms-i-received-is-authentic",
        "question": "How can I tell if the Workfare SMS I received is authentic?",
        "answer": "With the recent rise in scam and phishing attempts, it is important to verify that the message received is genuinely sent by an official source.From 1 July 2024, all government SMS communications will be sent under the sender ID “gov.sg”. The SMS begins with the full name of the sending agency (i.e. “Central Provident Fund Board”) and ends with “This is an automated message sent by the Singapore Government”. It means you should not reply to the message.This is only an example of a Workfare SMS. The actual SMS received may be different.Here are some tips on how you can protect yourself against phishing SMSes purporting to be sent from CPF Board:Check the SMS is sent by “gov.sg”to the mobile number registered with CPF Board. If you are unsure of whether you had registered your mobile number, please login to the CPF website with your Singpass and check youraccount settings.Verify the last four characters of the masked NRIC number are the same as your NRIC number.We will never ask you to reply to the Workfare SMS nor direct you to a non-Government website. Do report any suspicious SMS spoofing toCPF Board.Be Cautious, Pay attention to scams and don't be the next victim of Fraud.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-is-the-government-sending-sms-notifications-instead-of-hardcopy-letters",
        "question": "Why is the government sending SMS notifications instead of hardcopy letters?",
        "answer": "Moving to SMS notifications is part of the Government's efforts to provide timelier and more responsive services to the public. It also allows us to be more environmentally friendly. With SMS notifications, you can quickly and easily receive details of your Workfare payments, including the mode of payment and payment date, instead of having to wait for hardcopy letters.If you are on hardcopy notification and would like to switch to SMS notification, please log in to thee-Serviceswith your Singpass and opt-in to receive SMS at \"Notification\".",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-qualify-for-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts",
        "question": "How do I qualify for Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS)?",
        "answer": "You will qualify for Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) if you meet the following criteria:Are a Singapore Citizen;Born in 1995 or later; or born before 1995 andopted into increase your CPF contributions;Net income from platform work and other employment sources does not exceed $3,000 for the month (Net income refers to gross earnings minus the Fixed Expense Deduction Amount); andHave an increase in your share of CPF contributions to the Ordinary and Special Accounts as compared to the previous year.PCTS is intended to offset part of the year-on-year increase in a platform worker’s own share of his CPF contributions to his Ordinary and Special accounts, during the phase-in period when platform workers’ CPF contribution rates are gradually increased to aligned with employees’. Hence:Platform workers aged above 65 will not be eligible as they will not see an increase in their own share of CPF contributions if they opt in to increased CPF contributions.In 2025, platform workers aged above 60 to 65 will also not see an increase in their own share of CPF contributions and thus they will not be eligible.As PCTS is intended to offset the increase in CPF contributions, a platform worker will not receive PCTS for the months where his net earnings for a platform operator are$500 or less, as he does not have to make his own share of CPF contributions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/do-i-need-to-apply-for-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts",
        "question": "Do I need to apply for Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS)?",
        "answer": "You do not need to apply for Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS).We will automatically assess your eligibility for PCTS based on the net earnings declared by your platform operator when making CPF contributions.We will credit your PCTS payment to yourPayNow NRIC-linked bank accountif you have one. Otherwise, it will be credited to the bank account that you have registered to receive Government benefits, or viaGovCashif you had not registered a bank account with us. Crediting of PCTS will not go through your platform operators.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/to-qualify-for-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts-what-is-considered-income",
        "question": "To qualify for Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS), what is considered income?",
        "answer": "We will automatically assess your eligibility for Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) based on the net earnings declared by your platform operator(s) when making CPF contributions, and the wages declared by your employer when making CPF contributions if you also work as an employee.Your platform operator will compute your monthly platform net earnings based on your monthly gross earnings less aFixed Expense DeductionAmount(FEDA). The FEDA depends on the mode of transportation you use for platform work.Your wages from your employer are the total amount of wages for any calendar month, which is the sum of your Ordinary Wages for the month and the Additional Wage paid to you in that month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/i-am-a-part-time-platform-worker-will-i-be-eligible-for-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts",
        "question": "I am a part-time platform worker. Will I be eligible for Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS)?",
        "answer": "As eligibility is not based on working hours, even if you are a part-time or ad-hoc platform worker, you can qualify for the Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) as long as you meet the following criteria at the point of assessment:Are a Singapore Citizen;Born in 1995 or later; or born before 1995 andoptedinto increase your CPF contributions;Net income from platform work and other employment sources does not exceed $3,000 for the month (Net income refers to gross earnings minus the Fixed Expense Deduction Amount); andHave an increase in your share of CPF contributions to the Ordinary and Special Accounts as compared to the previous year.As PCTS is intended to offset the increase in CPF contributions, a platform worker will not receive PCTS for the months where his net earnings for a platform operator are$500 or less, as he does not have to make his own share of CPF contributions.In addition, platform workers aged above 65 will not be eligible as they will not see an increase in their own share of CPF contributions if they opt in to increased CPF contributions. In 2025, platform workers aged above 60 to 65 will also not see an increase in their own share of CPF contributions, and thus they will not be eligible.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/my-platform-operator-did-not-pay-my-cpf-contributions-what-can-i-do-to-qualify-for-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts",
        "question": "My platform operator did not pay my CPF contributions. What can I do to qualify for Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS)?",
        "answer": "We will assess your eligibility for Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) based on the earnings declared by your platform operator when making CPF contributions. If you are not paid your CPF contributions on time, you should approach your platform operator for an explanation and ask when your platform operator will be making the payment.If your platform operator does not provide you with a satisfactory response, you can lodge a report with CPF Board. The Board takes a serious view of platform operators who default on CPF contributions. The due date for CPF contributions is on the last day of the calendar month. Enforcement actionwould be taken against platform operators who fail to pay by the 14thof the following month (or the next working day if the 14thfalls on a Saturday, Sunday or Public Holiday).This includes imposing late payment interest charged at 1.5% per month commencing from the first day after the due date. In cases where the company is in financial difficulty, CPF arrears may not always be recoverable despite our enforcement efforts.You mayfind out moreon your rights and platform operators’ obligations under the CPF Act and the Platform Workers Act.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-must-i-earn-more-than-500-from-at-least-one-platform-to-receive-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts",
        "question": "Why must I earn more than $500 from at least one platform to receive Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS)?",
        "answer": "Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) is intended to offset part of the year-on-year increase in a platform worker’s own share of CPF contributions to his Ordinary and Special accounts. How much a platform worker will contribute to his CPF will be based on his net earnings from each platform.A platform worker whose net earnings from each platform is less than or equal to $500 does not have to make his own share of CPF contributions. Given there is no increase in the platform worker’s share of his CPF contributions, he will not be eligible for PCTS.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-platform-workers-above-a-certain-age-not-eligible-for-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts",
        "question": "Why are platform workers above a certain age not eligible for Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS)?",
        "answer": "Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) is intended to offset part of the year-on-year increase in a platform worker’s own share of CPF contributions to his Ordinary and Special accounts, during the phase-in period when platform workers’ CPF contribution rates are gradually increased to align with employees’.Platform workers who do not see an increase in their share of CPF contributions will not receive PCTS as there is no increase in CPF contributions to offset.This includes platform workers aged above 65 who opt in, as they will see a reduction in their own share of CPF contributions . As they will not see a drop in their take-home pay due to the decision to opt in, they will not receive PCTS.In 2025, platform workers aged above 60 to 65 will also not see an increase in their own share of CPF contributions and thus they will not be eligible.For platform workers in these age groups, although there is a reduction in their own share of CPF contributions after opting in, their total CPF contributions will still increase, after taking into account the platform operator’s CPF contributions.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-are-singapore-permanent-residents-not-eligible-for-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts",
        "question": "Why are Singapore Permanent Residents not eligible for Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS)?",
        "answer": "The Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) scheme is only for Singaporean lower-income platform workers.If you require financial assistance, please contact the ComCare hotline at 1800-222-0000, or emailAsk_SSO@msf.gov.sg.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/why-will-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts-cease-in-2029",
        "question": "Why will Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) cease in 2029?",
        "answer": "Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) is meant to offset the increase in the platform workers’ share of CPF contributions in the transition phase as platform workers’ CPF contributions are gradually aligned with that of employees over five years. In 2029, when platform worker’s CPF contributions are completely aligned with that of employees, PCTS will cease.Eligible lower-income platform workers can tap on the Workfare Income Supplement (WIS) instead, where platform workers will receive higher WIS payments at the same level as employees from 2029, once their CPF contribution rates fully align with that of employees. They will also receive a higher proportion of WIS payments in cash – 40% compared to 10% today.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-much-can-i-expect-to-receive-with-the-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts-scheme",
        "question": "How much can I expect to receive with the Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) scheme?",
        "answer": "From 2025 to 2028, Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) will provide monthly cash support to lower-income platform workers to offset part of the year-on-year increase in the platform workers' share of CPF contributions to their Ordinary and Special Accounts (OSA).The amount of PCTS you can receive is based on age, platform earnings and other income, as well as the offset rate for the year:2025202620272028100% offset of OSA increase from previous year75% offset of OSA increase from previous year50% offset of OSA increase from previous year25% offset of OSA increase from previous yearYou can use the onlinePCTS calculatorto estimate how much you can receive.To provide an illustrative example:",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-the-increase-in-platform-workers-share-of-cpf-ordinary-and-special-account-contribution-rates-which-is-used-to-compute-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts",
        "question": "What is the increase in platform workers’ share of CPF Ordinary and Special Account contribution rates, which is used to compute Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS)?",
        "answer": "From 2025 to 2028, platform workers’ own share of CPF contributions rates will increase by up to 2.5%-points each year, until it reaches up to 20% in 2029, to align with employees. This applies to platform workers born in or after 1995, or born before 1995 and opted in to increased CPF contributions (see illustration for example).Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) will offset a percentage of this year-on-year increase of up to 2.5%-points in contribution rate. The offset percentage will taper down from 2025 to 2028. In 2029, when platform workers’ CPF contributions are completely aligned with that of employees, PCTS will cease.*Infographic shows CPF contribution rates for platform workers in the “35 & below” age group, with net earnings above $750 in a month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/when-can-i-receive-my-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts-payments-and-which-bank-account-will-my-pcts-payments-be-credited-to",
        "question": "When can I receive my Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) payments and which bank account will my PCTS payments be credited to?",
        "answer": "As an eligible platform worker, you will receive Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) payment in cash every month. The table below shows when you will receive the payments.You will receive the PCTS in your bank account or via GovCashFor work done inPayNow – NRIC / Bank CreditingGovCashJanEnd March1stweek of AprilFebEnd April1stweek of MayMarEnd May1stweek of JuneMonth XEnd of month (X + 2)1stweek of the following month (X + 3)You will receive the PCTS payment via your PayNow NRIC-linked bank account. To check your PayNow NRIC-linked bank account details, please approach your bank.If you do not have a PayNow NRIC-linked bank account but provided your DBS/POSB, OCBC or UOB bank account to the Government previously, your PCTS will be credited to the bank account that you have registered to receive Government benefits. You may use thislinkto provide or update your bank account details*.If you do not have a registered or PayNow NRIC-linked bank account, you will receive PCTS via GovCash later in the 1stweek of the following month, as opposed to using PayNow-NRIC or Bank Crediting.*If you have linked your NRIC number to your bank account or submitted your bank account details after the 14thof the month, your updates will only be effective in the following month.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-change-the-mode-of-payment-for-my-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts-i-have-already-registered-for-paynow-nric-to-receive-my-government-cash-benefits-do-i-still-need-to-provide-my-bank-account-details",
        "question": "How can I change the mode of payment for my Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS)? / I have already registered for PayNow-NRIC to receive my Government cash benefits. Do I still need to provide my bank account details?",
        "answer": "No further action is required from you if you have already registered for PayNow-NRIC with the participating banks. You are encouraged to register for PayNow-NRIC with a PayNow-GIRO-participating local or foreign bank in Singapore to receive your Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) payments promptly. Payment will be made by default to your PayNow-NRIC-linked bank account.If you do not have a PayNow-NRIC-linked bank account, you can update your bank account details by logging in to oure-serviceswith your Singpass. Payment instructions received will be used for future government benefits. The Government will validate the bank account details that you have registered.If you have closed your bank account, ceased being a joint account holder, or have provided the wrong bank account details, we will inform you to update your bank account details. You will receive a notification sent to your Singpass app. If you do not have the app, a letter will be sent to your NRIC address. This notification will not be sent via SMS, WhatsApp or any other platforms.If you have not linked your NRIC to PayNow or have not provided a valid bank account to the Government, you will receive future Government cash benefits via GovCash.GovCashis a payment mode where you can withdraw your Government benefits in cash from OCBC ATMs.Citizens who are on GovCash will receive their cash benefits 2-3 weeks later than those who have linked their NRIC to PayNow or have provided a valid bank account.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-a-paynow-nric-linked-bank-account-and-how-do-i-register-for-it",
        "question": "What is a PayNow NRIC-linked bank account and how do I register for it?",
        "answer": "PayNow is a secure funds transfer service that enables you to receive payment conveniently in your preferred bank account with only your NRIC number. It adopts the same high security standards as other trusted funds transfer services like FAST and GIRO.You can register for a PayNow NRIC-linked bank account if you have a bank account with the PayNow participating banks in Singapore, which can be found on the Association of Banks in Singapore'swebsite.If your bank is a PayNow participating bank, you may refer to your bank's website for specific details on how to link your NRIC to PayNow.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/what-is-govcash-and-is-it-safe",
        "question": "What is GovCash and is it safe?",
        "answer": "GovCash is a payment mode that allows Singapore citizens to withdraw their Government benefits in cash from over 500 OCBC ATMs located across Singapore.Singaporeans who prefer to seek assistance with their GovCash withdrawals can visit the ATMs located within OCBC's branches during operating hours, where OCBC Digital Ambassadors will be present to guide them. In addition, GovCash also allows recipients to use the scan-and-pay function and PayNow transfer option through the LifeSG mobile app.GovCash is as secure as receiving payments via cheque. It adopts the Singpass Face Verification technology to authenticate users, including a liveness-detection capability that blocks the use of photographs, videos, or masks during the verification process. Users are also required to key in their unique 8-digit Payment Reference Number (PRN) during the withdrawal of the Government benefits at the OCBC ATMs.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-do-i-receive-my-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-cash-benefits-via-govcash",
        "question": "How do I receive my Platform Workers CPF Transition Support cash benefits via GovCash?",
        "answer": "There are three options which you can choose to receive your Platform Workers CPF Transition Support cash benefits via GovCash:Option 1: Use LifeSG to transfer to PayNow-NRIC linked bank accountIf you have an existing bank account, you can link your account to PayNow-NRIC with your bank. Thereafter, login to LifeSG mobile app (LifeSG) using your Singpass to transfer your GovCash to your PayNow-NRIC linked bank account. The LifeSG app can be downloaded from the Apple App store or Google Play Store.Option 2: Use LifeSG for Scan & PayYou can use LifeSG to scan participating merchant’s QR code for purchases or scan your friend/family’s QR code to transfer your GovCash to them. You can only make purchases at merchants that accept PayNow/NETS QR code using the LifeSG app. You can look out for the PayNow/NETS logo on the SG QR label that is displayed by the merchants.Option 3: Withdraw from OCBC ATMsYou can withdraw your cash benefits at OCBC ATMs islandwide. You just need to enter:a) Your unique 8-digit Payment Reference Number (PRN)b) Your NRIC number; andc) pass the facial verificationYou do not need to have an OCBC bank account to use this service.You will receive the PRN via SMS or email after your cash benefits has been paid.You can also log into thee-serviceswith your Singpass to view your PRN by selecting “GovCash PRN” that is found at the menu on the left. This will only be available after the payment has been made.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-and-when-will-i-be-notified-on-my-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts-payments",
        "question": "How and when will I be notified on my Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) payments?",
        "answer": "If you have registered your contact details with CPF Board, you will receive a notificationvia SMSoremailwhen your Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) payment has been credited.",
        "status": "success"
    },
    {
        "link": "https://www.cpf.gov.sg/service/article/how-can-i-update-my-contact-details-to-receive-notification-on-my-platform-workers-cpf-transition-support-pcts-payments",
        "question": "How can I update my contact details to receive notification on my Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) payments?",
        "answer": "To receive notification via SMS or email on your Platform Workers CPF Transition Support (PCTS) payment, you may update your mobile number viamy cpfdigital services -Account Settingswith your Singpass.",
        "status": "success"
    }
]